<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>chromium on Unusually Pink</title>
    <link>https://hugo.unusually.pink/tags/chromium/</link>
    <description>Recent content in chromium on Unusually Pink</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>2021</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hugo.unusually.pink/tags/chromium/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>RIP Chrome OS</title>
      <link>https://hugo.unusually.pink/posts/rip-chrome-os/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hugo.unusually.pink/posts/rip-chrome-os/</guid>
      <description>If you’ve listened to some of our episodes or read some of my other posts on this site, then you’re likely aware that I’ve historically been a Chromebook fan. I started with the original HP Chromebook 11 and have owned quite a Chromebook collection since then. The speed and simplicity to do the two main things I need in my personal life (interacting with web pages and making SSH connections) coupled with the low cost made them a perfect match.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;If you’ve listened to some of our episodes or &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unusually.pink/blog/unusually-pink-impressions-acer-chromebook-315&#34;&gt;read some of my other posts on this site&lt;/a&gt;, then you’re likely aware that I’ve historically been a Chromebook fan. I started with the original HP Chromebook 11 and have owned quite a Chromebook collection since then. The speed and simplicity to do the two main things I need in my personal life (interacting with web pages and making SSH connections) coupled with the low cost made them a perfect match.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My feelings about Chrome have been shifting, though, as I &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unusually.pink/blog/back-to-firefox&#34;&gt;elucidated in my post about switching back to Firefox as my main browser&lt;/a&gt; on my work laptop. That post was written from the context of Chrome as a browser without really looking specifically at the Chrome OS operating system. In that area Google has also been making some… less than stellar changes which have ultimately caused frustration to the point where I’ve now given up on Chromebooks entirely. The primary culprit: Google’s confusing war on swap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: Really smart people make Chrome and Chrome OS. I don’t mean to throw shade at them. I’m sure there’s well-reasoned thought behind the changes I’m about to describe that is either not posted or not posted in a location I found. The real-world impact is undeniable, though.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-symptoms&#34;&gt;The Symptoms&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before diving into the problem, I’d like to discuss the end user experience. I admittedly hadn’t been following the Chrome change logs over the past few months while I’ve been busy with starting a new job and moving; I’d mark those posts as read in Feedly and move on to more interesting things. So it seemed almost out of nowhere that my tabs and PWAs in Chrome OS would simply die and reload on their own. Sometimes it wasn’t a big deal. A tab with a news article or a Reddit post can reload without any dire consequences. In other cases, it was a bit more annoying: the Spotify PWA would reload, causing the music I was enjoying to stop playing. And in some instances it was catastrophic: I’d tab away from Squarespace where I had been working on a post for this site to verify some information, and the tab would reload when I went back to it, causing me to lose my progress. The same thing would happen with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/secure-shell-app/pnhechapfaindjhompbnflcldabbghjo?hl=en&#34;&gt;Secure Shell extension&lt;/a&gt;, kicking me out of my SSH session and causing me to lose everything if I didn’t have tmux running. Even if I &lt;strong&gt;did&lt;/strong&gt; have tmux running, it’s still insanely annoying to have to log back in every time I flip from an ebook back to my SSH session… assuming the ebook didn’t &lt;strong&gt;also&lt;/strong&gt; reload, causing me to have to find my place again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can likely imagine, this was maddening and quickly made it impossible for me to really &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; anything with my Chromebooks. At this point, it seemed like my device was in open rebellion against me, and I started doing research into what was happening under the hood to cause this behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-culprit&#34;&gt;The Culprit&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cause of this behavior ended up being a new “feature” referred to as &lt;a href=&#34;https://developers.google.com/web/updates/2015/09/tab-discarding?authuser=0&#34;&gt;Tab Discarding&lt;/a&gt;. The idea seems fine on the surface; not all open tabs in a browser are &lt;strong&gt;active&lt;/strong&gt; tabs. So to avoid low memory conditions, Google was discarding tabs that it deemed inactive. This drops the tab and its contents out of memory but keeps the tab open in the browser. If you open that tab again, the contents are then reloaded. The benefit tot his is that you can keep more memory available for actively utilized tabs without having to drop down to swap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-note-on-swap&#34;&gt;A Note On Swap&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you aren’t familiar with swap, it’s good to think about what computers do when they run out of memory. Since just crashing isn’t exactly an option, for the past few &lt;strong&gt;decades&lt;/strong&gt; computers have utilized what’s referred to as swap space. In most flavors of Linux, swap is an actual partition on the disk. In Windows you’ll have a &lt;strong&gt;pagefile.sys&lt;/strong&gt; file. The point of both is the same; when the operating system runs out of memory, it’ll take some data currently stored in memory that hasn’t been used in a little while and write that to the disk in either the swap partition or the pagefile. Then that memory becomes available for some new, active process to utilize. Should the content that was swapped be required again, something &lt;em&gt;else&lt;/em&gt; will be transferred from memory to disk, and then the previously swapped content can be moved from the disk back to memory. Most systems will give you insight into how much swap you’re using. For example, we can see from running &lt;strong&gt;htop&lt;/strong&gt; on this Linux laptop that I’m not currently leveraging swap:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/RIPChromeOS_htop_swap.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This matters because reading and writing from/to the disk is slower than just working in memory… though it’s not nearly as slow in the world of SSDs than it was in the world of spinning platter hard drives. The less swap you can use, the snappier things go… though I question if waiting for SSD swap is actually slower than waiting a few seconds for a web page to reload. Regardless, not using swap can be a matter of both adding more physical memory to the system and optimizing the software for it. Okay, back to the main point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;back-to-the-culprit&#34;&gt;Back To The Culprit&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google was attempting to use software optimizations to make Chrome stop leveraging swap and keep everything in active memory. The problem is that while this is good in theory, it doesn’t pan out so well in practice in a world of Chromebooks that have 2 - 4 GB of memory installed. I was hitting the point on my Acer Chromebook 315 (which has 4 GB of RAM) where two tabs were too much for the system. Flipping between the two would cause the tab I just left to be discarded. I tried to even go so far as to disable the Play Store and Linux support to see if that would help free up additional memory. While it helped a &lt;em&gt;little&lt;/em&gt;, in the end I was still experiencing the same problems. My laptop was a paperweight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;solutions&#34;&gt;Solutions?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I naturally started looking for solutions to this problem. The Chromium project put together a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.chromium.org/chromium-os/chromiumos-design-docs/tab-discarding-and-reloading&#34;&gt;decent FAQ on the behavior&lt;/a&gt;. While that confirmed for me &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; it was happening, it didn’t exactly provide solutions on how to make it stop. For the question of “How can I make it stop?” the answer was:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Close some tabs or uninstall extensions that take a lot of memory. If there&amp;rsquo;s a specific tab you don&amp;rsquo;t want discarded, right-click on the tab and pin it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Except the order of operations for discarding tabs goes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Internal pages like new tab page, bookmarks, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tabs selected a long time ago&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tabs selected recently&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tabs playing audio&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apps running in a window&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pinned tabs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The selected tab&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So even pinning a tab won’t necessarily prevent it from being discarded; it’s just less likely. It also seems legitimately &lt;strong&gt;insane&lt;/strong&gt; to me to have to temporarily pin any tab you’re actively working in to keep it from being discarded. The behavior is clearly detrimental and needs to be disabled. The original post for the “experiment” mentioned being able to toggle this feature from:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;chrome://flags/#enable-tab-discarding&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only that didn’t actually work for me; the option was gone. I noticed that &lt;a href=&#34;https://developers.google.com/web/updates/2015/09/tab-discarding?authuser=0&#34;&gt;the page was last updated in January of 2019&lt;/a&gt;, so I’m sure this behavior had changed. The post had also mentioned going to the flags page in order to &lt;em&gt;enable&lt;/em&gt; tab discarding when it was clearly now on by default.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Going further down the rabbit hole, i found some &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/chrome/comments/bxckh3/no_more_automatic_tab_discarding/&#34;&gt;threads on Reddit&lt;/a&gt; where users confirmed my fear; starting with Chrome OS 75 this “feature” was forcibly turned on and the flags to disable it removed. Yikes! The only solution present was to install &lt;a href=&#34;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/disable-automatic-tab-dis/dnhngfnfolbmhgealdpolmhimnoliiok?authuser=0&#34;&gt;some random browser extension to prevent tab discarding&lt;/a&gt;. I can only speculate as to why the ability to turn off such anti-user behavior was removed, but having to install an extension to get it back seems absurd, especially when, as the author of the extension notes, it still isn’t guaranteed to prevent your tabs from being discarded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point I decided that Chrome OS had finally crossed the line of what I was willing to tolerate in the name of simplicity. When I literally can’t use my laptop to author a post for this website, the device is valueless to me. I won’t go into what I’ve opted to replace my Chromebook with in this post (that’s a topic for another post or possibly even a podcast episode), but suffice to say I’ve officially hopped off the Chrome OS train. The good news is that I’m now not using the Chrome browser &lt;em&gt;anywhere&lt;/em&gt;, giving Google one less avenue to capture data on what I’m doing online.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unusually Pink Updates: Dropbox, Password Managers, and Ad Blocking</title>
      <link>https://hugo.unusually.pink/posts/unusually-pink-updates-dropbox-password-managers-and-ad-blocking/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hugo.unusually.pink/posts/unusually-pink-updates-dropbox-password-managers-and-ad-blocking/</guid>
      <description>This will be one of those weird amalgam posts featuring multiple only mildly-related topics but which are too short to be a post in their own right. I though it would be helpful to provide some updates on a few things that Brandi and I have talked about in some of our past episodes. They’re all tech-related… but you already know that from reading the title.
Dropbox Upgrades and Price Increases On June 1st, Dropbox added more features to their Plus plan.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;This will be one of those weird amalgam posts featuring multiple only mildly-related topics but which are too short to be a post in their own right. I though it would be helpful to provide some updates on a few things that Brandi and I have talked about in some of our &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unusually.pink/podcast&#34;&gt;past episodes&lt;/a&gt;. They’re all tech-related… but you already know that from reading the title.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;dropbox-upgrades-and-price-increases&#34;&gt;Dropbox Upgrades and Price Increases&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On June 1st, Dropbox added more features to their &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dropbox.com/individual/plans-comparison&#34;&gt;Plus plan&lt;/a&gt;. I’ve been a Plus customer for a couple of years now. It’s less of a “I need to pay for the extra space” situation and more of a “I store some important shit in here and this gives me more peace of mind” situation. The main features from the upgrade, according to the email they sent me, are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Double your storage—save everything with 2 TB (2,000 GB).&lt;br&gt;
World-class sync technology—move out-of-date files off your computer’s hard drive and to the cloud with Dropbox Smart Sync.&lt;br&gt;
Dropbox Rewind—roll back accidental changes to any folder, or your entire account, up to 30 days.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The extra storage is nice, though suffice to say it’s not exactly something I &lt;strong&gt;need&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/UnusuallyPinkUpdatesDropboxPasswordManagersandAdBlocking_dropbox_space.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rewind seems &lt;strong&gt;really&lt;/strong&gt; nice, though. I store a lot of PowerShell scripts in Dropbox, so I could see rewind being useful if I accidentally break one or need to snag an older version for some reason. While I’ve recently been making an effort to check in my bigger, more important scripts with &lt;a href=&#34;https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/services/devops/&#34;&gt;Azure DevOps&lt;/a&gt; for version control, smaller ones that I’m the only person likely to use still just go into Dropbox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things aren’t all roses and unicorns, though, as the added storage and features come at a cost: $2 USD more per month. This bumps the monthly price up to $12 USD. The good part is that if you go with yearly pricing, you save that $2 a month and pay $120 for the year. I’m actually still on monthly pricing despite having used the Plus service for a few years so I’ll need to move over for sure. While the bonus storage is available now the new pricing isn’t happening for me until July. So before early July I need to swap to yearly billing to avoid paying the extra couple of bucks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;wired-password-manager-recommendations&#34;&gt;Wired Password Manager Recommendations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unusually.pink/podcast/episode-8-playlists-and-privacy&#34;&gt;last episode&lt;/a&gt;, Brandi and I spoke a bit about password managers. Right after we recorded that episode &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wired.com/story/best-password-managers/&#34;&gt;Wired published an article all about password managers&lt;/a&gt;. The timing seemed perfect to share it. Of the ones Wired recommends Dashlane is the only that I haven’t used. It also makes me feel good that my preferred password manager, &lt;a href=&#34;https://1password.com/&#34;&gt;1Password&lt;/a&gt;, was Wired’s #1 recommendation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of Wired, I love their content but always run into my 5 free articles per month limit. I just happened to see earlier today that they’re &lt;a href=&#34;https://subscribe.wired.com/subscribe/wired/121031?source=EDT_WIR_TWITTER_0_WEEKOFJUNE03_3_ZZ&amp;amp;utm_brand=wired&amp;amp;utm_source=twitter&amp;amp;utm_social-type=owned&amp;amp;mbid=social_twitter&amp;amp;utm_medium=social&amp;amp;utm_campaign=wired&#34;&gt;doing a deal&lt;/a&gt; where you can snag a year’s subscription for just $10. This includes the print editions plus digital content (normally $50 a year) or just digital if you don’t care about print (normally $30 a year.) I was fortunate enough to see it right when &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/WIRED/status/1136709547022848006&#34;&gt;they posted to Twitter&lt;/a&gt;. I have no clue how long this is running for, but it seems pretty worthwhile if you’re a geek and like tech news. And no… we don’t get anything for promoting this. I just like Wired.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;browser-ad-blocking&#34;&gt;Browser Ad Blocking&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also from our &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unusually.pink/podcast/episode-8-playlists-and-privacy&#34;&gt;last episode&lt;/a&gt;, we discussed how &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.zdnet.com/article/google-chrome-could-soon-kill-off-most-ad-blocker-extensions/&#34;&gt;Google was initially thinking about making changes to the webRequest API&lt;/a&gt; that would essentially cripple ad blockers. Like we discussed in the episode, after those initial reports and backlash in January Google had backed off a little and said they would think through how this API update should work. At the end of May, though, it came to light that &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.androidpolice.com/2019/05/29/google-still-plans-to-kill-chromes-existing-adblock-apis/&#34;&gt;Google still plans to nuke the webRequest API pieces that allow current ad blockers to work&lt;/a&gt;… that is &lt;a href=&#34;https://9to5google.com/2019/05/29/chrome-ad-blocking-enterprise-manifest-v3/&#34;&gt;unless you’re a G Suite customer&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What’s worse is that these proposed changes seem to be in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.chromium.org/&#34;&gt;open-source Chromium project&lt;/a&gt;. So unless Microsoft does some work on their fork, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microsoftedgeinsider.com/en-us/&#34;&gt;Chromium-based version of Edge&lt;/a&gt; could also be impacted. Suffice to say this gives me some &lt;strong&gt;significant&lt;/strong&gt; pause on my previously mentioned plans to buy a new Chromebook. I’m now re-evaluating what I should do for my laptop situation. And if you haven’t used &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/&#34;&gt;Firefox Quantum&lt;/a&gt; recently, now might be a great time to check it out.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Edge Insider: It&#39;s Actually Not That Bad</title>
      <link>https://hugo.unusually.pink/posts/microsoft-edge-insider-its-actually-not-that-bad/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hugo.unusually.pink/posts/microsoft-edge-insider-its-actually-not-that-bad/</guid>
      <description>If you happened to listen to our Introduction Episode of the podcast, you’ll know that Brandi and I are sysadmins who work together in a highly Microsoft-centric environment. Essentially all of the servers we manage run some flavor of Windows, we make heavy use of Office 365 and Azure, and both of us spend our entire day either typing email into Outlook or commands into PowerShell.
You may read that and think, “Wow, they really like Microsoft stuff.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;If you happened to listen to our &lt;a href=&#34;https://unusuallypinkpodcast.podbean.com/e/episode-0-introduction-1556126516/&#34;&gt;Introduction Episode of the podcast&lt;/a&gt;, you’ll know that Brandi and I are sysadmins who work together in a &lt;em&gt;highly&lt;/em&gt; Microsoft-centric environment. Essentially all of the servers we manage run some flavor of Windows, we make heavy use of Office 365 and Azure, and both of us spend our entire day either typing email into Outlook or commands into PowerShell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may read that and think, “Wow, they really like Microsoft stuff.” At least for me (John, if that’s not clear by now) that’s not the case. I tend to be extremely critical and frequently frustrated with a lot of Microsoft’s offerings. I’ve poured a healthy bit of salt into the Internet over the years at Microsoft’s expense. I could even share some of my more recent frustration with Microsoft products if it wouldn’t spoil what will likely be content for a near-future podcast episode. Suffice to say, there’s a reason one of my former coworkers threw together this image… that’s my face on the can if you’re confused.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/MicrosoftEdgeInsiderItsActuallyNotThatBad_morton.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And there’s a reason why I made this image at one point. Cut me some slack… I didn’t really know how to use &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gimp.org/&#34;&gt;GIMP&lt;/a&gt; that well at the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/MicrosoftEdgeInsiderItsActuallyNotThatBad_admiral_o365.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That being said, I’m all about trying the new hotness where software is concerned, so I decided to install the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microsoftedgeinsider.com/en-us/&#34;&gt;new Microsoft Edge Insider build&lt;/a&gt; on my work machine. If you haven’t been keeping score at home, Microsoft essentially admitted that the current, production version of Edge that ships with Windows 10 is a disaster. No one uses it according to every metric, despite Microsoft’s attempts at forcing it on users. They also accepted that their rendering engine under-performed. Perhaps the biggest problem, though, was how the Edge browser was inextricably tied to the underlying operating system, meaning that Edge essentially only got updates during Microsoft’s major updates to Windows 10. Going 6+ months between browser updates is a pretty massive blow when competitors are releasing new versions every month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new builds of Edge are based on the open-source &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.chromium.org/&#34;&gt;Chromium&lt;/a&gt; project. While perhaps most notably serving as the underpinnings for Google’s behemoth of a browser that has come to dominate the web, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/chrome/&#34;&gt;Chrome&lt;/a&gt;, it’s also come to serve the same function for plenty of other noteworthy browsers, such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.opera.com/&#34;&gt;Opera&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://brave.com/&#34;&gt;Brave&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I threw the Insider build on my work PC to check it out. If you happen to be curious, you can install it alongside the current version of Edge. The icon looks the same but has a green “Dev” stamp over the blue “e”. If you fire it up, it looks essentially like what you’d expect to see opening the current version of Chrome. You get the option to sign in with a Microsoft account, though, rather than a Google account. The various options and settings have been changed up in how they appear, but they’re basically all the same. If you’d like to use an extension, you can select from a subset of Chrome extensions that are currently working with this build of Edge in Microsoft’s own gallery; I’ve read that they’re working to make every extension supported by Chromium and Chrome work with Edge eventually. I was just happy enough that I could get &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gorhill/uBlock&#34;&gt;uBlock Origin&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/MicrosoftEdgeInsiderItsActuallyNotThatBad_edge_chromium.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been running with it as my default browser for a couple of weeks now, and I have to admit that I haven’t run into any issues yet. Everything just works the same as I’d expect, only with a bit of a smaller footprint than with Chrome. I assume this is &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theverge.com/2019/4/8/18300772/microsoft-google-services-removed-changed-chromium-edge-browser&#34;&gt;due to all of the Google services Microsoft ended up removing&lt;/a&gt;. If so, it almost reminds me of how Firefox was before the Electrolysis rebuild, where it had become a bit slow and clunky due to bloat. Or how Opera was back in the day when the browser featured a mail client, IRC client, toaster oven, vacuum cleaner, etc. A good feature purge isn’t necessarily the worst thing to happen to some software projects as they expand over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/new/&#34;&gt;Firefox&lt;/a&gt;, one of the downsides to this is the fact that it means yet &lt;strong&gt;another&lt;/strong&gt; browser is now based on Chromium. Outside of looking as extremely niche browsers, this means that Firefox is now the only non-Chromium-based mainstream browser. That’s a sticky situation since it means that a single project (Chromium) can essentially dictate the growth and direction of the web if they so choose. If that project opted to move away from established standards to do their own thing, for example, no one would be able to ignore that many impacted users. Switching to a Chromium base is a situation that I would describe as good for Microsoft and extremely bad for the web as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if you’re one of the three people in the world using the current stable version of Edge with Windows 10 and you’re mad that it will be going away, please just read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.forbes.com/sites/daveywinder/2019/04/21/unpatched-windows-10-vulnerability-uses-microsoft-edge-to-steal-data-how-to-mitigate-the-risk/#503de7ad673f&#34;&gt;this article about a nasty Edge vulnerability that Microsoft has declined to patch&lt;/a&gt;. Then please stop using that browser.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
