<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>music on Unusually Pink</title>
    <link>https://hugo.unusually.pink/categories/music/</link>
    <description>Recent content in music on Unusually Pink</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>2021</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hugo.unusually.pink/categories/music/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2018 In Music: Spotify Wrapped</title>
      <link>https://hugo.unusually.pink/posts/2018-in-music-spotify-wrapped/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hugo.unusually.pink/posts/2018-in-music-spotify-wrapped/</guid>
      <description>I’ve used quite a few streaming services for music throughout the years (I feel old remembering when Pandora was new), but Spotify is by far my favorite. The main value I see from it as opposed to similar, competing services is the amount of personalized, curated content that Spotify generates for me on a regular basis. Each Monday I get a Discover Weekly playlist with music I’ve never listened to before but which is similar to other things I’ve enjoyed.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;I’ve used quite a few streaming services for music throughout the years (I feel old remembering when Pandora was new), but Spotify is by far my favorite. The main value I see from it as opposed to similar, competing services is the amount of personalized, curated content that Spotify generates for me on a regular basis. Each Monday I get a Discover Weekly playlist with music I’ve never listened to before but which is similar to other things I’ve enjoyed. Every Friday I get a Release Radar playlist with new releases that also match my taste. These only get better over time as the service learns more and more of what I like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along with these weekly goodies, Spotify also does neat stuff for various milestones, and that’s especially true at the end of the calendar year. For example, each December I get a yearly playlist with my top 100 songs from the past year. It’s always an interesting listen to see how varied my tastes were throughout the year. Accompanying that is &lt;a href=&#34;https://spotifywrapped.com&#34;&gt;Spotify Wrapped&lt;/a&gt; which provides all sorts of interesting statistics about my listening. As someone who keeps Spotify tied to &lt;a href=&#34;https://last.fm&#34;&gt;Last.fm&lt;/a&gt; because I love statistics, I always look forward to Wrapped. Here are some of my interesting notes from 2018 (no pun intended.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8,131: The total number of unique songs I listened to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;50,739: The total number of minutes I listened to music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For those keeping score at home, that’s over 35 &lt;strong&gt;days&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My top artist was Tegan and Sara.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I spent 32 hours listening just to their tracks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall top artists:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tegan and Sara&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grimes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eminem&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coeur De Pirate&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;St. Vincent&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall top tracks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RAP DEVIL (Machine Gun Kelly)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los Ageless (St. Vincent)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1940 - AmpLive Remix (The Submarines)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flesh without Blood (Grimes)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do You Feel It? (Chaos Chaos)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall top genres:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indie&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pop&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rock&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dance/Electronic&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hip Hop&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I listened to “non-mainstream” artists 69% more than the average Spotify listener.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have no idea what’s considered mainstream or whether Spotify is taking the “average” listener to be all listeners or only Premium accounts. Regardless, it makes me feel special.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s to more music in 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
