<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>manjaro on Unusually Pink</title>
    <link>https://unusually.pink/tags/manjaro/</link>
    <description>Recent content in manjaro on Unusually Pink</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>2021 - John Fabry</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://unusually.pink/tags/manjaro/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Swapping Mirrors On Manjaro Linux</title>
      <link>https://unusually.pink/swapping-mirrors-on-manjaro-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unusually.pink/swapping-mirrors-on-manjaro-linux/</guid>
      <description>One of my favorite aspects of Linux ever since my first Ubuntu 6.06 installation has been the software repository. Back in 2006, installing the overwhelming majority of the software I might need from a supported repository stood in stark contrast with the Windows XP method of searching the web for the software you wanted, finding a download link that didn&amp;rsquo;t seem shady, and then hoping for the best.
Repositories are frequently hosted by the maintainer of a Linux distribution (e.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;One of my favorite aspects of Linux ever since my first Ubuntu 6.06 installation has been the software repository. Back in 2006, installing the overwhelming majority of the software I might need from a supported repository stood in stark contrast with the Windows XP method of searching the web for the software you wanted, finding a download link that didn&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em&gt;seem&lt;/em&gt; shady, and then hoping for the best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Repositories are frequently hosted by the maintainer of a Linux distribution (e.g. &lt;a href=&#34;https://ubuntu.com/&#34;&gt;Ubuntu&lt;/a&gt; has official repos hosted by &lt;a href=&#34;https://canonical.com/&#34;&gt;Canonical&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://getfedora.org/&#34;&gt;Fedora&lt;/a&gt; has official repos hosted by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.redhat.com/en&#34;&gt;Red Hat&lt;/a&gt;, etc.) That being said, often times repositories are mirrored by service providers (e.g. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linode.com/&#34;&gt;Linode&lt;/a&gt; hosts many mirrors so that repository content can be served out of the same datacenter as the virtual machines), Linux interest groups, and other community members. This is great because it allows for the repos to be geographically diverse. Pulling downloads from a repository hosted in the same continent, for example, will typically show a marked improvement over using one on the opposite side of the planet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The downside to this is that repos occasionally become unavailable for whatever reason. This happened to be recently, as I went to update one of my &lt;a href=&#34;https://manjaro.org/&#34;&gt;Manjaro&lt;/a&gt; installs via:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo pacman -Syu&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After sitting for an unusual amount of time, I was told that a connection couldn&amp;rsquo;t be established to my current mirror, which happened to be: &lt;strong&gt;us.mirrors.fossho.st&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s worth noting that, at least on Manjaro, your mirror is only displayed when the connection fails. If the connection is successful, you only see the results of the update check. I could have simply tried again later, but without knowing how long the outage would be I instead decided to hunt for how to swap to a different mirror. Fortunately, the process is extremely easy. The current mirrors are contained in the file:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;/etc/pacman.d/mirrorlist&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The file contains a list of mirrors, with a comment above each indicating the country. At the very top of my list was my current mirror of &lt;strong&gt;us.mirrors.fossho.st&lt;/strong&gt;. I simply added a &lt;code&gt;#&lt;/code&gt; to the start of the line for it, commenting it out. I next ran a full package sync to make sure I didn&amp;rsquo;t have anything cached locally that wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be reflected on a different mirror:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo pacman -Syyu&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This picked a different mirror, and everything worked as expected. The problem was solved. Not satisfied with leaving things at that, though, I decided to see if I could tell of any indicators of a mirror being down. I first confirmed that I could ping &lt;strong&gt;us.mirrors.fossho.st&lt;/strong&gt;. Likewise, I could connect to it over port 80 (HTTP.) However, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t connect to it over port 443 (HTTPS.) I don&amp;rsquo;t actually know what mechanism is used for deliver updates, but I feel like it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; likely that HTTPS is used; I couldn&amp;rsquo;t see HTTP being the norm given that you wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be able to ensure the updates hadn&amp;rsquo;t been tampered with. A random port is always possible, though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the sake of comparison, I opened &lt;code&gt;/etc/pacman.d/mirrorlist&lt;/code&gt; back up and searched for another mirror in the US. &lt;strong&gt;mirror.dacentec.com&lt;/strong&gt; was the first hit. I repeated the same process and confirmed that I &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; reach it on both ports 80 and 443.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://unusually.pink/images/nmap_mirrors_full.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems like 443 is the key. It was only after doing this, though, that I realized a project like Manjaro likely has a status page for their mirrors. &lt;a href=&#34;https://repo.manjaro.org/&#34;&gt;I wasn&amp;rsquo;t disappointed.&lt;/a&gt; Checking this did appear to indicate that my original mirror is experiencing issues. Incidentally, the baseline mirror I tested is included in the same screenshot, and it&amp;rsquo;s shown to be up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://unusually.pink/images/mirror_status-1024x139.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrading Star Labs Firmware On Manjaro Linux</title>
      <link>https://unusually.pink/upgrading-star-labs-firmware-on-manjaro-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unusually.pink/upgrading-star-labs-firmware-on-manjaro-linux/</guid>
      <description>As you may recall, I purchased a new Linux laptop from Star Labs a while back. It’s a solid little device, though I admittedly haven’t been using it as much as I anticipated due to my increased reliance on my iPads. For more information on that, look for the new Same Shade Of Difference podcast episode that should be dropping very soon. That being said, because I don’t have the worst operational security ever, I do update my laptop every time I happen to see that something is pending.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;As you may recall, I &lt;a href=&#34;https://unusually.pink/star-lite-mk-iii/&#34;&gt;purchased a new Linux laptop from Star Labs&lt;/a&gt; a while back. It’s a solid little device, though I admittedly haven’t been using it as much as I anticipated due to my increased reliance on my iPads. For more information on that, look for the new &lt;a href=&#34;https://sameshadeofdifference.com&#34;&gt;Same Shade Of Difference&lt;/a&gt; podcast episode that should be dropping &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; soon. That being said, because I don’t have the worst operational security ever, I do update my laptop every time I happen to see that something is pending. Given that I run &lt;a href=&#34;https://manjaro.org&#34;&gt;Manjaro Linux&lt;/a&gt;, that tends to happen frequently. Manjaro is what’s known as an evergreen Linux distribution. It uses a rolling release cycle, meaning that there are no new “major” releases of the OS. For example, there’s no equivalent in Manjaro of moving from Ubuntu 20.04 to Ubuntu 20.10. Occasionally the maintainers spin off a new .iso with updated packages, but that’s just to save users from having to upgrade an insane number of packages when they do a fresh installation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I’ve been diligent about upgrading my OS and my Linux kernels (which Manjaro also provides a nice manager for), I’ve neglected to upgrade my firmware. Fortunately, Star Labs makes this process extremely simple. All of their firmware is published to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/StarLabsLtd/firmware?utm_campaign=9th%20March%202020%20coreboot%20MK%20III%20%28TQpHxp%29&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_source=Newsletter&amp;amp;_ke=eyJrbF9jb21wYW55X2lkIjogIlBjaGtVQyIsICJrbF9lbWFpbCI6ICJqamZhYnJ5QHByb3Rvbm1haWwuY29tIn0%3D&#34;&gt;their GitHub account&lt;/a&gt;. There’s no need to actually keep tabs on that if you don’t want to, though, because Star Labs also sends periodic emails announcing firmware updates for their devices. I obviously can’t speak to how deep into the lifecycle of each device these may go, but at least for the time being it’s extremely helpful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even better, when it comes to installing firmware there’s a dedicated utility for it. They cover the &lt;a href=&#34;https://support.starlabs.systems/articles/installing-updates-from-the-lvfs?utm_campaign=9th%20March%202020%20coreboot%20MK%20III%20%28TQpHxp%29&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_source=Newsletter&amp;amp;_ke=eyJrbF9jb21wYW55X2lkIjogIlBjaGtVQyIsICJrbF9lbWFpbCI6ICJqamZhYnJ5QHByb3Rvbm1haWwuY29tIn0%3D&#34;&gt;gamut of options on their support site&lt;/a&gt; since they support a large number of Linux variants, but for Manjaro you just need to start by installing a couple of additional packages:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34; data-lang=&#34;shell&#34;&gt;sudo pacman -Sy fwupd gnome-firmware
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I realized after the fact that I probably &lt;em&gt;didn’t&lt;/em&gt; need &lt;strong&gt;gnome-firmware&lt;/strong&gt; since I’m unlikely to ever use the GUI for this, but it’s not as though the application takes up a large degree of space. Once the packages are installed, the next step is to check for any new firmware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34; data-lang=&#34;shell&#34;&gt;sudo fwupdmgr refresh
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This should report back if there are new firmware updates. In my case, it reported firmware updates for 2 items, one of which was 3 revisions out of date. Yikes! I kicked off the firmware upgrade via:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34; data-lang=&#34;shell&#34;&gt;sudo fwupdmgr update
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s worth mentioning that the system will complain if you run the above command without having a power source connected since, generally, upgrading firmware and losing power in the middle of the process is a recipe for bricking your device. If power isn’t connected, though, it’ll very smartly prompt you to connect power and retry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the installation kicks off, the device will need to reboot. After the reboot, you’ll land in the firmware itself and be prompted to confirm the upgrades you’re about to apply. Use the arrow keys to move to the bottom and apply the pending changes (they’ll be pending by default.) This may take some time, and in my case the firmware application would move from 0% to 100% multiple times without any indication it was at different stages or anything like that. I recommend getting some coffee and letting your device do its thing. Once the upgrades are fully completed, you’ll be prompted to hit literally any key to kick off another reboot. This reboot will take noticeably longer than a normal reboot, and you’ll spend a decent amount of time staring at a black screen before you even see the Star Labs logo appear like you normally would during the boot cycle. Patience is a virtue, so just let the device do its thing. Eventually you should see the login screen you know and love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At that point, just log back in and everything should be running as expected with the new firmware. If you want to be certain, running&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34; data-lang=&#34;shell&#34;&gt;fwupdmgr refresh
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; again should confirm there are no longer any pending firmware upgrades. It’s also worth mentioning that, during the upgrade process, many peripherals may end up being disconnected if the device is docked or anything like that. In my case the laptop was running standalone with nothing but AC power connected. The upgrade utility also very kindly warns you of this ahead of time, so just be on the lookout for the messages it gives you as you go through the upgrade process. The tl;dr is that if you read the output given to you by &lt;strong&gt;fwupdmgr&lt;/strong&gt;, everything should go smoothly.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Star Lite Mk III</title>
      <link>https://unusually.pink/star-lite-mk-iii/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unusually.pink/star-lite-mk-iii/</guid>
      <description>After spending some quality time with my Pinebook Pro, I decided that I wanted something slightly more powerful for my personal laptop. While most of my heavy-lifting in the world of computers is done with my MacBook Pro for work (which was recently upgraded to a device featuring the new M1 chips; look for more on that soon both here and on the Same Shade of Difference podcast), the Pinebook Pro&amp;rsquo;s extremely weak ARM processor wasn&amp;rsquo;t quite cutting it.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;After spending some quality time with my &lt;a href=&#34;https://unusually.pink/unusually-pink-impressions-pinebook-pro/&#34;&gt;Pinebook Pro&lt;/a&gt;, I decided that I wanted something &lt;em&gt;slightly&lt;/em&gt; more powerful for my personal laptop. While most of my heavy-lifting in the world of computers is done with my MacBook Pro for work (which was recently upgraded to a device featuring the new M1 chips; look for more on that soon both here and on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sameshadeofdifference.com/&#34;&gt;Same Shade of Difference podcast&lt;/a&gt;), the Pinebook Pro&amp;rsquo;s extremely weak ARM processor wasn&amp;rsquo;t quite cutting it. Even doing things like writing up blog posts in the WordPress editor would occasionally lag, and watching videos above 720p is essentially impossible. I was still infatuated with the idea of a low-cost Linux laptop, though. I love using Linux, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t exactly need a workhorse device from somewhere like &lt;a href=&#34;https://system76.com/laptops&#34;&gt;System 76&lt;/a&gt; just to write blog posts, maintain a couple of websites, watch videos, and play chess. After going down a rabbit hole of trying to find a (relatively) inexpensive Linux laptop (spoiler alert: they&amp;rsquo;re rare), I decided to pre-order the &lt;a href=&#34;https://starlabs.systems/pages/lite-mk-iii&#34;&gt;Star Lite Mk III from Star Labs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;shipping&#34;&gt;Shipping&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I originally pre-ordered the laptop in the summer, with a shipping estimate of early September. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t exactly in a rush, so that wasn&amp;rsquo;t a problem for me. The global pandemic caused something of a cascading series of delays which ultimately meant that I didn&amp;rsquo;t receive my device until mid-November. For example, production delays in China that ran behind became exacerbated when the factory closed due to &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Golden_Week_(China)&#34;&gt;Golden Week&lt;/a&gt;. Star Labs is based in the UK, so once production and QA were done, the devices shipped from the factory in China to the UK. There they were held up in customs for an entire week before they actually reached Star Labs in order to be redistributed to the customers who pre-ordered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t say any of this to knock Star Labs or the device; it&amp;rsquo;s just the nature of ordering something that needs to be shipped to the opposite side of the planet during a global pandemic. In fact, the team at Star Labs did really well in setting up a dedicated part of their website to post daily updates on the status starting in October so that everyone knew exactly what was going on. Kudos to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;hardware&#34;&gt;Hardware&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While it was about double the cost of the Pinebook Pro (my Lite Mk III was just over $400 USD when I ordered it), the device itself still feels premium to an order of magnitude higher than what I would&amp;rsquo;ve expected for the price. It came packaged up in a sleek box with a nice, blue microfiber bag around the laptop in the packaging. Another sat between the closed screen and the keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://unusually.pink/images/IMG_0317.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The body of the device is plastic (I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure), but it feels &lt;strong&gt;very&lt;/strong&gt; high quality and sturdy. The hinge for the screen will almost catch me off guard with how strongly it wants to close the last few degrees, but it manages to do this in a way that doesn&amp;rsquo;t make it difficult to open, which is often a problem for such small, light laptops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trackpad is the antithesis of what the Pinebook Pro uses. It&amp;rsquo;s glass rather than plastic, and it&amp;rsquo;s incredibly snappy. Whereas the Pinebook Pro trackpad feels clunky and inaccurate, the Like Mk III feels precise. I&amp;rsquo;ve been extremely impressed with it. The keyboard, unfortunately, it&amp;rsquo;s quite as glowing. I mean, it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;literally&lt;/em&gt; glowing in that it&amp;rsquo;s backlit, and generally it feels good to type on with a decent bit of travel on the keys. The keys don&amp;rsquo;t always feel responsive, though, and hitting them in slightly the wrong way will often result in the keys failing to register the keystroke. I notice this most commonly in the way that I hit the L and Spacebar keys, though the problem occurs on others as well. It&amp;rsquo;s not a deal breaker, but it can be frustrating at times given that I type quickly and often have to go back and fix myriad errors. For the most part, I&amp;rsquo;m impressed with the amount of space they managed to give the keyboard on such a small device, though as I mentioned in my post about the &lt;a href=&#34;https://unusually.pink/keychron-k2-v2/&#34;&gt;Keychron K2 V2&lt;/a&gt;, the dedicated arrow keys resulted in a &lt;em&gt;tiny&lt;/em&gt; right Shift key; whereas the Shift keys are normally at least double the width of the standard letter keys, the right Shift is actually &lt;strong&gt;smaller&lt;/strong&gt; than the letter keys. Originally this resulted in my accidentally hitting the Up arrow key when I wanted to hit Shift, but after a couple of weeks I began to adjust. I&amp;rsquo;m still not perfect with it, but it&amp;rsquo;s not as problematic as I had been worried that it might be. It&amp;rsquo;s also a nice touch that, since the laptop is designed for Linux, it actually features Ctrl, Fn, Super, and Alt keys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://unusually.pink/images/IMG_0319.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The display is a rather nice 1080p IPS, which has all of the benefits and drawbacks one might expect on an 11&amp;quot; device. While everything looks extremely crisp, I have to adjust the text size in basically every application in order to be able to read anything. My eyesight is rather poor, so your mileage may vary, but for anyone with vision problems the zoom functionality and adjustable font sizes will be essential. The speakers aren&amp;rsquo;t groundbreaking, but they certainly get the job done and can be surprisingly loud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The processor is a Pentium Silver N5000 from Intel. It&amp;rsquo;s fairly low-end, but it gets the job done, and that&amp;rsquo;s exactly what I needed for the price point. It&amp;rsquo;ll occasionally stutter a bit for really heavy web pages or when firing up GIMP to do some light photo editing, but for the most part it chugs along happily. I was extremely impressed that the device actually comes with 8 GB of RAM, which is extremely helpful. I did &lt;a href=&#34;https://unusually.pink/swapfile-fix-on-manjar-linux-pinebook-pro/&#34;&gt;set up a swap file&lt;/a&gt; in order to be able to hibernate the device, but it basically stays untouched during active operation. For storage, it comes with a 240 GB over-provisioned SSD. That&amp;rsquo;s configurable up to 960 GB if you need it, though I was more than fine with 240 GB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While it&amp;rsquo;s not typically something I think too much about when getting new hardware, I have to mention that the charger for the Lite Mk III is extremely nice. It&amp;rsquo;s a slick-looking brick that comes with a blue and black braided USB-C cable. When I think of relatively inexpensive laptops, often the charger is an area where the OEM can save a little money, but that wasn&amp;rsquo;t something they opted for in this case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;software&#34;&gt;Software&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I won&amp;rsquo;t touch too much on this since the experience really comes down to which flavor of Linux you want to install. Star Labs offers most major distros as pre-installed options; I went with Manjaro XFCE since I&amp;rsquo;ve come to enjoy using Manjaro so much on my Pinebook Pro. The experience has been great so far aside from the fact that, after immediately upgrading to the latest Linux kernel after receiving my laptop, I had horrible video issues. I simply reverted back to the latest LTS kernel (which is extremely easy to do in Manjaro), and everything was fine. Ubuntu, Mint, MX Linux, and others are all offered as options and across a wide array of window managers for each. Of course, it&amp;rsquo;s simple to just reinstall any other OS whenever you want since the device is designed to facilitate that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://starlabs.kb.help/updates-upgrades/installing-updates-from-the-lvfs/&#34;&gt;Star Labs uses the LVFS to distribute new firmware&lt;/a&gt;, and it works very well. Along with firmware for the devices that are a part of the laptop, I&amp;rsquo;ve also received firmware upgrades through it for some of my peripherals that I use with it, like my Logitech MX Ergo trackball.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;wrap-up&#34;&gt;Wrap-Up&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://unusually.pink/images/IMG_0318.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the whole, I&amp;rsquo;m fairly pleased with the Lite Mk III. The unreliability of the keyboard is my only major issue that gives me some headaches. Otherwise, it&amp;rsquo;s exactly what I was looking for in a small, inexpensive Linux laptop. I really hope more Linux-focused OEMs consider making an entrance into this particular market for people who want something basically on the order of a Chromebook but without any Google nonsense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t think I could use the Lite Mk III as my &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; laptop, but for any Linux nerds like myself who are looking for a supplementary device it makes for a great fit. Add in the fact that the warranty allows for the device to be opened by the user and repairs made without voiding it &amp;ndash; the &lt;a href=&#34;https://starlabs.kb.help/star-lite-mk-ii/star-lite-mk-ii-complete-disassembly-guide/&#34;&gt;company even offers a disassembly guide&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ndash; and there&amp;rsquo;s a lot to like.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Swapfile Fix on Manjaro Linux Pinebook Pro</title>
      <link>https://unusually.pink/swapfile-fix-on-manjaro-linux-pinebook-pro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unusually.pink/swapfile-fix-on-manjaro-linux-pinebook-pro/</guid>
      <description>I wrote about a month ago of an update on my Pinebook Pro after switching to Manjaro Linux. I continue to make heavy use of my Pinebook Pro while I&amp;rsquo;m still social distancing and staying at home, giving me lots of time to work on personal projects without much else to do.
Today I ran into an interesting issue, though, after applying a round of updates. I mentioned in my last Pinebook Pro post about going through the process of creating a swapfile using the directions from the Manjaro wiki so that I could hibernate the machine and get much better battery life.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;I wrote about a month ago of an update &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unusually.pink/blog/unusually-pink-impressions-pinebook-pro&#34;&gt;on my Pinebook Pro&lt;/a&gt; after &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unusually.pink/blog/pinebook-pro-follow-up-manjaro-linux&#34;&gt;switching to Manjaro Linux&lt;/a&gt;. I continue to make heavy use of my Pinebook Pro while I&amp;rsquo;m still social distancing and staying at home, giving me lots of time to work on personal projects without much else to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today I ran into an interesting issue, though, after applying a round of updates. I mentioned in my last Pinebook Pro post about going through the process of creating a swapfile using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.manjaro.org/index.php?title=Swap#Using_a_Swapfile&#34;&gt;directions from the Manjaro wiki&lt;/a&gt; so that I could hibernate the machine and get &lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt; better battery life. I literally just opened the device back up, though, and saw a familiar message that there wasn&amp;rsquo;t enough swap space to successfully hibernate the machine, leaving me with about 20% less battery life than I had been expecting. Running &lt;code&gt;htop&lt;/code&gt; quickly showed me that my swap space was back to nothing. Weird.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following the instructions, my swapfile is literally called &lt;strong&gt;swapfile&lt;/strong&gt; on the root of the filesystem. I verified it was still in place with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;ll / | grep swap
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the file still in place, I ran through the instructions again. These ones were both successful:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo mkswap /swapfile
sudo chmod u=rw,go= /swapfile
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;I got an error when running this, though:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo swapon /swappfile
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;This told me:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;swapon: /swapfile: swapon failed: Invalid argument&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Weird. I verified that I still had my swapfile entry in &lt;code&gt;/etc/fstab&lt;/code&gt; to assign the swapfile on boot by running:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo cat /etc/fstab
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;I tried running the &lt;code&gt;swapon&lt;/code&gt; command a different way to have it apply everything in the &lt;code&gt;fstab&lt;/code&gt; file:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo swapon -a
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;This gave me another &amp;ldquo;Invalid argument&amp;rdquo; error still referencing &amp;ldquo;/swapfile&amp;rdquo;. At this point, I took to the Internet. After a couple of searches, I stumbled across &lt;a href=&#34;https://unix.stackexchange.com/questions/294600/i-cant-enable-swap-space-on-centos-7&#34;&gt;a matching Stack Exchange question&lt;/a&gt;. The top answer claims that the issue is the initial &lt;code&gt;fallocate&lt;/code&gt; command used to create the file (the same command used in the Manjaro wiki) doesn&amp;rsquo;t physically allocate the 4 GB on the storage for speed, but that&amp;rsquo;s apparently problematic for &lt;code&gt;swapon&lt;/code&gt;. Following that answer, I ran a &lt;code&gt;dd&lt;/code&gt; command to replace my swapfile with something physically allocated:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo dd if=/dev/zero of=/swapfile count=4096 bs=1MiB
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;This takes a few moments to run, especially on the eMMC storage of the Pinebook Pro. Once it completed, though, I repeated the other commands and verified they were all successful. Sure enough, running &lt;code&gt;htop&lt;/code&gt; once again shows my 4 GB of allocated swap space.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pinebook Pro Follow-up: Manjaro Linux</title>
      <link>https://unusually.pink/pinebook-pro-follow-up-manjaro-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unusually.pink/pinebook-pro-follow-up-manjaro-linux/</guid>
      <description>I had written in early February about my Pinebook Pro laptop after roughly a month of using it. Now that significantly more time has passed, time which I&amp;rsquo;ve almost exclusively spent at home due to nationwide stay-at-home orders and social distancing, I figure I&amp;rsquo;d share some of my thoughts on the laptop I raved about initially, and more specifically what I&amp;rsquo;ve done with the operating system.
The OS If you read my original post then you may recall that I was debating swapping the default Debian operating system for something different.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;I had &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unusually.pink/blog/unusually-pink-impressions-pinebook-pro&#34;&gt;written in early February about my Pinebook Pro laptop&lt;/a&gt; after roughly a month of using it. Now that significantly more time has passed, time which I&amp;rsquo;ve almost exclusively spent at home due to nationwide stay-at-home orders and social distancing, I figure I&amp;rsquo;d share some of my thoughts on the laptop I raved about initially, and more specifically what I&amp;rsquo;ve done with the operating system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-os&#34;&gt;The OS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you read my original post then you may recall that I was debating swapping the default Debian operating system for something different. While I mentioned NetBSD in the post I ended up installing &lt;a href=&#34;https://manjaro.org/&#34;&gt;Manjaro Linux&lt;/a&gt; instead. Why? There are a few reasons to consider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest reasons why swapping the OS can be considered important is that there are some issues with the Debian build that came on my device. It&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mrfixit2001/debian_desktop&#34;&gt;custom setup put together by a community member&lt;/a&gt;. It looks incredible, but that comes at a cost; the highly customized environment means that many things in it &lt;em&gt;cannot&lt;/em&gt; be updated; this includes both Chromium and Firefox. Running outdated browsers isn&amp;rsquo;t exactly cool, and I wasn&amp;rsquo;t too keen on having to compile Firefox from source every time there was a new release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand many of the community members seemed to really love Manjaro Linux, so I figured I&amp;rsquo;d gvie it a shot. Along with people in the Pinebook community raving about it, it&amp;rsquo;s also been hovering near the top of &lt;a href=&#34;https://distrowatch.com/&#34;&gt;Distrowatch&lt;/a&gt; for a while now. In fact it was &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pine64.org/2020/03/15/march-update-manjaro-on-pinebook-pro-pinephone-software/&#34;&gt;announced in March&lt;/a&gt; that Manjaro was going to be the default OS for new Pinebook Pro devices, which is pretty slick! They&amp;rsquo;re shipping with the KDE variant, though, and while I&amp;rsquo;ve read about people having a good experience with that, I personaly prefer the more lightweight &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.xfce.org/&#34;&gt;XFCE desktop&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s lighter, simpler, and overall I feel like it&amp;rsquo;s a better fit for the Pinebook Pro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;getting-the-os&#34;&gt;Getting The OS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As something of a noob when it comes to working with open source SoC setups like a Rock64 or Raspberry Pi, I struggled a little with figuring out exactly how to install a new OS on the Pinebook Pro. The first thing I figured out is that, currently, you cannot boot the Pinebook Pro from USB. I made a few bootable flash drives like I would&amp;rsquo;ve historically used when installing Linux on a more traditional device without success. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.pine64.org/index.php/Pinebook_Pro&#34;&gt;Pinebook Pro wiki&lt;/a&gt; seems to contradict itself on this point, saying:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Pinebook Pro is capable of booting from eMMC, USB 2.0, USB 3.0, or an SD card. It cannot boot from USB-C. The boot order of the hard-coded ROM of its RK3399 SoC is: SPI NOR, eMMC, SD, USB OTG.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then in the very next paragraph it says:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this time, the Pinebook Pro ships with a Debian + MATE build with uboot on the eMMC. Its boot order is: SD, then eMMC. Booting off USB storage is not currently available, but will be in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t put it past myself to just be misunderstanding something, though, so your mileage may vary. As you might be able to guess from the quotes shared above, I just ordred a cheap microSD card online and used that for the OS installation; everything worked great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Manjaro specifically, the best way to get the proper image is to go to the forum announcement for the latest version, like &lt;a href=&#34;https://forum.manjaro.org/t/manjaro-arm-20-04-released/133374&#34;&gt;this one for the 20.04 release&lt;/a&gt;. There you can select the appropriate link for your Pinebook Pro and for your preferred desktop environment. Once you select that, you&amp;rsquo;ll be taken to another page &lt;a href=&#34;https://osdn.net/projects/manjaro-arm/storage/pbpro/xfce/20.04/&#34;&gt;like this one listing all of the images files you can download for that version and desktop environment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be aware that if you want to install Manjaro &lt;strong&gt;directly on the laptop&lt;/strong&gt;, be sure to grab the image file with &amp;ldquo;emmc-installer&amp;rdquo; in the file name! This is the image designed to be flashed onto the internal eMMC storage of the Pinebook Pro! Grabbing the image without this will simply create a microSD card that will run the OS. This isn&amp;rsquo;t bad if you&amp;rsquo;d like to try out Manjaro while leaving the Debian installation on your eMMC, but I wanted to go all-in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;preparing-your-media&#34;&gt;Preparing Your Media&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To prepare the media, you can use basically any option that&amp;rsquo;ll allow you to flash the .img file you downloaded onto the microSD card. You can be old-school and use &lt;code&gt;dd&lt;/code&gt; from the command line, but I went easy mode and used &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.balena.io/etcher/&#34;&gt;balenaEtcher&lt;/a&gt; instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-rest&#34;&gt;The Rest&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The boot order on the Pinebook Pro automatically has the microSD card slot above the eMMC, so once you have a microSD card prepared just insert it into the Pinebook Pro, boot the device, and follow the prompts; it&amp;rsquo;s honestly pretty simple to install. The only catch is a known bug with the 20.04 release where you have to hit &lt;code&gt;Esc&lt;/code&gt; while looking at the Manjaro logo after booting from the microSD card before it&amp;rsquo;ll move forward; as a known bug I would imagine this won&amp;rsquo;t be relevant for future releases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the Manjaro logo has been present for about 15 seconds, press ESC (this is a bug, we know).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once it&amp;rsquo;s all done, you boot to this gorgeous view!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://unusually.pink/images/PinebookProFollow-upManjaroLinux_manjaro_pbp_xfce.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;caveats&#34;&gt;Caveats&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the most part, Manjaro works like a complete dream, and I&amp;rsquo;ve been extremely happy with it. There are just a couple of caveats that might be worth mentioning, though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;initial-update&#34;&gt;Initial Update&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, there was a bug when running the initial software update on the factory image. First I had to figure out &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; to update it, but after some quick DuckDuckGo-fu (since I&amp;rsquo;ve really only used Debian-based flavors of Linux before) I figured I could update Manjaro via:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34; data-lang=&#34;shell&#34;&gt;sudo pacman -Syyu
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Note that you can aslo just click the little shield icon in the bottom-right corner of the screen. Regardless of method, though, immediately after booting my new OS I would get the following error when attempting to update:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conflicting files: nss /usr/lib/p11-kit-trust.so already exists in filesystem&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another benefit to choosing Manjaro is that it has an extremely active community, so it&amp;rsquo;s easy to search on errors like this and get solutions! I quickly found a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NexyTfO0iuY&#34;&gt;YouTube video&lt;/a&gt; covering this error and providing the solution:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34; data-lang=&#34;shell&#34;&gt;sudo pacman -Syyu --overwrite /usr/lib*/p11-kit-trust.so
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;After that initial update succeeded I&amp;rsquo;ve been able to perform subsequent updates without needing the &lt;code&gt;--overwrite&lt;/code&gt; parameter. Updating via the GUI also works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;swap&#34;&gt;Swap&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s entirely possible I just made a mistake in my installation, but I eventually realized that I didn&amp;rsquo;t have a swap partition or file. I realized this because I noticed that the battery drain while under suspend was a bit severe; I was losing roughly 6% of my battery per hour. This meant that leaving the device on suspend for a day would completely drain a full battery. I changed my XFCE setting so that when closing the lid of the device it would hibernate. This gave me an error, though, that I didn&amp;rsquo;t have enough swap space to hibernate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I checked the output of &lt;code&gt;htop&lt;/code&gt; and realized that I didn&amp;rsquo;t have enough space because I didn&amp;rsquo;t have &lt;strong&gt;any&lt;/strong&gt; swap. Luckily for me, the Manjaro folks have a wiki page dedicated to exactly this; I ended up following the steps to &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.manjaro.org/index.php?title=Swap#Using_a_Swapfile&#34;&gt;create a swapfile rather than adjusting my partitions to have a swap partition&lt;/a&gt;. Since there are 4 GB of RAM in the Pinebook Pro, I ended up creating a 4 GB swap file. Once it&amp;rsquo;s created you can verify it by looking at &lt;code&gt;htop&lt;/code&gt; or running &lt;code&gt;swapon&lt;/code&gt;. If you&amp;rsquo;re concerned about the amount of storage on the eMMC, you can see how much you&amp;rsquo;re using via:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34; data-lang=&#34;shell&#34;&gt;df -H | grep /$
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;typing-and-the-touchpad&#34;&gt;Typing and the Touchpad&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed on occasion is that typing does not disable the touchpad on the laptop, meaning that it&amp;rsquo;s easy for your hand to accidentally brush it, clicking somewhere else and causing a bit of havoc on whatever it is you&amp;rsquo;re trying to do. I&amp;rsquo;ve accidentally done it once just while working on this article. I&amp;rsquo;ve not found a solution for this yet (I&amp;rsquo;ll update the post if I do), but it hasn&amp;rsquo;t been a big deal for me. It&amp;rsquo;s just something to be mindful about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-end&#34;&gt;The End&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the whole, I&amp;rsquo;m &lt;em&gt;extremely&lt;/em&gt; pleased with my switch to Manjaro. If you&amp;rsquo;re running a Pinebook Pro with the original Debian build, I&amp;rsquo;d highly recommend giving Manjaro a shot; it honestly feels like a whole new device afterward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unusually.pink/blog/its-all-about-open-source&#34;&gt;open source love alive&lt;/a&gt;, and stay pink!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
