<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>star-lite on Unusually Pink</title>
    <link>https://hugo.unusually.pink/tags/star-lite/</link>
    <description>Recent content in star-lite on Unusually Pink</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>2021</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hugo.unusually.pink/tags/star-lite/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Upgrading Star Labs Firmware On Manjaro Linux</title>
      <link>https://hugo.unusually.pink/posts/upgrading-star-labs-firmware-on-manjaro-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hugo.unusually.pink/posts/upgrading-star-labs-firmware-on-manjaro-linux/</guid>
      <description>As you may recall, I purchased a new Linux laptop from Star Labs a while back. It’s a solid little device, though I admittedly haven’t been using it as much as I anticipated due to my increased reliance on my iPads. For more information on that, look for the new Same Shade Of Difference podcast episode that should be dropping very soon. That being said, because I don’t have the worst operational security ever, I do update my laptop every time I happen to see that something is pending.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;As you may recall, I &lt;a href=&#34;https://unusually.pink/star-lite-mk-iii/&#34;&gt;purchased a new Linux laptop from Star Labs&lt;/a&gt; a while back. It’s a solid little device, though I admittedly haven’t been using it as much as I anticipated due to my increased reliance on my iPads. For more information on that, look for the new &lt;a href=&#34;https://sameshadeofdifference.com&#34;&gt;Same Shade Of Difference&lt;/a&gt; podcast episode that should be dropping &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; soon. That being said, because I don’t have the worst operational security ever, I do update my laptop every time I happen to see that something is pending. Given that I run &lt;a href=&#34;https://manjaro.org&#34;&gt;Manjaro Linux&lt;/a&gt;, that tends to happen frequently. Manjaro is what’s known as an evergreen Linux distribution. It uses a rolling release cycle, meaning that there are no new “major” releases of the OS. For example, there’s no equivalent in Manjaro of moving from Ubuntu 20.04 to Ubuntu 20.10. Occasionally the maintainers spin off a new .iso with updated packages, but that’s just to save users from having to upgrade an insane number of packages when they do a fresh installation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I’ve been diligent about upgrading my OS and my Linux kernels (which Manjaro also provides a nice manager for), I’ve neglected to upgrade my firmware. Fortunately, Star Labs makes this process extremely simple. All of their firmware is published to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/StarLabsLtd/firmware?utm_campaign=9th%20March%202020%20coreboot%20MK%20III%20%28TQpHxp%29&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_source=Newsletter&amp;amp;_ke=eyJrbF9jb21wYW55X2lkIjogIlBjaGtVQyIsICJrbF9lbWFpbCI6ICJqamZhYnJ5QHByb3Rvbm1haWwuY29tIn0%3D&#34;&gt;their GitHub account&lt;/a&gt;. There’s no need to actually keep tabs on that if you don’t want to, though, because Star Labs also sends periodic emails announcing firmware updates for their devices. I obviously can’t speak to how deep into the lifecycle of each device these may go, but at least for the time being it’s extremely helpful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even better, when it comes to installing firmware there’s a dedicated utility for it. They cover the &lt;a href=&#34;https://support.starlabs.systems/articles/installing-updates-from-the-lvfs?utm_campaign=9th%20March%202020%20coreboot%20MK%20III%20%28TQpHxp%29&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_source=Newsletter&amp;amp;_ke=eyJrbF9jb21wYW55X2lkIjogIlBjaGtVQyIsICJrbF9lbWFpbCI6ICJqamZhYnJ5QHByb3Rvbm1haWwuY29tIn0%3D&#34;&gt;gamut of options on their support site&lt;/a&gt; since they support a large number of Linux variants, but for Manjaro you just need to start by installing a couple of additional packages:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34; data-lang=&#34;shell&#34;&gt;sudo pacman -Sy fwupd gnome-firmware
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I realized after the fact that I probably &lt;em&gt;didn’t&lt;/em&gt; need &lt;strong&gt;gnome-firmware&lt;/strong&gt; since I’m unlikely to ever use the GUI for this, but it’s not as though the application takes up a large degree of space. Once the packages are installed, the next step is to check for any new firmware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34; data-lang=&#34;shell&#34;&gt;sudo fwupdmgr refresh
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This should report back if there are new firmware updates. In my case, it reported firmware updates for 2 items, one of which was 3 revisions out of date. Yikes! I kicked off the firmware upgrade via:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34; data-lang=&#34;shell&#34;&gt;sudo fwupdmgr update
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s worth mentioning that the system will complain if you run the above command without having a power source connected since, generally, upgrading firmware and losing power in the middle of the process is a recipe for bricking your device. If power isn’t connected, though, it’ll very smartly prompt you to connect power and retry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the installation kicks off, the device will need to reboot. After the reboot, you’ll land in the firmware itself and be prompted to confirm the upgrades you’re about to apply. Use the arrow keys to move to the bottom and apply the pending changes (they’ll be pending by default.) This may take some time, and in my case the firmware application would move from 0% to 100% multiple times without any indication it was at different stages or anything like that. I recommend getting some coffee and letting your device do its thing. Once the upgrades are fully completed, you’ll be prompted to hit literally any key to kick off another reboot. This reboot will take noticeably longer than a normal reboot, and you’ll spend a decent amount of time staring at a black screen before you even see the Star Labs logo appear like you normally would during the boot cycle. Patience is a virtue, so just let the device do its thing. Eventually you should see the login screen you know and love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At that point, just log back in and everything should be running as expected with the new firmware. If you want to be certain, running&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34; data-lang=&#34;shell&#34;&gt;fwupdmgr refresh
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; again should confirm there are no longer any pending firmware upgrades. It’s also worth mentioning that, during the upgrade process, many peripherals may end up being disconnected if the device is docked or anything like that. In my case the laptop was running standalone with nothing but AC power connected. The upgrade utility also very kindly warns you of this ahead of time, so just be on the lookout for the messages it gives you as you go through the upgrade process. The tl;dr is that if you read the output given to you by &lt;strong&gt;fwupdmgr&lt;/strong&gt;, everything should go smoothly.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Star Lite Mk III</title>
      <link>https://hugo.unusually.pink/posts/star-lite-mk-iii/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hugo.unusually.pink/posts/star-lite-mk-iii/</guid>
      <description>After spending some quality time with my Pinebook Pro, I decided that I wanted something slightly more powerful for my personal laptop. While most of my heavy-lifting in the world of computers is done with my MacBook Pro for work (which was recently upgraded to a device featuring the new M1 chips; look for more on that soon both here and on the Same Shade of Difference podcast), the Pinebook Pro&amp;rsquo;s extremely weak ARM processor wasn&amp;rsquo;t quite cutting it.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;After spending some quality time with my &lt;a href=&#34;https://unusually.pink/unusually-pink-impressions-pinebook-pro/&#34;&gt;Pinebook Pro&lt;/a&gt;, I decided that I wanted something &lt;em&gt;slightly&lt;/em&gt; more powerful for my personal laptop. While most of my heavy-lifting in the world of computers is done with my MacBook Pro for work (which was recently upgraded to a device featuring the new M1 chips; look for more on that soon both here and on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sameshadeofdifference.com/&#34;&gt;Same Shade of Difference podcast&lt;/a&gt;), the Pinebook Pro&amp;rsquo;s extremely weak ARM processor wasn&amp;rsquo;t quite cutting it. Even doing things like writing up blog posts in the WordPress editor would occasionally lag, and watching videos above 720p is essentially impossible. I was still infatuated with the idea of a low-cost Linux laptop, though. I love using Linux, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t exactly need a workhorse device from somewhere like &lt;a href=&#34;https://system76.com/laptops&#34;&gt;System 76&lt;/a&gt; just to write blog posts, maintain a couple of websites, watch videos, and play chess. After going down a rabbit hole of trying to find a (relatively) inexpensive Linux laptop (spoiler alert: they&amp;rsquo;re rare), I decided to pre-order the &lt;a href=&#34;https://starlabs.systems/pages/lite-mk-iii&#34;&gt;Star Lite Mk III from Star Labs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;shipping&#34;&gt;Shipping&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I originally pre-ordered the laptop in the summer, with a shipping estimate of early September. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t exactly in a rush, so that wasn&amp;rsquo;t a problem for me. The global pandemic caused something of a cascading series of delays which ultimately meant that I didn&amp;rsquo;t receive my device until mid-November. For example, production delays in China that ran behind became exacerbated when the factory closed due to &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Golden_Week_(China)&#34;&gt;Golden Week&lt;/a&gt;. Star Labs is based in the UK, so once production and QA were done, the devices shipped from the factory in China to the UK. There they were held up in customs for an entire week before they actually reached Star Labs in order to be redistributed to the customers who pre-ordered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t say any of this to knock Star Labs or the device; it&amp;rsquo;s just the nature of ordering something that needs to be shipped to the opposite side of the planet during a global pandemic. In fact, the team at Star Labs did really well in setting up a dedicated part of their website to post daily updates on the status starting in October so that everyone knew exactly what was going on. Kudos to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;hardware&#34;&gt;Hardware&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While it was about double the cost of the Pinebook Pro (my Lite Mk III was just over $400 USD when I ordered it), the device itself still feels premium to an order of magnitude higher than what I would&amp;rsquo;ve expected for the price. It came packaged up in a sleek box with a nice, blue microfiber bag around the laptop in the packaging. Another sat between the closed screen and the keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/IMG_0317.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The body of the device is plastic (I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure), but it feels &lt;strong&gt;very&lt;/strong&gt; high quality and sturdy. The hinge for the screen will almost catch me off guard with how strongly it wants to close the last few degrees, but it manages to do this in a way that doesn&amp;rsquo;t make it difficult to open, which is often a problem for such small, light laptops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trackpad is the antithesis of what the Pinebook Pro uses. It&amp;rsquo;s glass rather than plastic, and it&amp;rsquo;s incredibly snappy. Whereas the Pinebook Pro trackpad feels clunky and inaccurate, the Like Mk III feels precise. I&amp;rsquo;ve been extremely impressed with it. The keyboard, unfortunately, it&amp;rsquo;s quite as glowing. I mean, it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;literally&lt;/em&gt; glowing in that it&amp;rsquo;s backlit, and generally it feels good to type on with a decent bit of travel on the keys. The keys don&amp;rsquo;t always feel responsive, though, and hitting them in slightly the wrong way will often result in the keys failing to register the keystroke. I notice this most commonly in the way that I hit the L and Spacebar keys, though the problem occurs on others as well. It&amp;rsquo;s not a deal breaker, but it can be frustrating at times given that I type quickly and often have to go back and fix myriad errors. For the most part, I&amp;rsquo;m impressed with the amount of space they managed to give the keyboard on such a small device, though as I mentioned in my post about the &lt;a href=&#34;https://unusually.pink/keychron-k2-v2/&#34;&gt;Keychron K2 V2&lt;/a&gt;, the dedicated arrow keys resulted in a &lt;em&gt;tiny&lt;/em&gt; right Shift key; whereas the Shift keys are normally at least double the width of the standard letter keys, the right Shift is actually &lt;strong&gt;smaller&lt;/strong&gt; than the letter keys. Originally this resulted in my accidentally hitting the Up arrow key when I wanted to hit Shift, but after a couple of weeks I began to adjust. I&amp;rsquo;m still not perfect with it, but it&amp;rsquo;s not as problematic as I had been worried that it might be. It&amp;rsquo;s also a nice touch that, since the laptop is designed for Linux, it actually features Ctrl, Fn, Super, and Alt keys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/IMG_0319.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The display is a rather nice 1080p IPS, which has all of the benefits and drawbacks one might expect on an 11&amp;quot; device. While everything looks extremely crisp, I have to adjust the text size in basically every application in order to be able to read anything. My eyesight is rather poor, so your mileage may vary, but for anyone with vision problems the zoom functionality and adjustable font sizes will be essential. The speakers aren&amp;rsquo;t groundbreaking, but they certainly get the job done and can be surprisingly loud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The processor is a Pentium Silver N5000 from Intel. It&amp;rsquo;s fairly low-end, but it gets the job done, and that&amp;rsquo;s exactly what I needed for the price point. It&amp;rsquo;ll occasionally stutter a bit for really heavy web pages or when firing up GIMP to do some light photo editing, but for the most part it chugs along happily. I was extremely impressed that the device actually comes with 8 GB of RAM, which is extremely helpful. I did &lt;a href=&#34;https://unusually.pink/swapfile-fix-on-manjar-linux-pinebook-pro/&#34;&gt;set up a swap file&lt;/a&gt; in order to be able to hibernate the device, but it basically stays untouched during active operation. For storage, it comes with a 240 GB over-provisioned SSD. That&amp;rsquo;s configurable up to 960 GB if you need it, though I was more than fine with 240 GB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While it&amp;rsquo;s not typically something I think too much about when getting new hardware, I have to mention that the charger for the Lite Mk III is extremely nice. It&amp;rsquo;s a slick-looking brick that comes with a blue and black braided USB-C cable. When I think of relatively inexpensive laptops, often the charger is an area where the OEM can save a little money, but that wasn&amp;rsquo;t something they opted for in this case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;software&#34;&gt;Software&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I won&amp;rsquo;t touch too much on this since the experience really comes down to which flavor of Linux you want to install. Star Labs offers most major distros as pre-installed options; I went with Manjaro XFCE since I&amp;rsquo;ve come to enjoy using Manjaro so much on my Pinebook Pro. The experience has been great so far aside from the fact that, after immediately upgrading to the latest Linux kernel after receiving my laptop, I had horrible video issues. I simply reverted back to the latest LTS kernel (which is extremely easy to do in Manjaro), and everything was fine. Ubuntu, Mint, MX Linux, and others are all offered as options and across a wide array of window managers for each. Of course, it&amp;rsquo;s simple to just reinstall any other OS whenever you want since the device is designed to facilitate that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://starlabs.kb.help/updates-upgrades/installing-updates-from-the-lvfs/&#34;&gt;Star Labs uses the LVFS to distribute new firmware&lt;/a&gt;, and it works very well. Along with firmware for the devices that are a part of the laptop, I&amp;rsquo;ve also received firmware upgrades through it for some of my peripherals that I use with it, like my Logitech MX Ergo trackball.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;wrap-up&#34;&gt;Wrap-Up&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/IMG_0318.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the whole, I&amp;rsquo;m fairly pleased with the Lite Mk III. The unreliability of the keyboard is my only major issue that gives me some headaches. Otherwise, it&amp;rsquo;s exactly what I was looking for in a small, inexpensive Linux laptop. I really hope more Linux-focused OEMs consider making an entrance into this particular market for people who want something basically on the order of a Chromebook but without any Google nonsense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t think I could use the Lite Mk III as my &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; laptop, but for any Linux nerds like myself who are looking for a supplementary device it makes for a great fit. Add in the fact that the warranty allows for the device to be opened by the user and repairs made without voiding it &amp;ndash; the &lt;a href=&#34;https://starlabs.kb.help/star-lite-mk-ii/star-lite-mk-ii-complete-disassembly-guide/&#34;&gt;company even offers a disassembly guide&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ndash; and there&amp;rsquo;s a lot to like.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
