<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>dropbox-passwords on Unusually Pink</title>
    <link>https://hugo.unusually.pink/tags/dropbox-passwords/</link>
    <description>Recent content in dropbox-passwords on Unusually Pink</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>2021</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hugo.unusually.pink/tags/dropbox-passwords/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>RememBear Password Manager</title>
      <link>https://hugo.unusually.pink/posts/remembear-password-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hugo.unusually.pink/posts/remembear-password-manager/</guid>
      <description>A few weeks ago I received an email offering to let me try the premium variant of the RememBear password manager for a year for free. I assume that I received this since I currently have an active TunnelBear subscription that I use for my VPN. I didn&amp;rsquo;t bother looking into things too closely, but my understanding is that you can normally use RememBear for free, but syncing your passwords between multiple devices requires a premium subscription&amp;hellip; meaning that in 2020 when people have a phone, a tablet, and at least one computer, a premium subscription is basically a requirement.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago I received an email offering to let me try the premium variant of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.remembear.com/&#34;&gt;RememBear&lt;/a&gt; password manager for a year for free. I assume that I received this since I currently have an active TunnelBear subscription that I use for my VPN. I didn&amp;rsquo;t bother looking into things too closely, but my understanding is that you can normally use RememBear for free, but syncing your passwords between multiple devices requires a premium subscription&amp;hellip; meaning that in 2020 when people have a phone, a tablet, and at &lt;strong&gt;least&lt;/strong&gt; one computer, a premium subscription is basically a requirement. I figured that I may as well give it a shot in order to see if it could possibly tide me over until &lt;a href=&#34;https://unusually.pink/dropbox-passwords/&#34;&gt;Dropbox Passwords&lt;/a&gt; is a bit more mature; a year of free service seems like a good bit of time for the Dropbox team to improve upon their product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The RememBear apps for macOS, iOS, and iPadOS are all very slick. They feature the same cute, cartoon bear as TunnelBear. If I type in my master password on macOS, the bear will even move its head to follow along as I type. That being said, typing in my master password happens infrequently since the apps on all 3 platforms work really well with Touch ID and Face ID.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The apps on all 3 platforms also do well with auto-filling passwords for me, including with the browser extension for Safari on macOS. Likewise, the iPadOS app is, mercifully, an iPad application rather than the expanded iOS app. I did run into a few random bugs on macOS where the application would be blank after unlocking it, showing as if I didn&amp;rsquo;t have any logins stored. I saw another issue where my logins were all listed, but using the search feature wouldn&amp;rsquo;t return any results even if there were matches. In both cases, closing out of the application and re-opening it fixed the problem, and I only encountered each bug once.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/remembear.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adding new devices or recovering your account is streamlined with a QR code mechanism that leverages another device which already has RememBear configured on it. This makes the setup quick and easy, though it remains unclear what recourse there is if the master password itself is lost and no other devices are configured. They don&amp;rsquo;t give you anything like the secret word list for Dropbox Passwords or the secret key from 1Password.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the nice benefits to RememBear over the immaturity of Dropbox Passwords is that it does offer an option for creating and syncing secure notes. I frequently use these for things like saving WiFi pre-shared keys. Unfortunately, I&amp;rsquo;ve had to start using these for saving API keys, too, because RememBear doesn&amp;rsquo;t offer the option to add multiple credential fields for each login. I can also store them, much as I did with Dropbox Passwords, in the provided notes section for each login, though it does make copying and pasting the keys a bit more annoying than in something like 1Password or Bitwarden which simply give you the option to add multiple credential fields.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biggest issue with Dropbox Passwords, though, is unfortunately shared with RememBear: there is no web-only option. Installing the browser extension for Firefox, for example, will not work on my Manjaro Linux laptops because the desktop client is still expected and there is no Linux application. This was really surprising to me since one of the reasons I initially started using &lt;a href=&#34;https://unusually.pink/chromebooks-vpns-and-you/&#34;&gt;TunnelBear as my VPN service was due to the fact that they offered a standalone browser extension that I could use back when I had Chromebooks&lt;/a&gt; which couldn&amp;rsquo;t install any type of full-fledged VPN client. Given that RememBear has been around for at least a few years and is by no means a new product, I did a little bit of digging to see if there were any plans to support Linux or Chrome OS (while I no longer use Chromebooks because Google is pretty gross, Chrome OS support would indicate a standalone browser extension.) The latest I could find was a comment from May of 2019 on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/remembear/ehpbfbahieociaeckccnklpdcmfaeegd&#34;&gt;Chrome extension&lt;/a&gt; which simply confirmed Linux and Chrome OS weren&amp;rsquo;t supported.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With its slick, cute, and bear-laden UI, RememBear is probably one of the nicest-looking and most user-friendly password managers around. For the overwhelming majority of people, it also likely ticks all of the boxes they would care about as far as features are concerned. Any Linux users out there, though, will be disappointed with the complete inability to use it with their operating system of choice. Here&amp;rsquo;s to hoping for web support or a standalone browser extension at some point in the future, but for the time being Linux aficionados are better off sticking with something like 1Password or Bitwarden.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dropbox Passwords</title>
      <link>https://hugo.unusually.pink/posts/dropbox-passwords/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hugo.unusually.pink/posts/dropbox-passwords/</guid>
      <description>I tend to pay for a lot of subscription services. In fact, my friend Mark and I have enough of them between us that we needed not one but two episodes of our podcast just to talk about all of our subscriptions. Since the pandemic means I have nothing better to do with my time than sit around and think about things like how much money I spend on subscriptions, though, I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about which ones I might be able to do without, which ones I could swap for cheaper services, etc.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;I tend to pay for a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of subscription services. In fact, my friend Mark and I have enough of them between us that we needed not &lt;a href=&#34;https://sameshadeofdifference.com/episodes/mo-money-mo-money&#34;&gt;one&lt;/a&gt; but &lt;a href=&#34;https://sameshadeofdifference.com/episodes/even-mo-money&#34;&gt;two&lt;/a&gt; episodes of our podcast just to talk about all of our subscriptions. Since the pandemic means I have nothing better to do with my time than sit around and think about things like how much money I spend on subscriptions, though, I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about which ones I might be able to do without, which ones I could swap for cheaper services, etc. to save myself a little bit of money each year. It often feels trivial to tack on yet another thing that costs $5 - $10 a month, but over the course of the year it adds up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enter &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dropbox.com/features/security/passwords&#34;&gt;Dropbox Passwords&lt;/a&gt;, a password manager built into Dropbox. In the past I&amp;rsquo;ve used Dropbox to sync passwords in conjunction with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.keepassx.org/&#34;&gt;KeePassX&lt;/a&gt;, so having the same functionality built directly into the platform seemed nice. The fact that it&amp;rsquo;s a feature included with my Dropbox Plus plan and would save me from paying $80 a year for my current password manager is also a nice bonus. First I just had to put it through its paces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;migration&#34;&gt;Migration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Migrating to a new password manager is typically a fairly painless process. Every password manager I&amp;rsquo;ve ever used has given me the option to export my passwords to a variety of plaintext file formats. Naturally, having a plaintext file with all of your credentials is a &lt;em&gt;terrible&lt;/em&gt; idea, but unless the machine you&amp;rsquo;re operating on is a digital cesspool it should be fine for the few minutes it takes to import the file somewhere else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my case, I exported a CSV and imported it into Dropbox Passwords. I initially got a message that there weren&amp;rsquo;t any accounts to import. I opened the CSV file and saw that some of the columns had weird headings and assumed Dropbox didn&amp;rsquo;t know what fields in the CSV mapped to which fields within Passwords. Their &lt;a href=&#34;https://help.dropbox.com/installs-integrations/desktop/how-to-use-dropbox-passwords&#34;&gt;help documentation&lt;/a&gt; covers what&amp;rsquo;s needed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The columns in your CSV file must be labeled so Dropbox Passwords knows how to import the information. Although Dropbox Passwords can recognize a range of labels, we recommend labeling them “Name”, “Password”, “Username”, “Notes”, and “URL”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I updated the column headings to match the documentation above, and everything was fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;desktop-client&#34;&gt;Desktop Client&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The desktop client for Dropbox Passwords is spartan to say the least. You get fields for:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Site Name&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Username&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Password&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;URL&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s it. In other password managers, I frequently leverage either additional passwords or custom fields to add things like app passwords, API keys, etc. While I could store those in the free-form Notes field in Dropbox Passwords, the values aren&amp;rsquo;t masked out like they would be in other services with dedicated fields for this sort of thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the initial setup where I logged in with my Dropbox credentials, the app gave me a &amp;ldquo;word list.&amp;rdquo; This PDF just had 12, random, English words on it. This serves as an extra security mechanism that I&amp;rsquo;ll touch on in the next section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the app was set up, it asked me to create a 6 digit PIN. That PIN is used to unlock the app if it times out due to inactivity. It&amp;rsquo;s worth noting that the browser extensions will &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; autofill login information is the application is currently locked; more on that later as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;mobile-apps&#34;&gt;Mobile Apps&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There isn&amp;rsquo;t too much to say about the mobile apps; they&amp;rsquo;re basically exactly what you would expect. It is worth mentioning that, at the time of this writing, there&amp;rsquo;s no iPad version of the app, meaning I&amp;rsquo;m stuck looking at the blown-up iOS app. It&amp;rsquo;s not a huge ordeal, though, because aside from logging in initially I almost &lt;em&gt;never&lt;/em&gt; open the app itself. Like every other password manager, iOS can be configured to automatically get passwords out of it without requiring an app switch. It also integrates with Face ID and Touch ID on iOS for quick unlocking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;multi-factor-authentication&#34;&gt;Multi Factor Authentication&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dropbox Passwords automatically implements a sort of MFA. When I logged in to the app on my phone, for example, it gave me a prompt on the desktop client. I had to accept the prompt there to confirm that I was, in fact, trying to configure the app on a phone. Likewise, when I configured the app on my iPad, I received a prompt on both my laptop and my phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is where you might wonder what happens if I don&amp;rsquo;t have any of those other devices handy. In that case, I can use the word list to log in. I actually ended up doing this one time, and it worked without a hitch. What happens if I also lose the word list? Let&amp;rsquo;s hope I never find out. It&amp;rsquo;s nice to know, though, that despite the fact that the content is tied to a Dropbox account, Dropbox account credentials alone aren&amp;rsquo;t enough to access it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;browser-extensions&#34;&gt;Browser Extensions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might wonder why I talked about desktop and mobile clients, switched gears to authentication, and then came back to a &amp;ldquo;client.&amp;rdquo; The reason is that the browser extensions are literally just a wrapper that provides integration with the desktop app for things like autofilling credentials. For example, clicking on the Dropbox Passwords extension icon in Safari on macOS doesn&amp;rsquo;t even open a UI for the extension&amp;hellip; it pops open the full Dropbox Passwords client. I see this frequently when nothing autofills in my browser, I click on the icon for the browser extension, and then it opens the full app where I see it requesting my PIN to unlock it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason why wrapper browser extensions are noteworthy for me is that there are &lt;strong&gt;no&lt;/strong&gt; standalone extensions or even direct web access. If Dropbox Passwords doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a client on your platform of choice, you&amp;rsquo;re simply out of luck. For example, I can&amp;rsquo;t access my passwords when using Manjaro Linux on my Pinebook Pro. I verified this by installing the browser extension; clicking on it will bring me to a lovely message that the application isn&amp;rsquo;t available for my platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/dbp_linux-1024x464.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where this seems &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; insane to me is that if I log into my Dropbox account on the web I can &lt;em&gt;see&lt;/em&gt; the vault for Dropbox Passwords! But clicking on it gives me the same screen as shown in the image above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/dropbox.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;rsquo;t actually do anything to access it. Even &lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt; some kind of web portal like I can access with &lt;a href=&#34;https://bitwarden.com/&#34;&gt;Bitwarden&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lastpass.com/&#34;&gt;LastPass&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&#34;https://1password.com/&#34;&gt;1Password&lt;/a&gt; would be better than &lt;strong&gt;nothing&lt;/strong&gt;. I can definitely understand not making a native Linux app a priority, but not having a browser extension or web access in 2020 blows my mind more than a little.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I &lt;strong&gt;really&lt;/strong&gt; hope this is something the Dropbox Passwords team is actively working on. While the overall service isn&amp;rsquo;t quite as slick or polished as some of its competitors, the fact that it comes included with paid Dropbox Plans is a huge boon; people like myself will have to think twice about paying extra money for a service they already have included with their existing Dropbox subscription. There are some hurdles to overcome for Dropbox Passwords to reach parity with its competitors, but for many people it&amp;rsquo;ll be good enough as-is.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
