<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>unusually-pink-playlist on Unusually Pink</title>
    <link>https://hugo.unusually.pink/tags/unusually-pink-playlist/</link>
    <description>Recent content in unusually-pink-playlist on Unusually Pink</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>2021</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hugo.unusually.pink/tags/unusually-pink-playlist/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Unusually Pink Playlist</title>
      <link>https://hugo.unusually.pink/the-unusually-pink-playlist/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hugo.unusually.pink/the-unusually-pink-playlist/</guid>
      <description>Do you want to listen to the dankest collection of music since my 2018 Spotify wrapped post? If your answer is yes (and really… I don’t see a single possible reason why it shouldn’t be) then you’re in luck. We are pleased to introduce the Unusually Pink Playlist. Featuring tracks loved by Brandi and I, most will be more recent discoveries as opposed to old favorites; we don’t really want to start off a brand new playlist with 10+ hours of material right out of the gate… even if it would be really good material.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Do you want to listen to the dankest collection of music since my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unusually.pink/blog/2018-in-music-spotify-wrapped&#34;&gt;2018 Spotify wrapped post&lt;/a&gt;? If your answer is yes (and really… I don’t see a single possible reason why it shouldn’t be) then you’re in luck. We are pleased to introduce the &lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/playlist/26aNDr4SulSOQm1vEzUMpG&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unusually Pink Playlist&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Featuring tracks loved by Brandi and I, most will be more recent discoveries as opposed to old favorites; we don’t really want to start off a brand new playlist with 10+ hours of material right out of the gate… even if it would be &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; good material.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brandi and I have a lot in common when it comes to music, but we also a good bit of diversity and different methods of finding new music. We just start putting this playlist together the other day, but you’ll eventually start seeing plenty of indie, hip-hop, and EDM making the rounds along with some pop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you find yourself enjoying the playlist, feel free to give it a follow! Song recommendations are always welcome; hit us up on Twitter &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/UnusuallyPink&#34;&gt;@UnusuallyPink&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
