<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tunnelbear on Unusually Pink</title>
    <link>https://hugo.unusually.pink/tags/tunnelbear/</link>
    <description>Recent content in tunnelbear on Unusually Pink</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>2021</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hugo.unusually.pink/tags/tunnelbear/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>RememBear Password Manager</title>
      <link>https://hugo.unusually.pink/remembear-password-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hugo.unusually.pink/remembear-password-manager/</guid>
      <description>A few weeks ago I received an email offering to let me try the premium variant of the RememBear password manager for a year for free. I assume that I received this since I currently have an active TunnelBear subscription that I use for my VPN. I didn&amp;rsquo;t bother looking into things too closely, but my understanding is that you can normally use RememBear for free, but syncing your passwords between multiple devices requires a premium subscription&amp;hellip; meaning that in 2020 when people have a phone, a tablet, and at least one computer, a premium subscription is basically a requirement.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago I received an email offering to let me try the premium variant of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.remembear.com/&#34;&gt;RememBear&lt;/a&gt; password manager for a year for free. I assume that I received this since I currently have an active TunnelBear subscription that I use for my VPN. I didn&amp;rsquo;t bother looking into things too closely, but my understanding is that you can normally use RememBear for free, but syncing your passwords between multiple devices requires a premium subscription&amp;hellip; meaning that in 2020 when people have a phone, a tablet, and at &lt;strong&gt;least&lt;/strong&gt; one computer, a premium subscription is basically a requirement. I figured that I may as well give it a shot in order to see if it could possibly tide me over until &lt;a href=&#34;https://unusually.pink/dropbox-passwords/&#34;&gt;Dropbox Passwords&lt;/a&gt; is a bit more mature; a year of free service seems like a good bit of time for the Dropbox team to improve upon their product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The RememBear apps for macOS, iOS, and iPadOS are all very slick. They feature the same cute, cartoon bear as TunnelBear. If I type in my master password on macOS, the bear will even move its head to follow along as I type. That being said, typing in my master password happens infrequently since the apps on all 3 platforms work really well with Touch ID and Face ID.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The apps on all 3 platforms also do well with auto-filling passwords for me, including with the browser extension for Safari on macOS. Likewise, the iPadOS app is, mercifully, an iPad application rather than the expanded iOS app. I did run into a few random bugs on macOS where the application would be blank after unlocking it, showing as if I didn&amp;rsquo;t have any logins stored. I saw another issue where my logins were all listed, but using the search feature wouldn&amp;rsquo;t return any results even if there were matches. In both cases, closing out of the application and re-opening it fixed the problem, and I only encountered each bug once.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hugo.unusually.pink/images/remembear.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adding new devices or recovering your account is streamlined with a QR code mechanism that leverages another device which already has RememBear configured on it. This makes the setup quick and easy, though it remains unclear what recourse there is if the master password itself is lost and no other devices are configured. They don&amp;rsquo;t give you anything like the secret word list for Dropbox Passwords or the secret key from 1Password.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the nice benefits to RememBear over the immaturity of Dropbox Passwords is that it does offer an option for creating and syncing secure notes. I frequently use these for things like saving WiFi pre-shared keys. Unfortunately, I&amp;rsquo;ve had to start using these for saving API keys, too, because RememBear doesn&amp;rsquo;t offer the option to add multiple credential fields for each login. I can also store them, much as I did with Dropbox Passwords, in the provided notes section for each login, though it does make copying and pasting the keys a bit more annoying than in something like 1Password or Bitwarden which simply give you the option to add multiple credential fields.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biggest issue with Dropbox Passwords, though, is unfortunately shared with RememBear: there is no web-only option. Installing the browser extension for Firefox, for example, will not work on my Manjaro Linux laptops because the desktop client is still expected and there is no Linux application. This was really surprising to me since one of the reasons I initially started using &lt;a href=&#34;https://unusually.pink/chromebooks-vpns-and-you/&#34;&gt;TunnelBear as my VPN service was due to the fact that they offered a standalone browser extension that I could use back when I had Chromebooks&lt;/a&gt; which couldn&amp;rsquo;t install any type of full-fledged VPN client. Given that RememBear has been around for at least a few years and is by no means a new product, I did a little bit of digging to see if there were any plans to support Linux or Chrome OS (while I no longer use Chromebooks because Google is pretty gross, Chrome OS support would indicate a standalone browser extension.) The latest I could find was a comment from May of 2019 on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/remembear/ehpbfbahieociaeckccnklpdcmfaeegd&#34;&gt;Chrome extension&lt;/a&gt; which simply confirmed Linux and Chrome OS weren&amp;rsquo;t supported.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With its slick, cute, and bear-laden UI, RememBear is probably one of the nicest-looking and most user-friendly password managers around. For the overwhelming majority of people, it also likely ticks all of the boxes they would care about as far as features are concerned. Any Linux users out there, though, will be disappointed with the complete inability to use it with their operating system of choice. Here&amp;rsquo;s to hoping for web support or a standalone browser extension at some point in the future, but for the time being Linux aficionados are better off sticking with something like 1Password or Bitwarden.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chromebooks, VPNs, and You</title>
      <link>https://hugo.unusually.pink/chromebooks-vpns-and-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hugo.unusually.pink/chromebooks-vpns-and-you/</guid>
      <description>Do you trust your Internet service provider? If you answer that question with a resounding “No!”, then you’re among friends here. While Internet connectivity is an essential need for many of us, there are a plethora of reasons to be wary of the company providing that connectivity to you. Especially in the United States, the recent repeal of net neutrality rules and erosion of privacy mean you may want to obscure exactly what you’re doing from your Internet provider, even if that activity is completely legal and innocuous.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Do you trust your Internet service provider? If you answer that question with a resounding “No!”, then you’re among friends here. While Internet connectivity is an essential need for many of us, there are a plethora of reasons to be wary of the company providing that connectivity to you. Especially in the United States, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Net_neutrality_in_the_United_States#Rollback_of_Obama-era_rules&#34;&gt;recent repeal of net neutrality rules&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2017/04/heres-how-protect-your-privacy-your-internet-service-provider&#34;&gt;erosion of privacy&lt;/a&gt; mean you may want to obscure exactly what you’re doing from your Internet provider, even if that activity is completely legal and innocuous. Just because I’m not doing anything illegal online doesn’t mean I want to allow my ISP to gather data on what I’m doing in order to sell it to advertisers; in my opinion they make plenty of money off of the monthly fee I pay them for Internet access.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is where a VPN (virtual private network) can come in handy, as we discussed in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unusually.pink/podcast/episode-8-playlists-and-privacy&#34;&gt;Episode 8&lt;/a&gt;. VPNs are historically most common in the corporate world. They allow employees to create a secure tunnel between wherever they are and their internal company network in order to access resources that aren’t available to the outside world. In the consumer space, though, they’ve been gaining popularity as privacy-conscious consumers look for way to protect themselves from things like public WiFi and, increasingly, ISP data collection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: This post is&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;going to cover the potential risks for a VPN or how to choose one. We recommend you check out guidance from sources like the&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://ssd.eff.org/en/module/choosing-vpn-thats-right-you&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;EFF&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;for that. Brandi and John personally recommend either&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.privateinternetaccess.com&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Private Internet Access&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;or&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tunnelbear.com&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;TunnelBear&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Check out&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unusually.pink/podcast/episode-8-playlists-and-privacy&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Episode 8&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;for more details!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we’ve discussed in a few podcast episodes, I happen to be a fan of Chromebooks as my personal laptop. While I have a beefy desktop to use as a gaming computer or when I need to do some heavy lifting, I like having a Chromebook as a cheap, fast, and easy computer for things like browsing Reddit, watching YouTube videos, and typing up blog posts. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unusually.pink/blog/unusually-pink-impressions-acer-chromebook-315&#34;&gt;addition of a Linux VM&lt;/a&gt; means I can even do some programming. VPNs get a little wonky on a Chromebook, though. Most VPNs offer applications for Windows, macOS, Android, and iOS. Many services will also support configurations with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://openvpn.net&#34;&gt;OpenVPN Connect&lt;/a&gt; client in case you want to use something open source and/or are running some flavor of Linux. For example, Brandi subscribes to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.privateinternetaccess.com&#34;&gt;Private Internet Access&lt;/a&gt;. On her MacBook, she simply runs the PIA application, selects the endpoint she’d like to direct her traffic to, and is done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The waters get murkier in Chromebook land since you don’t install traditional applications on them. You also have to consider the scope of where you’re working on a Chromebook and what it is you’re looking to protect. Are you just concerned about securing the data flowing through the Chrome browser? Do you need to cover system level networking? Are you doing anything online via your Linux VM that you want to secure? These all play a role, and hopefully this post will enlighten you as to the reach of the options at your disposal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first step to testing the scope of VPN clients on Chromebooks is to be able to figure out what your external IP is since that can tell you where the outside world sees your connection coming from, be it your home network or a VPN provider’s. I personally like &lt;a href=&#34;http://icanhazip.com/&#34;&gt;I Can Haz IP&lt;/a&gt; for that. Simply going to the site will give you a web page with your public IP address. Here we can see the result I get from my Chromebook with no VPN solutions at play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hugo.unusually.pink/images/ChromebooksVPNsandYou_browser_none.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The really cool part about this service is that if you bounce an HTTP request off of it from &lt;a href=&#34;https://curl.haxx.se&#34;&gt;curl&lt;/a&gt;, it’ll reply with your public IP address. This easily allows testing of VPN providers from a command line. If you don’t have curl in your Linux VM, you can easily install it via:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34; data-lang=&#34;shell&#34;&gt;sudo apt install curl
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here we can see what happens when I curl against I Can Haz IP from my Linux VM on my Chromebook. Note that it matches the public IP I get from my browser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hugo.unusually.pink/images/ChromebooksVPNsandYou_terminal_none.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have an older Chromebook that doesn’t feature Google Play support, there are several VPN providers (including both &lt;a href=&#34;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/private-internet-access/jplnlifepflhkbkgonidnobkakhmpnmh&#34;&gt;PIA&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/tunnelbear-vpn/omdakjcmkglenbhjadbccaookpfjihpa&#34;&gt;TunnelBear&lt;/a&gt;) that offer Chrome extensions. These can be great for quickly proxying your traffic in a pinch. After flipping the switch on the TunnelBear extension, for example, I can see that the endpoint I’m seen as coming from via my browser has changed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hugo.unusually.pink/images/ChromebooksVPNsandYou_browser_extension.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s important to keep in mind, though, that the VPN is operating at the &lt;em&gt;application&lt;/em&gt; level rather than at the system level. Only traffic from my browser is going through the VPN. As a result, running curl again has no change; my Linux VM’s traffic is still going straight out through my ISP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hugo.unusually.pink/images/ChromebooksVPNsandYou_terminal_extension.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is what we refer to as a bummer. If you happen to have a Chromebook with Google Play support, though, there’s a better solution available. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.aboutchromebooks.com/news/chrome-os-75-android-vpn-support-linux-project-crostini/&#34;&gt;Updates to Chrome OS 75 in the spring of this year&lt;/a&gt; resulted in better integration between Android VPNs and Chrome OS as a whole. Installing an Android VPN client from the Play Store and connecting it will result in the WiFi icon in Chrome OS changing to display a tiny key icon, just like you’d see in the notification area of Android. After making this connection, I can verify that my browser shows my connection as coming from my VPN provider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hugo.unusually.pink/images/ChromebooksVPNsandYou_browser_android.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even better, though, checking from my Linux VM now shows the same thing; the VM’s traffic is now also going through my VPN provider instead of to the prying eyes of my ISP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hugo.unusually.pink/images/ChromebooksVPNsandYou_terminal_android.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suffice to say, this is &lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt; better. While the Chrome extensions are passable for older Chromebooks without Google Play access, the corresponding Android applications will offer far superior coverage if they’re an option on your particular device. Not that you shouldn’t have already been doing this anyway, but this should be an incentive to avoid purchasing the &lt;em&gt;insanely&lt;/em&gt; cheap Chromebooks that so frequently go on sale; I’d recommend making sure you get a device that at least has Google Play and Linux support. Keep encrypting that traffic, and stay pink!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: In my testing, the Linux VM in Chrome OS would often struggle to reconnect properly after an Android VPN application was connected and/or disconnected. For the best results, I’d recommend launching the VM&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;after&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;connecting your VPN. If you forget and connect your VPN after the fact, shut down your VM and restart it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
