<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>squarespace on Unusually Pink</title>
    <link>https://unusually.pink/tags/squarespace/</link>
    <description>Recent content in squarespace on Unusually Pink</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>2021 - John Fabry</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://unusually.pink/tags/squarespace/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Salvaging Images From Squarespace</title>
      <link>https://unusually.pink/salvaging-images-from-squarespace/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unusually.pink/salvaging-images-from-squarespace/</guid>
      <description>I wrote previously about moving this blog from Squarespace to WordPress. One of my cited concerns with Squarespace was being locked into that particular platform without a lot of options for moving somewhere else. So how did I move my content to WordPress? I was able to export the written content for the posts themselves from within Squarespace, fortunately. Inside of Settings &amp;gt; Advanced is an Import / Export option. The only export offering is WordPress, so I guess it was lucky that&amp;rsquo;s where I was moving.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;I wrote previously about &lt;a href=&#34;https://unusually.pink/unusually-pink-migration/&#34;&gt;moving this blog from Squarespace to WordPress&lt;/a&gt;. One of my cited concerns with Squarespace was being locked into that particular platform without a lot of options for moving somewhere else. So how did I move my content to WordPress? I was able to export the &lt;em&gt;written&lt;/em&gt; content for the posts themselves from within Squarespace, fortunately. Inside of Settings &amp;gt; Advanced is an &lt;strong&gt;Import / Export&lt;/strong&gt; option. The &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; export offering is WordPress, so I guess it was lucky that&amp;rsquo;s where I was moving. This gives an XML file with the written content and metadata for each post. Unfortunately, there is no option to export the &lt;em&gt;images&lt;/em&gt; that I&amp;rsquo;ve uploaded over the past year of creating content over at Squarespace; within the XML file the images show up as &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; tags with a link to the Squarespace CDN for the actual image. For example, this is what I see where the image is for the last post I authored over on Squarespace:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;div style=&amp;quot;padding-bottom:45.903255462646484%;&amp;quot; class=&amp;quot; image-block-wrapper has-aspect-ratio &amp;quot; data-animation-role=&amp;quot;image&amp;quot; &amp;gt; &amp;lt;noscript&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5cabd40b755be258403ccb99/1595366630913-VD12AA9IHURXLT6CWQ66/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kKEtlFlv-8yggmb8KJA0a9wUqsxRUqqbr1mOJYKfIPR7LoDQ9mXPOjoJoqy81S2I8N_N4V1vUb5AoIIIbLZhVYxCRW4BPu10St3TBAUQYVKcpEap199WJ5tA07nqy9HB7RsfdGE2RUqSBzw535kCng92V_tkyiZ3FgjXcK6wugnz/html.png&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;html.png&amp;quot; /&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/noscript&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img class=&amp;quot;thumb-image&amp;quot; data-src=&amp;quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5cabd40b755be258403ccb99/1595366630913-VD12AA9IHURXLT6CWQ66/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kKEtlFlv-8yggmb8KJA0a9wUqsxRUqqbr1mOJYKfIPR7LoDQ9mXPOjoJoqy81S2I8N_N4V1vUb5AoIIIbLZhVYxCRW4BPu10St3TBAUQYVKcpEap199WJ5tA07nqy9HB7RsfdGE2RUqSBzw535kCng92V_tkyiZ3FgjXcK6wugnz/html.png&amp;quot; data-image=&amp;quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5cabd40b755be258403ccb99/1595366630913-VD12AA9IHURXLT6CWQ66/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kKEtlFlv-8yggmb8KJA0a9wUqsxRUqqbr1mOJYKfIPR7LoDQ9mXPOjoJoqy81S2I8N_N4V1vUb5AoIIIbLZhVYxCRW4BPu10St3TBAUQYVKcpEap199WJ5tA07nqy9HB7RsfdGE2RUqSBzw535kCng92V_tkyiZ3FgjXcK6wugnz/html.png&amp;quot; data-image-dimensions=&amp;quot;1013x465&amp;quot; data-image-focal-point=&amp;quot;0.5,0.5&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;html.png&amp;quot; data-load=&amp;quot;false&amp;quot; data-image-id=&amp;quot;5f175ce6cb20a366ea6f4d62&amp;quot; data-type=&amp;quot;image&amp;quot; /&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you think that looks disgusting, that&amp;rsquo;s because it is. When I imported the XML file into WordPress, I saw an option to download any attachments on each post. I checked that box, but since the images are linked to the Squarespace CDN they&amp;rsquo;re considered to be HTML content rather than attachments. As a result, WordPress simply embeds the &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; in each post as a custom HTML block that doesn&amp;rsquo;t actually render the image.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://unusually.pink/images/cash_money.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Set on &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; going through 50 posts to manually save the images out of them, I started looking at the XML to see if I could do anything useful with the image URLs. One thing that immediately concerned me was that, when I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure what I was going to do with the &lt;code&gt;unusually.pink&lt;/code&gt; domain but knew that I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to keep it at Squarespace, I marked the Squarespace site as Private, meaning the only way to view the content was to log in. I &lt;em&gt;assumed&lt;/em&gt; this meant the image content on the Squarespace CDN would be inaccessible until I made the site public again. After copying an image URL from my XML file, though, I saw that it was still publicly available. Flagging a Squarespace site as private means you can&amp;rsquo;t load the site directly, but content on Squarespace&amp;rsquo;s CDN is still accessible. That in itself seems like a problem to me and a very good reason to leave the platform, but in this one case it was working to my benefit. I realized that I could parse all of the images files out of the XML file with a script and download them programmatically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see from the XML snippet above, images on the Squarespace CDN have URLs like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5cabd40b755be258403ccb99/1595366630913-VD12AA9IHURXLT6CWQ66/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kKEtlFlv-8yggmb8KJA0a9wUqsxRUqqbr1mOJYKfIPR7LoDQ9mXPOjoJoqy81S2I8N\_N4V1vUb5AoIIIbLZhVYxCRW4BPu10St3TBAUQYVKcpEap199WJ5tA07nqy9HB7RsfdGE2RUqSBzw535kCng92V\_tkyiZ3FgjXcK6wugnz/html.png
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a whole lot of CDN nonsense, followed by a forward slash and the original file name at the very end. While this would be handy for getting the original file name, I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to end up with dozens of images in a folder where I had no idea what post they belonged to, and I definitely didn&amp;rsquo;t want to manually correlate the file name with the CDN link in each of the HTML blocks in WordPress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The XML, though, also includes the title of each post, and I realized that if I was scanning each line of the XML for image tags, I could also check for the title tag and keep a variable constantly updated with that. With this idea, I would just &lt;em&gt;start&lt;/em&gt; each file name with the post title so that they would be grouped together. Once the dots were connected, it was simple to come up with the following short PowerShell script:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It downloads all of the images referenced in the XML file in the format of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;postTitle_fileName.extension
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;I added some extra checks to remove unsavory characters from the file names; while it&amp;rsquo;s a valid character in most modern filesystems, for example, have you ever tried to actually programmatically do things from a Bash shell with a file that has a &lt;code&gt;[&lt;/code&gt; in the name? It&amp;rsquo;s not pretty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While this saved me from having to manually download each image from Squarespace, I still had to manually go through each post in WordPress, remove the custom HTML block where each image should have been, and then upload the appropriate image. With the way I downloaded the images, though, I just started at the top of the directory and worked my way through the images alphabetically since each post was grouped together. It sucked, but it could have been a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; worse. If nothing else it made me glad that I moved forward with migrating the site now rather than waiting a few more months for the Squarespace subscription to lapse; I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to deal with this for any more posts than was strictly necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unusually Pink Migration</title>
      <link>https://unusually.pink/unusually-pink-migration/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unusually.pink/unusually-pink-migration/</guid>
      <description>So Long, Squarespace! If anyone stumbles across this site who was previously an Unusually Pink reader, then you might notice that the site looks a bit different after a few months of hiatus. In the short, just under 2 year lifespan of the site it has now moved to its 3rd host. Originally it was hosted on a Vultr VPS that I had been hosting a few other things on, back when I originally bought the domain because I loved the name but had no idea what to do with it.</description>
      <content>&lt;h2 id=&#34;so-long-squarespace&#34;&gt;So Long, Squarespace!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If anyone stumbles across this site who was previously an Unusually Pink reader, then you might notice that the site looks a bit different after a few months of hiatus. In the short, just under 2 year lifespan of the site it has now moved to its 3rd host. Originally it was hosted on a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vultr.com/&#34;&gt;Vultr VPS&lt;/a&gt; that I had been hosting a few other things on, back when I &lt;a href=&#34;https://unusually.pink/its-all-about-being-unusually-pink/&#34;&gt;originally bought the domain because I loved the name but had no idea what to do with it&lt;/a&gt;. Then Brandi, my former co-host, and I decided to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dropbox.com/sh/v9yvrhsoahu2vlw/AAB_JaXv3isvQjVyIMdlPHm6a?dl=0&#34;&gt;start a podcast&lt;/a&gt;; it quickly became apparent that my web development skills weren&amp;rsquo;t exactly up to par with what we wanted to accomplish. As a result, we moved the site over to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.squarespace.com/&#34;&gt;Squarespace&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our podcast lived just long enough for the Squarespace hosting to renew before Brandi and I both decided that things had run their course. It was unfortunate that I had just forked over another year&amp;rsquo;s worth of money to Squarespace for hosting before reaching that decision. With that being said, you might be wondering why on Earth I&amp;rsquo;d be re-hosting the site somewhere else if I still have time left on the Squarespace subscription; more on that will come a little later on. With this being my first time using Squarespace, though, I thought I would first share some thoughts after running a site there for a year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-good&#34;&gt;The Good&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I initially decided to move the site from my VPS to Squarespace, it was mainly because I knew I needed hosting &lt;em&gt;somewhere&lt;/em&gt;, and it seemed like a good chance to mess around with something new. I had run numerous blogs on a free &lt;a href=&#34;https://wordpress.com&#34;&gt;WordPress.com&lt;/a&gt; account along with compiling many of my own blogs with &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; as I tend to &lt;a href=&#34;https://unusually.pink/full-content-rss-feeds-with-hugo/&#34;&gt;discuss frequently&lt;/a&gt;. With us wanting to have a presence online that made us look like we knew what we were doing, though, I figured this was a worthwhile opportunity to justify spending the money on hosting with Squarespace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Squarespace offers, hands down, the &lt;em&gt;nicest&lt;/em&gt; management interface I&amp;rsquo;ve ever seen. Everything is very slick and inviting, without being overly cluttered and complicated. It&amp;rsquo;s simple to add new pages to your site or even branches to your site. For example, I originally migrated the blog I had been running under the Unusually Pink domain to Squarespace, but I quickly realized that the best way to handle the show notes for each podcast episode would &lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; be basically a blog. It was trivial to literally add another blog to the site; I just had to tell Squarespace what directory I wanted to host that under and which of the two would be the &amp;ldquo;main&amp;rdquo; page of the site. The two were then independent of one another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Squarespace doesn&amp;rsquo;t offer nearly as many themes as you&amp;rsquo;ll find with something like WordPress, but all of the Squarespace themes are &lt;em&gt;highly&lt;/em&gt; customizable without having to wander into the realm of HTML and CSS. For example, for any theme I can change literally every color by simply using the menus presented to me. On the flip side, the WordPress theme you see right now only offered a handful of elements for color modification. Even worse, this theme offered &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; options than many of the others I looked at, where changing anything beyond the text color would&amp;rsquo;ve involved modifying the CSS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, Squarespace gives you an absurd amount of information about the traffic to your site, all without the need for any type of plugins. You can simply link up Google credentials to integrate with Google Analytics, for example, and see what people are searching for to reach your site, what position you&amp;rsquo;re in for the search results, the click percentage, how many impressions you get, etc. It also offers a very slick, interactive map if you want to drill down to the specifics of where your hits stem from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-bad&#34;&gt;The Bad&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main purpose for the previous site on Squarespace was blogging. Case in point, there were &lt;em&gt;two&lt;/em&gt; blogs hosted on it; one for my own random posts and one for the show notes that went along with each podcast episode. Easily the single biggest nail in the Squarespace coffin is that the service is in no way &lt;em&gt;designed&lt;/em&gt; for blogging. That might seem contradictory considering I just said that I hosted not one but &lt;strong&gt;two&lt;/strong&gt; blogs on a single site there, but allow me to elaborate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adding a blog to Squarespace just means that when you go to edit the site, you have two different streams of posts you can choose from. You pick the blog, say you want to make a new post, and start to edit the content. This is where things immediately get murky. The editor for authoring content in Squarespace is pretty bad. It tries to break the content of each post down into blocks the way the current WordPress editor does, but it does so in an extremely clunky, unintuitive way. Simple things like handling the appearance of media you upload is often not possible, meaning that I had to resize every photo prior to uploading since I knew there would be no good options for scaling this after the fact. Likewise, trying to embed any sort of content was frequently gated behind a paywall; I couldn&amp;rsquo;t embed the player for each episode into the post with the show notes because they wanted me to pay more for that privilege. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t embed tweets but had to just link to them. That may not have been a big deal were it not for the fact that the Squarespace plan I was on was already more than &lt;strong&gt;double&lt;/strong&gt; what I&amp;rsquo;m paying for hosting now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As another blow to blogging, Squarespace doesn&amp;rsquo;t provide any real outlet for managing the posts on the site. While in the management interface, for example, going to one of the two blogs I had added would simply show me a lists of posts on the left in chronological order. If the post I needed to modify was at the very bottom of the list because it was old, then I had to just keep scrolling until I got to it, letting the clusters of posts incrementally load the further I scrolled. There weren&amp;rsquo;t any options to just search for the post I wanted. This may have been a limitation of the theme I selected, but I was equally disappointed that I couldn&amp;rsquo;t search the blog itself for specific content, either. I frequently author blog posts that I know will help &lt;strong&gt;me&lt;/strong&gt; in the future; they live on a blog as opposed to just in my personal notes because they might also be beneficial to someone else. If I can&amp;rsquo;t easily get back to that content, though, without mindlessly clicking a &amp;ldquo;Next&amp;rdquo; button, that&amp;rsquo;s a problem. This WordPress blog offers both a search box and sane pagination; neither was an option for my Squarespace deployment. I&amp;rsquo;d frequently have to search the web for what I wanted to find with the URL of my own site to reach it. That&amp;rsquo;s a problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last thing I&amp;rsquo;ll mention is portability. Admittedly, WordPress might be just as bad at this, but it&amp;rsquo;s extremely difficult to take content from Squarespace and move it somewhere else. &lt;strong&gt;This&lt;/strong&gt; was the big reason why I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to continue creating content on Squarespace even though I&amp;rsquo;ve already paid for the hosting there; I knew that I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to stick with Squarespace once the current hosting expired, but anything new I posted there would just be more work to move to somewhere else later on. Squarespace offers you the ability to export your content, but it&amp;rsquo;s to an XML file. While this will get the written content for each post and the metadata about it, it will not include any media. I managed to throw together a bit of a workaround that&amp;rsquo;ll most likely be the topic of my next post, but it was still a large amount of work to move everything from one host to another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An obvious question at this point would be:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But aren&amp;rsquo;t you just in the same option regarding portability after moving to WordPress?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The answer is&amp;hellip; maybe. As long as I don&amp;rsquo;t become disenfranchised with the platform as a whole, there are &lt;em&gt;many&lt;/em&gt; different WordPress hosting platforms out there. If I want to move from one to another, I can easily export my site or take a backup of it and move the content somewhere else. I had initially tried moving a lot of the content from Squarespace to a Hugo site I already ran, but I very quickly ran into many of the same issues I described with Squarespace regarding management and discoverability; while being lightweight is nice, sometimes having a CMS is beneficial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;wrap-up&#34;&gt;Wrap-Up&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the vibe you may get, I don&amp;rsquo;t dislike Squarespace at all. I feel like their business is really tailored to users who want a professional, mostly static website but who don&amp;rsquo;t have the skills to create that themselves. For a hobbyist like myself with a focus on blogging, the premium you pay for Squarespace gets you essentially nothing. Any WordPress instance is going to be a better blogging platform, and one that is significantly cheaper at that. Similarly, if you need to have firm divisions in your site (e.g. a blog for the sake of shitposting and a blog for podcast show notes), you can&amp;rsquo;t easily do that within WordPress. While you can create multiple pages, such as the &lt;a href=&#34;https://unusually.pink/about/&#34;&gt;About page&lt;/a&gt; here, you can&amp;rsquo;t set up an entirely separate blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At least for the moment, what I did with Squarespace for both a blog and podcast repository wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be possible with WordPress. For a standalone blog, though, the experience is &lt;em&gt;significantly&lt;/em&gt; better on WordPress. It&amp;rsquo;s important to understand what the goal of your site is and what you need out of your platform. When that goal changes, moving platforms might be the best move. Hopefully my next post on how I migrated my images between Squarespace and WordPress can help with that.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Switching To Squarespace</title>
      <link>https://unusually.pink/switching-to-squarespace/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unusually.pink/switching-to-squarespace/</guid>
      <description>If you happened to see this site around the time when the first post went up, you might notice that:
  The site looks very different now.
  A lot of what’s in that first post no longer seems to be true.
  For example, this is not the Rusty theme for Hugo. Those technically savvy would also notice that the site no longer has the same DNS record value as laifu.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;If you happened to see this site around the time when the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unusually.pink/blog/its-all-about-being-unusually-pink&#34;&gt;first post&lt;/a&gt; went up, you might notice that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The site looks very different now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of what’s in that first post no longer seems to be true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, this is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; the &lt;a href=&#34;https://themes.gohugo.io/hugo-theme-rusty/&#34;&gt;Rusty&lt;/a&gt; theme for Hugo. Those technically savvy would also notice that the site no longer has the same DNS record value as &lt;a href=&#34;https://laifu.moe&#34;&gt;laifu.moe&lt;/a&gt; where things were originally hosted. That’s because the site is no longer running on my own web server and is not created using Hugo. There were a few reasons for this. The main was just that I’m &lt;strong&gt;really&lt;/strong&gt; bad at web design. The Rusty theme in Hugo is pretty light on imagery, which I’m cool with. Once we decided to actually make &lt;em&gt;Unusually Pink&lt;/em&gt; into a thing and do a podcast, though, we had our &lt;strong&gt;amazing&lt;/strong&gt; logos made by the uber-talented &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jpfdesigns.com/&#34;&gt;JPFDesigns&lt;/a&gt;. Integrating those into the Rusty theme for Hugo was a bit more than I was up for; CSS is legitimately the final boss of my life, and my life is (apparently) an NES &lt;em&gt;Contra&lt;/em&gt; game; I couldn’t do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other reason was just that it allows for &lt;strong&gt;much&lt;/strong&gt; better reliability. The site isn’t beholden to my ability to not mess up my web server. Not that it’s particularly likely for me to do something to brick it (I’ve been using Linux and Nginx for my web servers for ages now), but it’s possible. I was also responsible for backups, which I’d prefer to take off of my own hands if possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last reason was that the site really needed to be divided from one main section (e.g. the blog I originally planned just to do &lt;strong&gt;something&lt;/strong&gt; with the domain) to two sections: a blog and a list of podcast episodes. While I was able to just dump a &lt;strong&gt;/podcast&lt;/strong&gt; directory into my &lt;strong&gt;static&lt;/strong&gt; folder for Hugo, it meant that posting podcast episodes and summaries was now an entirely manual process rather than something assisted by a CMS-esque system like Hugo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Swapping to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.squarespace.com/&#34;&gt;Squarespace&lt;/a&gt; allowed me to let someone far smarter than me figure out all of that within a theme; all I had to do was upload some images (Squarespace is awesome at scaling images for me, even when it needed to make one tiny for the favicon) and then swap around a few of the colors in the theme to get something &lt;em&gt;unusually pink&lt;/em&gt;. I was also able to simply add two blogs to the site; one is a normal blog and the other will have posts for each podcast episode. In this way, both sections of the site are managed by a CMS rather than being done manually. Doing it manually may not seem like &lt;strong&gt;too&lt;/strong&gt; big of a deal at first, but once you start to get too many posts for a single page, creating and manually updating the pagination after each new post would be enough to drive someone insane.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for choosing Squarespace, it’s the one I’ve heard the most about through various avenues on the Internet. Their pricing was reasonable, and I figured it seemed like a safe bet since I know a few other people who have experience with them. The other recommendation I got was Wix, which I admittedly had never heard of previously. Looking at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wix.com/upgrade/website&#34;&gt;pricing for Wix&lt;/a&gt; compared to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.squarespace.com/pricing&#34;&gt;pricing for Squarespace&lt;/a&gt;, though, I think it’s clear that Squarespace is a better deal. The Wix $11 USD per month package is pretty lackluster, especially when you look at 2 GB of bandwidth and 3 GB of storage. To get something more comparable to Squarespace’s $12 per month package that includes unlimited bandwidth and storage, you’d need the $14 per month plan from Wix… and that still doesn’t give you unlimited storage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Expect the site to still go through a few minor changes as we continue to tweak the layout, colors, and everything else. Feel free to drop any feedback to our &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/UnusuallyPink&#34;&gt;Twitter profile&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
