<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>apple on Unusually Pink</title>
    <link>https://unusually.pink/tags/apple/</link>
    <description>Recent content in apple on Unusually Pink</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>2021 - John Fabry</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://unusually.pink/tags/apple/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Apple Music: Back in the Saddle</title>
      <link>https://unusually.pink/apple-music-back-in-the-saddle/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unusually.pink/apple-music-back-in-the-saddle/</guid>
      <description>For anyone who listens to the Same Shade of Difference podcast, you may have heard a brief discussion between Mark and I about how I had switched from Apple Music to Amazon Music. I&amp;rsquo;ve previously been a fan of Spotify, though I became increasingly irritated with the focus they started giving podcasts rather than music. I know it&amp;rsquo;s weird coming from someone who has spent the past couple of years creating podcasts, but I don&amp;rsquo;t listen to them.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;For anyone who listens to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sameshadeofdifference.com&#34;&gt;Same Shade of Difference&lt;/a&gt; podcast, you may have heard a brief discussion between Mark and I about how I had switched from Apple Music to Amazon Music. I&amp;rsquo;ve previously been a fan of &lt;a href=&#34;https://unusually.pink/2018-in-music-spotify-wrapped/&#34;&gt;Spotify&lt;/a&gt;, though I became increasingly irritated with the focus they started giving podcasts rather than music. I know it&amp;rsquo;s weird coming from someone who has spent the past couple of years creating podcasts, but I don&amp;rsquo;t listen to them. Additionally, I don&amp;rsquo;t really want them being advertised to me when I&amp;rsquo;m trying to look for music. When I swapped to an iPhone about a year ago, I decided to try out Apple Music since I could get a few months of it for free. After my free 3 months, I decided to stick with it. Recently, though, I swapped away from it and decided to give Amazon Music a shake. After about a month and a half, though, I quickly abandoned ship back to Apple Music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, let&amp;rsquo;s start with why I left Apple Music in the first place. After all, I use a MacBook Pro, an iPhone, and an iPad. Shouldn&amp;rsquo;t Apple Music be my best choice? The main issue is that the Apple Music application on macOS is, to be blunt, a dumpster fire. The application has a plethora of issues when it comes to responsiveness and playback. &amp;ldquo;Did I accidentally &lt;em&gt;miss&lt;/em&gt; clicking on that button or is the application just being super slow?&amp;rdquo; is a question I find myself asking on the regular. The biggest issue, though, is when it just randomly decides to either 1.) not load or 2.) skip every song as though playback is unavailable. It&amp;rsquo;s not at all uncommon, for example, for me to click the &lt;strong&gt;Browse&lt;/strong&gt; option from the menu only to be presented with a completely blank UI. No buttons, no albums, no genres. All I can do is quit the application, re-launch it, and hope for the best. In other instances, Apple Music will rapid-fire skip through tracks as though they&amp;rsquo;re unavailable. It&amp;rsquo;ll select a track from whatever album or playlist I&amp;rsquo;m trying to listen to, pause for a second or two, immediately skip to the next track, and just repeat this endlessly. Searching online shows plenty of people experiencing the same issues. Usually some secret handshake combination of signing out and back in, de-authorizing and re-authorizing the device, and switching networks (yes, really) will sometimes take care of the problem. It&amp;rsquo;s frustrating to the extreme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that being said, what would make someone switch back? First, let&amp;rsquo;s talk about what&amp;rsquo;s good about Amazon Music. The application on both macOS and iOS/iPadOS is rock-solid. I didn&amp;rsquo;t experience any errors, playback problems, bugs, etc. Beyond that, though, it was just an &lt;em&gt;incredibly&lt;/em&gt; lackluster experience; while there wasn&amp;rsquo;t anything I&amp;rsquo;d qualify as &amp;ldquo;bad&amp;rdquo;, there also wasn&amp;rsquo;t anything I&amp;rsquo;d qualify as &amp;ldquo;good&amp;rdquo;. To start off, the application regularly would pester me about doing a free trial for their Premium offering that allows you to stream music at a higher bit-rate. It would offer 3 months of that, after which time it would automatically swap me from paying the standard $10 USD a month that everyone charges for their individual plan to $15 a month. Hard pass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While that was irritating, the bigger issue was the lack of personalized content. Apple Music and Spotify both offer a handful of customized playlists each week showcasing music that you like, music to fit different moods, etc. Amazon Music gives you &lt;strong&gt;one&lt;/strong&gt;; you get a discovery playlist, and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t even necessarily focus on new releases. That was a major letdown for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had initially thought that I would just step up the manual work to discover music on my own, but this is where Amazon Music really fell apart. As anyone who knows me is likely already aware, I listen mostly to indie music. Amazon Music doesn&amp;rsquo;t even delineate indie into its own genre; to see indie music, I had to browse through the &amp;ldquo;Alternative&amp;rdquo; section. This means that when I&amp;rsquo;m trying to check out new releases for discovery, I&amp;rsquo;m shifting through garbage like Coldplay while trying to reach gold like &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/32kiLOylCFM&#34;&gt;Falcon Jane&lt;/a&gt;. Music discovery in Amazon Music quickly became less enjoyable and more frustrating. To make matters worse, shortly before I switched away from it, the macOS application received a complete overhaul that did away with the normal ability to browse through different genres and playlists. Everything suddenly revolved around searching, and while it worked to get me to the same content as before, it was ultimately a very clunky and unintuitive experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The nail in the coffin, though, was that Amazon Music doesn&amp;rsquo;t bother to get the rights to a not insignificant amount of international music. For example, when &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GywDFkY3z-c&#34;&gt;Lee Suhyun&amp;rsquo;s track ALIEN&lt;/a&gt; released, I was surprised to see that it wasn&amp;rsquo;t available on Amazon Music. The same thing happened with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oBTxxpYre3g&#34;&gt;Reol&amp;rsquo;s track Q?&lt;/a&gt;. At this point, I realized that I just really needed to switch to a different service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So now the last big question: why did I switch &lt;em&gt;back&lt;/em&gt; to Apple Music instead of going back to something like Spotify? There were several reasons. One of the big ones is that I&amp;rsquo;ve been interested in subscribing to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.apple.com/apple-one/&#34;&gt;Apple One&lt;/a&gt;. I was wanting to bump my iCloud storage space up a little bit, and if I was using Apple Music then it seemed like the easy decision that would also get me access to Apple TV+ and Apple Arcade. Additionally, I&amp;rsquo;ve been interested in the Apple HomePod for a while but never wanted to spend the $300 USD on one; when they started dropping to $200 USD over the past few months, I figured that had to be due to something new and exciting being on the horizon. Sure enough, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.apple.com/homepod-mini/&#34;&gt;HomePod Mini&lt;/a&gt; recently released, and I decided to pull the trigger on one. While Apple Music &lt;em&gt;does&lt;/em&gt; work with Amazon Echo devices, of which I have several, I figure the HomePod Mini will offer a much more elegant experience. The final reason is pure laziness; I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to bother with trying to update all of my playlists yet again. When I moved from Spotify to Apple Music, I spent more time than I care to admit moving all of my playlists over by hand. When I decided to try out Amazon Music, I went through the same process &lt;em&gt;again&lt;/em&gt;. I didn&amp;rsquo;t relish the thought of moving nearly a year&amp;rsquo;s worth of playlist updates from Amazon Music to Spotify; if I stuck with Apple Music I&amp;rsquo;d only have to worry about catching up my playlists on the last month of content&amp;hellip; a month that was a bit of a discovery drought due to the issues already mentioned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After switching back, I&amp;rsquo;ve already discovered significantly more music than I had while I was using Amazon. I&amp;rsquo;ve also run into a couple of issues with the macOS application for Apple Music, but I&amp;rsquo;m trying to keep my hopes up that things will be better with it on the new Macs running on the M1 chip. In the meantime, I&amp;rsquo;ve updated the links on both my &lt;a href=&#34;https://unusually.pink/about/&#34;&gt;About page&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://jfabhd.com&#34;&gt;jfabhd.com&lt;/a&gt; to point to my &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.apple.com/profile/jfabhd&#34;&gt;Apple Music profile&lt;/a&gt;; feel free to scope out my playlists!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Safari 14</title>
      <link>https://unusually.pink/safari-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unusually.pink/safari-14/</guid>
      <description>Last week the 10.15.7 update to macOS Catalina came with a nice surprise: Safari 14. I was caught off guard by this since I had assumed we wouldn&amp;rsquo;t see Safari 14 until Big Sur released later this year. It was also a nice surprise for me since Safari has become my browser of choice, not just on my iPhone and iPad, but also on my MacBook Pro. The big reason for this is that I do my best to avoid any Chromium-based browser.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Last week the 10.15.7 update to macOS Catalina came with a nice surprise: Safari 14. I was caught off guard by this since I had assumed we wouldn&amp;rsquo;t see Safari 14 until &lt;a href=&#34;https://unusually.pink/thoughts-on-apples-wwdc-2020/&#34;&gt;Big Sur released later this year&lt;/a&gt;. It was also a nice surprise for me since Safari has become my browser of choice, not just on my iPhone and iPad, but also on my MacBook Pro. The big reason for this is that I do my best to avoid any &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chromium_(web_browser)&#34;&gt;Chromium&lt;/a&gt;-based browser. Over the last few years we&amp;rsquo;ve seen diversity in browsers erode more and more as new browsers are built based on Chromium (e.g. Brave) while others abandon their own engines in favor of using Chromium (e.g. Opera and Edge.) I personally see this homogeneous browsing platform as being pretty bad for the Internet as a whole, as it opens up the possibility for web developers to focus all of their development on Chrome and ignore everything else. This leads to sites that &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; work on Chrome and that ignore web standards, just like we saw back in the day when much of the web was developed with only Internet Explorer 6 in mind. The difference now is the way the web has evolved into an entire platform. In 2004 the main issue was that sites developed just for IE 6 wouldn&amp;rsquo;t quite render properly on other browsers. In 2020, there are entire web apps that straight up won&amp;rsquo;t work on non-Chromium browsers. That&amp;rsquo;s something I can&amp;rsquo;t support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two &lt;em&gt;major&lt;/em&gt; browsers moving forward with different engines are Firefox (with Gecko) and Safari (with WebKit.) I was previously using Firefox on my laptops, but I became extremely concerned recently when &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mozilla.org/blog/2020/08/11/changing-world-changing-mozilla/&#34;&gt;Mozilla had massive layoffs and switched their mission to focus on revenue&lt;/a&gt;. I certainly understand that Mozilla needs to make money in order to continue making Firefox, but when a group lays off their entire incident response team, I don&amp;rsquo;t exactly feel warm and fuzzy inside about using the product. I still use it on my Linux installations, but on macOS I switched to Safari.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pleasant part about switching to Safari is that, for the most part, it&amp;rsquo;s been a very slick browser that I&amp;rsquo;ve enjoyed. While Safari 14 doesn&amp;rsquo;t do anything too Earth-shattering or even different from any other browsers, it does bring Apple&amp;rsquo;s offering up to parity with some of the major players. For example, Safari will now &lt;em&gt;finally&lt;/em&gt; display favicons for websites on tabs. How they&amp;rsquo;ve made it this far without supporting them I&amp;rsquo;ll never understand, but it immediately makes a huge difference in quickly finding the tab I want&amp;hellip; and I say this as a person who typically doesn&amp;rsquo;t have more than 10 tabs open at any given time. Tab addicts (you know who you are) will especially appreciate this when Safari starts stacking tabs on top of one another. As another update to tabs, Safari can now preview the content of a page when the mouse is hovered over a tab. This can also be useful for quickly finding the appropriate tab without actually having to switch to anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The big change, though, is how Safari communicates with the user about how it has helped protect against invasive tracking. This feature is &lt;em&gt;extremely&lt;/em&gt; similar to the Protections Dashboard in Firefox. There&amp;rsquo;s an icon to the left of the address bar that can be clicked at any given time to see a breakdown of trackers on the current page. Clicking will also allow me to see the specifics of what trackers are being blocked:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://unusually.pink/images/safari_icon.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a bigger picture, I can also get an overall view of what&amp;rsquo;s been blocked in the past 30 days. I can see which sites were attempting to be the most invasive, and similar to the per-site rendering, each can be expanded to show which trackers they had embedded:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://unusually.pink/images/safari_websites.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, I can click on the &lt;strong&gt;Trackers&lt;/strong&gt; heading in order to see a list of which trackers appear the most frequently across the sites I&amp;rsquo;m visiting. I can expand those listings to see which specific sites are hosting that tracker:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://unusually.pink/images/safari_trackers.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t think it should come as a surprise to anyone that Google, Bing, and Facebook appear the most frequently after just a short period of testing. It&amp;rsquo;s also interesting to see trackers from both Facebook and Snapchat when I don&amp;rsquo;t use either of those &amp;ldquo;services&amp;rdquo;. It really shows you how pervasive they are across the Internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I can already hear the Apple-haters I know railing on the fact that Firefox already has this feature, in my opinion it&amp;rsquo;s nice to see Apple bringing their browser up to feature parity and offering a more transparent and secure browsing experience to people in a package that &lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; does not leverage Chromium but which &lt;em&gt;does&lt;/em&gt; have a support team behind it that&amp;rsquo;s more than a skeleton crew. Similarly, you &lt;em&gt;still&lt;/em&gt; don&amp;rsquo;t see anything like this today in Chrome or Edge, likely because the companies behind them both appear relatively high up in the tracker list.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Note-Taking With Notable</title>
      <link>https://unusually.pink/note-taking-with-notable/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unusually.pink/note-taking-with-notable/</guid>
      <description>The Others I’ve struggled for years with finding a good, reliable, and simple note-taking application that fit my needs and didn’t lock me in to a particular platform. When I started my career, I was using Evernote for handling my notes at work. At the time, the free version of Evernote was pretty solid which was good because I didn’t have the money to be spending on notes. After a few years, however, Evernote apparently decided that not enough people were paying for the premium version of the product; as a result they crippled the free version.</description>
      <content>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-others&#34;&gt;The Others&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve struggled for years with finding a good, reliable, and simple note-taking application that fit my needs and &lt;em&gt;didn’t&lt;/em&gt; lock me in to a particular platform. When I started my career, I was using &lt;a href=&#34;https://evernote.com/&#34;&gt;Evernote&lt;/a&gt; for handling my notes at work. At the time, the free version of Evernote was pretty solid which was good because I didn’t have the money to be spending on notes. After a few years, however, Evernote apparently decided that not enough people were paying for the premium version of the product; as a result they crippled the free version. The free version had previously been limited to the amount of data you could sync in a month, and that alone seemed reasonable. They added on to this by limiting the number of &lt;em&gt;devices&lt;/em&gt; which could connect to an account. Since having my work laptop, personal laptop, and phone all connect was no longer an option, I decided to look for something else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the time, nothing else really stuck out to me. I was working in a &lt;strong&gt;very&lt;/strong&gt; Microsoft-centric environment and was managing Office 365 at the time a fairly new service. I opted to use &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.onenote.com/signin?wdorigin=ondc&#34;&gt;OneNote&lt;/a&gt; since it would integrate in to Office 365. I almost immediately hated pretty much everything about OneNote, from the appearance, to how shitty the web app was at the time, to how poorly it would index and search my notes. However, I stuck with it for &lt;em&gt;years&lt;/em&gt; because 1.) it was able to import my years of existing notes from Evernote and 2.) intertia made it easy to stay with a product (even if I strongly disliked it) because it meant I didn’t need to invest my time in anything else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I finally switched to a new job about a year ago, though, I decided it was time for a fresh start with my notes. I was working in a new role that meant my years of previous notes were no longer going to be nearly as important to me as they were. In the rare instance I needed one, I could easily pop open the OneNote (finally improved) web app and find it; I didn’t need to worry about importing those notes into another system for daily use. Since the job change also marked a change in switching from Windows to macOS for work, I originally started off using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.icloud.com/notes&#34;&gt;Apple Notes&lt;/a&gt;. I rather like Apple Notes in that it’s simple, fast, lightweight, and it syncs nicely between my MacBook, iPhone, and iPad. However, I quickly found that being locked in to Apple’s ecosystem for my notes wasn’t exactly what I was wanting. For example, while there’s a web app for Apple Notes, it’s clunky and slow. This means accessing my notes from my personal laptop running Linux is a painful experience. Likewise, what if I stopped using Apple products in the future? It makes no sense to be locked in to a particular hardware vendor when it comes to something as ubiquitous as note-taking software. While I still use Apple Notes occasionally for quick, personal notes that I’m only accessing from my phone, I didn’t want to continue using it as my primary note-taking application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I was already an avid Dropbox user and had been for many years, I decided to give &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dropbox.com/paper&#34;&gt;Dropbox Paper&lt;/a&gt; a try. I was initially drawn to it since it seemed like it was basically &lt;a href=&#34;https://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/&#34;&gt;Markdown&lt;/a&gt;, the markup language I perfer to write things in. In fact, all of the posts for this blog are created in Markdown and compiled through &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;. In reality, though, the syntax wasn’t exactly Markdown but a weird mix where some pieces of Markdown had been cherry-picked (e.g. bold, italics) while others were ignored (e.g. hyperlinks.) Being that the files were created with a &lt;code&gt;.paper&lt;/code&gt; extension also meant they weren’t Markdown files I could directly edit with something else in a clean manner; I was locked in to Dropbox. What if I wanted to change my cloud storage to something different, which could very well happen if &lt;a href=&#34;https://protonmail.com/blog/protondrive-security/&#34;&gt;ProtonDrive&lt;/a&gt; lives up to my expectations when it releases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is when I started to realize that what I &lt;strong&gt;really&lt;/strong&gt; wanted was something that would allow me to easily work with Markdown but that would leave vanilla Markdown files on my system. These files could be synced through whatever means I wanted to use, be in Dropbox, ProtonDrive, iCloud, or anything else; I didn’t want to be dependent upon a particular sync mechanism. Likewise, I needed the files to &lt;strong&gt;be&lt;/strong&gt; Markdown so that I wasn’t dependent upon a particular application, either. I’ve discussed before how I love having all of the posts on this site saved as Markdown because it means that I can (and have!) moved them quickly and easily between different websites. I wanted to have the same flexibility with my notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;notable&#34;&gt;Notable&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-good&#34;&gt;The Good&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did a quick search for note-taking applications that deal with Markdown, and one of the first results I got was &lt;a href=&#34;https://notable.app/&#34;&gt;Notable&lt;/a&gt;. Almost immediately it seemed to fit the bill. It was a simple, lightweight application that dealt with Markdown files. When a file is open in edit mode, I see all of the Markdown syntax I know and love. When I save a file, the Markdown is rendered for easy consumption. While I don’t get a live-preview like I do with &lt;a href=&#34;https://atom.io/&#34;&gt;Atom&lt;/a&gt;, I think this is a much more elegant setup for note-taking and reference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s important to note, pun not intended, that the name for “Notable” gives away the fact that it is &lt;em&gt;focused&lt;/em&gt; on notes in particular. When I was discussing my attempts to find a good Markdown editor for my notes, a friend of mine shared with me an &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.relay.fm/mpu/548&#34;&gt;episode of the Mac Power Users podcast focused on Markdown&lt;/a&gt;. While they list a lot of options (with an obvious focus on software for Apple products), many were not note-specific; some were just Markdown editors. For example, &lt;a href=&#34;https://bywordapp.com/&#34;&gt;Byword&lt;/a&gt; looks cool but seems to be much more focused on a minimalist writing experience than on a note-taking experience. While I could use something like that and simply search through my notes with &lt;code&gt;grep&lt;/code&gt; from the CLI, if I wanted to do that I would just use Vim or Atom as my editor and be done with it. I was &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; looking for something that would allow me to easily categorize and search my notes. Notable does this through tags which can be applied to each of my notes. Tags are used as an organization method; with them it’s easy to then do a text search across the content of either all of my notes or on just the notes with particular tags applied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of the notes created in Notable are &lt;code&gt;.md&lt;/code&gt; files that live in a directory I choose. At the moment, that directory is inside of my Dropbox folder. This is especially cool for a couple of reasons. First off, Dropbox can render Markdown files. So if I just need to &lt;em&gt;reference&lt;/em&gt; one of my notes from another device, I can simply go through Dropbox on the web, open the file, and reference all of my notes. I just have to know the name of the file since the tags are not readily accessible or searchable outside of Noteable. All of that information is stored as metadata at the top of each &lt;code&gt;.md&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-bad&#34;&gt;The Bad&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While using Notable has been working well for me after about a month, there are a couple of things that could be better. The immediate problem is that there isn’t any type of mobile app, and even if there were a mobile app I don’t know exactly how it would continue to sync since Dropbox isn’t keeping my files directly on my iPhone and iPad the way that it does on my MacBook. I think the design of Notable would need to be fundamentally changed, and suddenly integration with cloud storage would need to be done at the application level rather than the filesystem level. I don’t think that’s a good solution. Similarly, I also don’t really &lt;strong&gt;want&lt;/strong&gt; to be authoring a bunch of Markdown content on my mobile devices, either. Most of the notes I’d be using on my phone are more personal (e.g. my grocery list) and those I continue to use Apple Notes for. In the instance I need to &lt;em&gt;view&lt;/em&gt; some notes from Notable on my mobile device, that’s where opening them from Dropbox and rendering the Markdown works rather well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notable itself exists on a wide array of platforms. While it’s fairly simple to install on macOS or Debian-based Linux, I haven’t installed it yet on my Manjaro Linux laptop where it would be available via the &lt;a href=&#34;https://aur.archlinux.org/packages/notable-bin/&#34;&gt;AUR&lt;/a&gt;. I didn’t see the point since on this machine I haven’t installed &lt;a href=&#34;https://aur.archlinux.org/packages/dropbox/&#34;&gt;Dropbox&lt;/a&gt;, either, and that’s where all of the notes are. On this machine, however, I mainly only need to reference blog-specific notes; for those I’m typically just once again opening the files from Dropbox on the web. In the instance that I want to edit a note, I can use &lt;a href=&#34;https://dillinger.io/&#34;&gt;Dillinger&lt;/a&gt; for that to edit the files directly in Dropbox from the cloud. In another life, I made &lt;em&gt;heavy&lt;/em&gt; use of Dillinger for authoring blog posts for WordPress via Markdown; this was back when WordPress had support for authoring content in Markdown but didn’t support it in their editor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; rare cases I’ve wanted to create a new note in Notable but didn’t have access to my MacBook. In that case, from Dropbox I can simply copy an existing note, manually update the metadata to apply the appropriate tags, and then make whatever notes I need. I’ve verified in a few occasions that this seems to work without a hitch, though I suppose it’s possible to mess something up in the metadata if you really farkle it up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, the downsides I’ve enumerated here are more minor inconveniences than serious issues. I am curious how well the application will scale; right now I have a few dozen notes saved and everything is snappy. If I reach the same number of notes that I had in OneNote, though, I’m curious how quickly things like searching and swapping between notes will continue to be. The good news, though, is that since I’m not really locked in to Notable given that the files are just Markdown, if there are any problems in the future it shouldn’t be too terribly difficult to switch to something else or just work with the files directly if I can’t find a better solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re comfortable with Markdown and the idea of controlling your notes without being locked into a particular application for editing and syncing them is important to you, then I would highly recommend checking out Notable. I’m extremely pleased with it right now, and for the low cost of free there’s really no reason &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; to give it a shot. It’s worth mentioning that while Notable &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/notable/notable/blob/master/SOURCE_CODE.md&#34;&gt;was originally open source&lt;/a&gt;, that’s no longer the case. While I’d personally prefer if it was open source, it’s not a dealbreaker for me.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts On Apple&#39;s WWDC 2020</title>
      <link>https://unusually.pink/thoughts-on-apples-wwdc-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unusually.pink/thoughts-on-apples-wwdc-2020/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday was the keynote for Apple&amp;rsquo;s 2020 Worldwide Developer Conference. Like so many things right now, the entire conference, keynote included, is virtual due to the coronavirus pandemic. In this case, it&amp;rsquo;s a blessing for the sessions since it means they&amp;rsquo;re all free for anyone to stream as opposed to being a $1500+ USD ticket. Admittedly, though, the keynote left something to be desired. Just a few weeks ago at Microsoft Build, I feel like Microsoft crushed it with their keynote.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday was the keynote for Apple&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.apple.com/wwdc20/&#34;&gt;2020 Worldwide Developer Conference&lt;/a&gt;. Like so many things right now, the entire conference, keynote included, is virtual due to the coronavirus pandemic. In this case, it&amp;rsquo;s a blessing for the sessions since it means they&amp;rsquo;re all free for anyone to stream as opposed to being a $1500+ USD ticket. Admittedly, though, the keynote left something to be desired. Just a few weeks ago at &lt;a href=&#34;https://mybuild.microsoft.com/&#34;&gt;Microsoft Build&lt;/a&gt;, I feel like Microsoft crushed it with their keynote. It was still streamed live, and it featured popular Microsoft employees all working remote. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hanselman.com/blog/&#34;&gt;Scott Hanselman&lt;/a&gt; really killed it during the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mybuild.microsoft.com/sessions/871ef73f-f04a-405b-a0fa-01d7433067d1?WT.mc_id=-blog-scottha&#34;&gt;keynote with a ton of guests&lt;/a&gt; in a way that was still believable and relatable for everyone working from home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple&amp;rsquo;s keynote was just a recording, and while it had all of the glitz and shine you&amp;rsquo;d expect from Apple, it really felt more like a 2 hour advertisement at times. At the end of the day, the presentation itself doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter nearly as much as the content, but in the future I&amp;rsquo;d like for Apple to make things feel a little more&amp;hellip; &lt;em&gt;human&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought it would be fun to rank some of the announcements (especially to help organize my thoughts since a discussion on them is a likely podcast topic for me in the near future) at least for products that I actually care about. You won&amp;rsquo;t see anything about the Apple Watch here, for example, because I don&amp;rsquo;t own one, don&amp;rsquo;t plan to buy one, and didn&amp;rsquo;t even really pay attention to those parts of the keynote. That&amp;rsquo;s not to say anything bad about the Apple Watch; I just don&amp;rsquo;t need a health tracker or notifications on my wrist when I sit at home every&amp;hellip; single&amp;hellip; day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;meh&#34;&gt;Meh&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ios-app-library&#34;&gt;iOS App Library&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The App Library is basically a series of folders where applications are auto-sorted, giving some order to the chaos without forcing users to spend hours manually putting apps into folders themselves. I&amp;rsquo;m definitely not opposed to the idea, but it gets a sold &amp;ldquo;meh&amp;rdquo; from me simply because I don&amp;rsquo;t have enough apps for that sort of thing to be useful. At the time of this writing, my phone has 3 pages of apps, none of which are even full. I rarely install apps unless I really need them, and I regularly prune any apps I haven&amp;rsquo;t opened in a few weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;app-clips&#34;&gt;App Clips&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like the idea of these; App Clips are small, partial versions of apps that you can access on the fly without needing to open the App Store, search for the correct app, and then download the whole thing. The example they gave is when you need a specific app to pay for parking, a situation I&amp;rsquo;ve definitely been in before. Beyond that scenario, though, I&amp;rsquo;m just skeptical over how useful this will be. When I go into stores, am I going to be willing to scan a special barcode to access their App Clip? Most likely that&amp;rsquo;s going to be a hard pass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;widgets&#34;&gt;Widgets&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like App Clips, I like the &lt;em&gt;idea&lt;/em&gt; of Widgets, and having more options and sizes is cool. I&amp;rsquo;ll definitely take some time to play around with new ones in my sidebar. What I&amp;rsquo;m not as enthused about is the ability to start cluttering up the app list with widgets sprinkled everywhere. I&amp;rsquo;ve seen a few people draw parallels to the home screen of Windows Phone 8, and I don&amp;rsquo;t think that&amp;rsquo;s a particularly good thing. Obviously I can just choose to only use widgets in the sidebar where they live today, but I hope they don&amp;rsquo;t start to change the focus of the app list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;good&#34;&gt;Good&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;picture-in-picture&#34;&gt;Picture-In-Picture&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve seen a lot of people throwing (warranted) shade that this is something which has existed for quite a while on Android, and that&amp;rsquo;s certainly true. Just because they&amp;rsquo;re late to the party, though, doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean Apple &lt;em&gt;shouldn&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em&gt; add picture-in-picture; that&amp;rsquo;s just silly. Having recently switched from being a long-time Android user to an iPhone user, picture-in-picture is one of the few things I miss from Android. It&amp;rsquo;s super handy when you&amp;rsquo;re watching a video to be able to pop out to picture-in-picture mode and quickly check something else. I also like the look of some of the intuitive controls Apple seems to have worked out to improve the experience over that of Android with the ability to easily resize and even hide the video while it plays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;maps-improvements&#34;&gt;Maps Improvements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cycling-specific additions to Maps look slick, though they aren&amp;rsquo;t initially available in my area, and I don&amp;rsquo;t currently do a lot of cycling regardless.. Given my goal of eschewing all things Google, though, since switching to an iPhone I&amp;rsquo;ve been relying on Apple Maps in lieu of Google Maps. As such, I like seeing the commitment Apple has to improving the product. I also appreciate the fact that they themselves mentioned the privacy of Maps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;macos-big-sur&#34;&gt;macOS Big Sur&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most immediately noticeable things about Big Sur are the UI tweaks. Most of them are small and subtle, but overall I think it really makes the operating system look significantly better. Having everything slightly tweaked with the uniformity and cohesion you&amp;rsquo;d expect from Apple just makes everything look and feel extremely polished. I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to using it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More specifically, I&amp;rsquo;m also looking forward to getting my hands on the updated versions of the Mail and Messages applications in Big Sur. I live in those applications pretty frequently, and they feel just a little dated in Catalina.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;aww-yeah&#34;&gt;Aww Yeah!&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;siri-improvements&#34;&gt;Siri Improvements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use Siri not infrequently on both my phone and iPad. One of those most jarring things about it is the experience you get when it takes over your entire screen to answer a simple query. The new UI for Siri looks like a massive improvement to me, with Siri appearing as a sphere toward the bottom of the screen and not covering all of the content with which you may have just been interacting. I think this will make for a much better workflow, especially for sequential questions to Siri where your next question is based off of the response to the previous question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On top of that, it&amp;rsquo;s also nice to see a focus from Apple on giving Siri to the ability to respond to a broader range of questions. While it doesn&amp;rsquo;t happen all the time, it&amp;rsquo;s not unexpected when I ask Siri something only to be essentially given a list of links from a web search rather than an actual answer. The more that type of response can be eliminated, the better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ipados-sidebar&#34;&gt;iPadOS Sidebar&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This may seem silly, but I&amp;rsquo;m actually &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; stoked for the new sidebar UI in iPadOS. I think it&amp;rsquo;ll add a lot of uniformity to iPad apps that also make better use of the screen real-estate you get on an iPad. Too many apps that are &amp;ldquo;optimized&amp;rdquo; for an iPad (meaning they aren&amp;rsquo;t scaled iPhone apps), are still essentially just bigger versions of their iPhone counterparts. The more that can be done to make the iPad a unique thing of its own with its own strengths the better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;hell-yeah&#34;&gt;Hell Yeah!&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;macos-running-a-series-arm-processors&#34;&gt;macOS Running A-series ARM Processors&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the most-leaked announcement in human history, I think pretty much everyone was expecting this announcement. It was still exciting to see it made official, though. Given how stagnant Intel processors have been for the last few generations and the insane performance Apple is getting out of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.apple.com/ipad-pro/specs/&#34;&gt;A12Z Bionic in the iPad Pro&lt;/a&gt;, I think this is a smart and exciting move. A chip like the A12Z Bionic in something with active cooling? Sign me up. I &lt;em&gt;was&lt;/em&gt; surprised that the first ARM macOS devices will ship before the end of the year, but it seems like the process for porting applications is fairly streamlined. Likewise, having a binary translator like &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rosetta_(software)#Rosetta_2&#34;&gt;Rosetta 2&lt;/a&gt; for any applications not getting timely love is a nice safety net, though I don&amp;rsquo;t know if I&amp;rsquo;d &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; want to be playing games run through it like they had demoed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;wrap-up&#34;&gt;Wrap-Up&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of the day, nothing absolutely Earth-shattering was announced at WWDC 2020 &lt;em&gt;other&lt;/em&gt; than the macOS architecture switch that everyone already knew about. I still think there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of solid improvments coming on the horizon, though, and I&amp;rsquo;m eager to start upgrading my devices to the new software this fall.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
