<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>bandcamp on Unusually Pink</title>
    <link>https://hugo.unusually.pink/tags/bandcamp/</link>
    <description>Recent content in bandcamp on Unusually Pink</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>2021</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hugo.unusually.pink/tags/bandcamp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2020 Apple Music Replay</title>
      <link>https://hugo.unusually.pink/posts/2020-apple-music-replay/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hugo.unusually.pink/posts/2020-apple-music-replay/</guid>
      <description>At the end of each year I always look forward to my yearly music stats. I did a post back in 2018 with my Spotify Wrapped statistics, and Brandi and I did a podcast episode on our 2019 music stats. This year is a bit wonky since I used several different music services, but the most relevant metrics I got were from my 2020 Replay from Apple Music. Apple gives a few metrics after getting some flack for historically not providing anything like what Spotify does, but what they did share is at least interesting and worthy of comparison to previous years.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;At the end of each year I always look forward to my yearly music stats. I did a post back in &lt;a href=&#34;https://unusually.pink/2018-in-music-spotify-wrapped/&#34;&gt;2018 with my Spotify Wrapped statistics&lt;/a&gt;, and Brandi and I did a podcast episode on our &lt;a href=&#34;https://unusuallypinkpodcast.podbean.com/e/episode-18-end-of-year-music-stats/&#34;&gt;2019 music stats&lt;/a&gt;. This year is a bit wonky since I used several different music services, but the most relevant metrics I got were from my 2020 Replay from Apple Music. Apple gives a few metrics after getting some flack for historically not providing anything like what Spotify does, but what they did share is at least interesting and worthy of comparison to previous years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along with the metrics, Apple also provides a 2020 Replay playlist with the most played tracks for each user. Feel free to &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.apple.com/us/playlist/replay-2020/pl.rp-XWWGiykwaMlw&#34;&gt;check out mine&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;time-listened&#34;&gt;Time Listened&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Apple, in 2020 I spent &lt;strong&gt;962&lt;/strong&gt; hours listening to music, or over &lt;strong&gt;40&lt;/strong&gt; days. For the sake of comparison, in my 2018 Spotify Wrapped I listened to 845 hours of music. This is especially impressive to me when considering that I &lt;em&gt;didn&amp;rsquo;t use Apple Music for the entire year&lt;/em&gt;. I started using Apple Music in early 2020 shortly after I switched to an iPhone; prior to that I was still using Spotify for about a month. I also spent about 2 months trying out &lt;a href=&#34;https://unusually.pink/apple-music-back-in-the-saddle/&#34;&gt;Amazon Music before switching back to Apple Music&lt;/a&gt;. Similarly, I spent a good bit of time listening to music I purchased during &lt;a href=&#34;https://unusually.pink/buy-literally-anything-from-bandcamp-today/&#34;&gt;Bandcamp&amp;rsquo;s specials where all of the money went to the artists&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I listened to far less music in 2020 while driving simply because I didn&amp;rsquo;t really drive anywhere during the pandemic, I listened to much &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; music while working since I never had to account for anyone else being around given that I now work from home full time. If I wasn&amp;rsquo;t in a meeting or on a call, there&amp;rsquo;s a good chance that I had some music playing while I worked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;artists&#34;&gt;Artists&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/phem.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;phem&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I listened to &lt;strong&gt;2,217&lt;/strong&gt; different artists. Suffice to say, I did a good bit of music discovery. A lot of that came from things like my personalized playlists from Apple and Apple&amp;rsquo;s curated, new music playlists in the genres I like. Plenty of it happened naturally as I would frequently go to the indie section each week, for example, and just listen to every new release that seemed interesting. While the albums sometimes wouldn&amp;rsquo;t appeal to me, on the whole it was a terrific way to find tons of new artists I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have discovered otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of my top artists had new album releases that I played endlessly, as we&amp;rsquo;ll see in the next section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grimes - 14 hours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dua Lipa - 9 hours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jinka - 8 hours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allie X - 8 hours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Soccer Mommy - 7 hours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HAIM - 6 hours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vita and the Woolf - 6 hours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ashnikko - 6 hours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;phem - 6 hours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dounia - 5 hours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From this list, I want to give the nod to phem for absolutely crushing it in 2020 with new releases. From her cover of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7q5soAhn_fs&#34;&gt;Creep&lt;/a&gt; to her releases of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=p4zZB5ShvyU&#34;&gt;Self Control&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=55XuQm3NZi8&#34;&gt;stfu&lt;/a&gt;, she was easily one of my favorite artists of the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;albums&#34;&gt;Albums&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/jinka.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jinka&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I listened to &lt;strong&gt;310&lt;/strong&gt; different albums in 2020. The metrics for the individual albums are a little weird as Apple doesn&amp;rsquo;t really highlight what they mean when they count the number of times I&amp;rsquo;ve &amp;ldquo;played&amp;rdquo; an album. I &lt;em&gt;think&lt;/em&gt; they&amp;rsquo;re counting playing a track from that album as a play of the album, regardless of whether I&amp;rsquo;ve played it from the album directly or when the song was added to a playlist. Many of the albums on the list did receive the &amp;ldquo;we&amp;rsquo;re just going to play this on loop for the entire day&amp;rdquo; treatment, though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Future Nostalgia - Dua Lipa - 127 plays&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No Anything Else - Jinka - 108 plays&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anna Ohio - Vita and the Woolf - 75 plays&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;color theory - Soccer Mommy - 63 plays&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Petals for Armor - Hayley Williams - 58 plays&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;folklore - Taylor Swift - 51 plays&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Miss Anthropocene (Deluxe Edition) - Grimes - 50 plays&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bad Ideas - Tessa Violet - 48 plays&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cape God - Allie X - 46 plays&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SAWAYAMA - Rina Sawayama - 44 plays&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2020 saw a ton of great album releases. While many of them I had been eagerly anticipating, &lt;em&gt;No Anything Else&lt;/em&gt; by Jinka completely caught me off guard and was easily one of my favorites. It was an album I stumbled upon while just listening to anything new in the Apple Music indie section, and it almost immediately became one of my favorites that I played on loop for days. Literally every song on it is phenomenal, though &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jDwHtgRiwfQ&#34;&gt;QT3.14&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/uDNxEYIegBc&#34;&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d Like That&lt;/a&gt; emerged as my absolute favorites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;wrap-up&#34;&gt;Wrap Up&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While 2020 was an awful year in plenty of regards, we had a ton of amazing new music from talented artists to help us get through it&amp;hellip; even while many of the artists creating it suffered since they weren&amp;rsquo;t able to go on tour, do shows, and sell merchandise. While I imagine that trend will continue for at least the first half of 2021 (at least in the United States, where I am), I&amp;rsquo;m excited for finally being able to see live shows again and going out of my way to support all of the artists who helped us so much. Here&amp;rsquo;s to more incredible music in 2021. If I stick with one product the entire year, I think I can easily eclipse 1000 hours of time listened!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Buy Literally Anything From Bandcamp Today</title>
      <link>https://hugo.unusually.pink/posts/buy-literally-anything-from-bandcamp-today/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hugo.unusually.pink/posts/buy-literally-anything-from-bandcamp-today/</guid>
      <description>The coronavirus has been causing havoc for industries across the globe, including the music industry. Especially for small, indie artists, the revenue they make from doing live shows is vital for their ability to continue doing what they love. In the case of a global pandemic, though, all of those shows have been canceled, leaving artists struggling to make it by.
Having been social distancing/self quarantining for about two weeks now, I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing my best to live by the very wise, meaningful words of Craft Brew Geek when he told a group of us:</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;The coronavirus has been causing havoc for industries across the globe, including the music industry. Especially for small, indie artists, the revenue they make from doing live shows is vital for their ability to continue doing what they love. In the case of a global pandemic, though, all of those shows have been canceled, leaving artists struggling to make it by.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having been social distancing/self quarantining for about two weeks now, I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing my best to live by the very wise, meaningful words of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/craftbrewgeek/&#34;&gt;Craft Brew Geek&lt;/a&gt; when he told a group of us:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the time when we need to take care of the people who take care of us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He said this within the context of doing what we can for local restaurants and breweries that are trying to weather this storm. There are plenty of places where we&amp;rsquo;re regulars and have been the recipients of preferrential treatment from those establishments for months or even years: getting your drink filled before other people, getting deals on your order, etc. As these businesses try to tackle the biggest threat to their very existence that they&amp;rsquo;ve ever seen, we&amp;rsquo;ve been doing our part to get carry-out food and drinks whenever possible and while leaving the most generous tips we can because every little bit helps. I&amp;rsquo;d highly encourage anyone reading this to do the same if it&amp;rsquo;s within your means.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But restaurants and breweries aren&amp;rsquo;t the only ones who take care of you. My memory tends to be pretty good, so I trust it when I recall Hayley Williams posting a message on Twitter &lt;em&gt;years&lt;/em&gt; ago that amounted to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be there for music because music will always be there for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried searching for the post, but it was so long ago that I&amp;rsquo;ll never find it. The sentiment is certainly true though. Everyone has had that song that has made an event, be it a party, a roadtrip, or just a special moment with friends, unforgettable. Everyone has felt sorrow and heartache and didn&amp;rsquo;t know how they would&amp;rsquo;ve been able to get through if it wasn&amp;rsquo;t for that &lt;strong&gt;one&lt;/strong&gt; song that knew exactly how you felt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Music has had such a profound impact on my life, and I can&amp;rsquo;t imagine where I&amp;rsquo;d be without it. It pains me to see so many small artists having to cancel their shows, knowing they&amp;rsquo;re upset at having to let down their fans and worried about how they&amp;rsquo;re going to continue making ends meet and create the art we all love so much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s why today is such a great day to support indie music. Today &lt;a href=&#34;https://daily.bandcamp.com/features/bandcamp-covid-19-fundraiser&#34;&gt;Bandcamp is waiving their revenue share on all purchases through the site&lt;/a&gt;. This means that 100% of the revenue is going to support artists who need it now more than ever. Dozens of artists I listen to regularly, and some of whom were mentioned in our &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unusually.pink/podcast/episode-18-end-of-year-music-stats&#34;&gt;music stats episode&lt;/a&gt; have Bandcamp profiles. Even if you don&amp;rsquo;t need a digital album because you always use Spotify or Apple Music, consider buying an album anyway just to help out and show some love for the people who have made such a difference in your life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/BuyLiterallyAnythingFromBandcampToday_music.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pre-orders count as well, so you can show some support for artists with upcoming albums. Also note that most albums have a minimum price but offer you the ability to throw a little extra on top if you want. Please help out if you have the means.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you don&amp;rsquo;t have the means, you can still help out! The payouts are garbage, but stream as much music from indie artists as you possibly can. Check out the Twitter profiles for artists you love; many have started doing online shows. For example, on her &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOw4v1j3QnzH7X4krQAS7fg&#34;&gt;YouTube channel&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/TessaViolet&#34;&gt;Tessa Violet&lt;/a&gt; has been streaming what she&amp;rsquo;s coined &amp;ldquo;The Something To Look Forward To Tour&amp;rdquo;. There are still 3 shows left. Tune in for those and look for other artists who are doing the same!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/BuyLiterallyAnythingFromBandcampToday_stlftt-768x1024.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do whatever you can to support artists and musicians now because every little bit helps. It&amp;rsquo;s time that we take care of the people who take care of us.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
