<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>hilton on Unusually Pink</title>
    <link>https://hugo.unusually.pink/tags/hilton/</link>
    <description>Recent content in hilton on Unusually Pink</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>2021</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hugo.unusually.pink/tags/hilton/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>BlizzCon and the AXS of Evil</title>
      <link>https://hugo.unusually.pink/posts/blizzcon-and-the-axs-of-evil/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hugo.unusually.pink/posts/blizzcon-and-the-axs-of-evil/</guid>
      <description>As we mention in our latest episode, our plans have changed and we will not be going to BlizzCon this year. We could just let it go and accept that it is what it is… but remember how I mentioned my love of throwing salt into the Internet? So we’re gonna do that instead!
AXS: The most useless ticketing service We mentioned a few of our issues with AXS in Episode 5.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;As we mention in our &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unusually.pink/podcast&#34;&gt;latest episode&lt;/a&gt;, our plans have changed and we will &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; be going to BlizzCon this year. We could just let it go and accept that it is what it is… but remember how I mentioned my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unusually.pink/blog/microsoft-edge-insider-its-actually-not-that-bad&#34;&gt;love of throwing salt into the Internet&lt;/a&gt;? So we’re gonna do that instead!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;axs-the-most-useless-ticketing-service&#34;&gt;AXS: The most useless ticketing service&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We mentioned a few of our issues with AXS in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unusually.pink/podcast/episode-5-gotta-blizz-em-all&#34;&gt;Episode 5&lt;/a&gt;. It’s the new ticketing service that Blizzard decided to go with this year. Using AXS was a first for them; last year they went with Universe. In theory, it seemed like a good idea for a convention as popular as BlizzCon where there’s always a massive scramble to get tickets. Instead of having to hope you’re lucky enough to click on the button to buy tickets within 0.23 seconds of it going live, AXS is &lt;strong&gt;supposed&lt;/strong&gt; to serve as an equalizer. They open up a lobby 30 minutes before tickets are available. Anyone who is in that lobby at &lt;strong&gt;any&lt;/strong&gt; time before tickets go live is supposed to have an equal chance at getting them. Hopeful customers are randomly selected from the lobby and are given 7 minutes to purchase their tickets. Seven minutes is plenty of time, but if you don’t purchase them within that allotment then you’ve lost your opportunity and someone else from the lobby is given a chance at them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem is that &lt;strong&gt;it didn’t fucking work at all&lt;/strong&gt;. Instead of getting tickets when I submitted the purchase after getting lucky RNG, I got this error. Over and over and over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/BlizzConandtheAXSofEvil_axs_is_trash.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I immediately opened support cases with both Blizzard and AXS. Blizzard was insanely unhelpful. They first asserted it must’ve been an issue with my card. I told them I tried 3 different cards with the same results, and that I saw pending transactions for each of them. They then told me it would have to be handled through AXS. This isn’t surprising, but I was hoping they would be a bit more accommodating considering it was an error on the side of the partner they were ignorant enough to select. So I then waited to hear something on my support case with AXS. And waited. And waited. And &lt;strong&gt;waited&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Days went by without hearing anything, so I hit them up on Twitter where they asked me to DM them. I sent them my case number and they responded with the following lovely exchange:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/BlizzConandtheAXSofEvil_axs_dms_edit.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Essentially they just admitted that their service didn’t do the &lt;strong&gt;one thing it’s supposed to do&lt;/strong&gt;. On top of that, they didn’t even bother to read my reply, let alone respond to it. As I point out with the arrows I drew in the screenshot above, the blue check next to my original message means that it was “Seen”. The grey check next to my follow-up questions simply means that it was “Sent”. If that isn’t garbage-tier customer service, I don’t know what is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, this apparently counted as covering the support case I opened as I never received an email or anything else in regard to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite this setback, we were still planning to go. Brandi had been in touch with someone we met at BlizzCon last year who has a friend who works for Blizzard and thus was supposedly able to hit us up with tickets. They weren’t on lockdown yet since internal folks apparently get their tickets later on, but we figured worst-case scenario we’d get to hang out in southern California for a few days. It was a nice bonus because I we got a great deal on a hotel… until we didn’t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;hilton-us-where-it-hurts&#34;&gt;Hilton us where it hurts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’ve ever been to BlizzCon before, then you know the Anaheim Hilton is &lt;strong&gt;the&lt;/strong&gt; place to be. Along with being right next to the Anaheim Convention Center for easy access to BlizzCon, it’s also the after-hours social hub of the convention with parties breaking out each night. The Hilton embraces this and last year had a bunch of pop-up bars in the lobby selling Bottle Logic’s special StarCraft 20th Anniversary beer. It was awesome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/BlizzConandtheAXSofEvil_sc_beer.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year we didn’t stay at the Hilton because, on top of just being a Hilton, event prices are pretty insane. Staying for just 4 days, for example, easily pushes over $2,000 USD. I have family who works for Hilton which means I can often get a “friends and family” discount, but events are always blacked out. Brandi and I just happened to check this year, though, and sure enough discounted rooms were available. Suffice to say we pounced on one, booking 5 days for half the price most people were paying for 4 days. Even if something fell through without our BlizzCon tickets, being in the area and in the epicenter for the happenings of the convention still seemed super fun. Unfortunately, a week later I got the following email:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We are contacting you regarding your upcoming Go Hilton reservation at Hilton Anaheim - Confirmation # XXXXXXXXXX. Unfortunately, due to a misconfiguration in our booking system there were Go Hilton rates offered that should have not been made available. This affected reservations booked between May 09th and May 13th 2019. We regret to inform you that we can no longer honor these reservations, and they will be cancelled shortly. We are deeply sorry for this inconvenience and appreciate your understanding due to the systems error.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Followed shortly by a cancellation email with the most tone-deaf greeting possible:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“JOHN, we’re sorry to see you go! We hope you allow Hilton Hotels &amp;amp; Resorts the opportunity to serve you in the future.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I let Brandi know, we were both pretty fed up with the whole ordeal. Along with losing the insanely good Hilton pricing, now a week had passed since most people would have booked their rooms… meaning that the availability of something else in the area had already been shrinking. We would have to settle for a worse room at a higher price. Did we really want to spend the money and go through the hassle when neither of us having even played a Blizzard game in the past three months? Ultimately the answer was no, so we’ll be bailing on the convention this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the money we &lt;em&gt;aren’t&lt;/em&gt; spending on BlizzCon, Brandi and I will likely do other cool shit this year. I have a few other trips in mind that I’d like to take, and Brandi is getting a freaking puppy! Expect &lt;strong&gt;TONS&lt;/strong&gt; of puppy pics on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/unusuallypinkpodcast/&#34;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt; when that happens!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, keep the Morton’s flowing and stay pink!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
