<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>twenty-twenty-one on Unusually Pink</title>
    <link>https://hugo.unusually.pink/tags/twenty-twenty-one/</link>
    <description>Recent content in twenty-twenty-one on Unusually Pink</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>2021</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hugo.unusually.pink/tags/twenty-twenty-one/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Twenty Twenty-One WordPress Theme</title>
      <link>https://hugo.unusually.pink/twenty-twenty-one-wordpress-theme/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hugo.unusually.pink/twenty-twenty-one-wordpress-theme/</guid>
      <description>While I made the change a few weeks ago, it seems fitting that my first post of 2021 should be about my swap to the Twenty Twenty-One WordPress theme. For anyone who isn&amp;rsquo;t aware, each year WordPress releases a new &amp;ldquo;official&amp;rdquo; theme for the platform. While theme-elitists out there may scoff at them in favor of paid, premium themes, I&amp;rsquo;ve always found the yearly offerings to be elegant and well-designed. I had originally planned on putting this post together on January 1st, but what can I say&amp;hellip; movies on HBO Now aren&amp;rsquo;t going to binge-watch themselves.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;While I made the change a few weeks ago, it seems fitting that my first post of 2021 should be about my swap to the Twenty Twenty-One WordPress theme. For anyone who isn&amp;rsquo;t aware, each year WordPress releases a new &amp;ldquo;official&amp;rdquo; theme for the platform. While theme-elitists out there may scoff at them in favor of paid, premium themes, I&amp;rsquo;ve always found the yearly offerings to be elegant and well-designed. I had &lt;em&gt;originally&lt;/em&gt; planned on putting this post together on January 1st, but what can I say&amp;hellip; movies on HBO Now aren&amp;rsquo;t going to binge-watch themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I&amp;rsquo;ve typically enjoyed the yearly WordPress theme releases, the previous iteration of this blog was actually back on the Twenty Sixteen theme since the yearly releases after that one didn&amp;rsquo;t feel like they were a particularly good fit for a blog. I still liked the look of the Twenty Sixteen theme, especially after I switched the colors around to match the &lt;a href=&#34;https://unusually.pink/all-dracula-everything/&#34;&gt;Dracula Theme&lt;/a&gt;, but the fact remains that 2016 is more or less ancient history in the world of web design. As a result, parts of the site just felt a bit&amp;hellip; antiquated. For example, while the banner at the top allowed me to show off the Unusually Pink graphics that we originally commissioned for the podcast, it left the site feeling just a bit old.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hugo.unusually.pink/images/cropped-cropped-Unusually-Pink-Facebook-Cover-Photo.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The artwork is still amazing, though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I spent a decent bit of time tweaking the Twenty Sixteen theme to suit my needs, once I saw the &lt;a href=&#34;https://make.wordpress.org/core/2020/09/23/introducing-twenty-twenty-one/&#34;&gt;Twenty Twenty-One theme announcement in September I decided to stop further tweaking and try being patient&lt;/a&gt;. I also followed a bit &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/wordpress/twentytwentyone&#34;&gt;of the progress on the GitHub repository&lt;/a&gt;, but not being a web developer meant that it didn&amp;rsquo;t really give me a good vibe for how the theme would feel in practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the theme released, though, I immediately found myself drawn to how minimalist and streamlined it is. I feel like it provides me with the bare necessities, and then I can expand upon it from there to fit my needs without a lot of unnecessary overhead. One look at the current layout at the time of this writing probably clues you in to the fact that these aren&amp;rsquo;t the default colors; I once again opted to update the design to feel like the Dracula theme. While Twenty Twenty-One offers less in the customization UI for modifying the colors, it can still easily be done via CSS (a level of access that I sorely missed when &lt;a href=&#34;https://unusually.pink/unusually-pink-migration/&#34;&gt;the site was hosted on Squarespace&lt;/a&gt;.) I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if there&amp;rsquo;s a better way to do it than just opening the published site in my browser&amp;rsquo;s developer tools and using the inspection feature to get the classes of the objects I want to change, but that ended up getting me to the end result I wanted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along with the colors, I also felt the need to adjust some of the font sizes. In the default setup, Twenty Twenty-One opts for &lt;strong&gt;big&lt;/strong&gt; fonts, and while they looked kind of nice on my brand new MacBook Pro with a Retina display, on my 1080p, 11&amp;quot; &lt;a href=&#34;https://unusually.pink/star-lite-mk-iii/&#34;&gt;Star Lite Mk III&lt;/a&gt; going to a post would result in just the header and the post title being visible. None of the actual content could be read without scrolling. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t thrilled about my site looking so gigantic on lower resolution displays, so many of the font sizes were tweaked. That being said, as someone with extremely poor vision I&amp;rsquo;m a fan of large-ish fonts, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to completely flip to tiny text. Readability is, arguably, one of the most import things on a text-heavy site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If anyone is curious, my full CSS customizations are below. Hopefully it&amp;rsquo;s not too offensive since frontend is most definitely not my specialty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While there may still be some minor adjustments for sizes and spacing, for the most part I like where things are at. I&amp;rsquo;ve historically disliked blog landing pages which only showed the beginning of each post, but I&amp;rsquo;ve done a bit of a 180 in that regard. With Twenty Twenty-One I&amp;rsquo;ve been appreciating how the front page is much less cumbersome, especially when trying to reach the links or search box at the very bottom of the page. I think it also provides a bit of a cleaner focus on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://unusually.pink/about/&#34;&gt;link for the About page&lt;/a&gt; that I link to on most of my online profiles.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
