<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>privacy on Unusually Pink</title>
    <link>https://hugo.unusually.pink/tags/privacy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in privacy on Unusually Pink</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>2021</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hugo.unusually.pink/tags/privacy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Even More Storage: Yearly Bonuses For Paid ProtonMail Accounts</title>
      <link>https://hugo.unusually.pink/even-more-storage-yearly-bonuses-for-paid-protonmail-accounts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hugo.unusually.pink/even-more-storage-yearly-bonuses-for-paid-protonmail-accounts/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s no secret around this blog or for anyone who listened to the Unusually Pink Podcast that I&amp;rsquo;m a fan of ProtonMail. While it&amp;rsquo;s unfortunate that privacy in the world of computing often comes with an associated monetary cost, the simple fact of the matter is that if you aren&amp;rsquo;t paying for your email account then chances are the provider is making money off of your data that happens to be stored in it.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s no secret &lt;a href=&#34;https://unusually.pink/protonmail-bonus-storage/&#34;&gt;around this blog&lt;/a&gt; or for anyone who listened to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dropbox.com/sh/v9yvrhsoahu2vlw/AAB_JaXv3isvQjVyIMdlPHm6a?dl=0&#34;&gt;Unusually Pink Podcast&lt;/a&gt; that I&amp;rsquo;m a fan of ProtonMail. While it&amp;rsquo;s unfortunate that privacy in the world of computing often comes with an associated monetary cost, the simple fact of the matter is that if you &lt;em&gt;aren&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em&gt; paying for your email account then chances are the provider is making money off of your data that happens to be stored in it. Google, for example, is happy to give you free email so that they can scrape your data out of it and make a comprehensive profile about your life for advertising purposes. ProtonMail takes a firm stance against this practice, and they actually &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; permit users to create completely free email accounts that are never scraped or monitored; their setup actually ensures that they couldn&amp;rsquo;t access the plaintext content of your email even if they wanted to. Doing this is only possible, though, because some users opt to pay for additional features and thus subsidize the free accounts. I happen to be one of those people who has been paying for a few years now both to help support the ProtonMail mission and to get access to a custom domain in my account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ProtonMail occasionally likes to give special perks to their paid customers as a token of appreciation; I&amp;rsquo;ve written before about how they&amp;rsquo;ve &lt;a href=&#34;https://unusually.pink/protonmail-bonus-storage/&#34;&gt;given away a bonus 5 GB of storage for paid accounts&lt;/a&gt;. They&amp;rsquo;ve done the same thing another time since that post, giving me 10 GB of bonus storage on top of the 5 GB that comes with my paid plan. While I said at the time of my original post that I didn&amp;rsquo;t really need the storage at the moment but was happy to have the extra bits just in case, ProtonMail has subsequently stated that the storage can be shared with the upcoming ProtonDrive secure cloud storage offering once that&amp;rsquo;s available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As another token of gratitude, ProtonMail has announced regular storage increases for paid accounts; each year that a paid account remains active, it receives 1 GB of bonus storage on the anniversary. Even better, this is retroactive. Since I&amp;rsquo;ve had a paid account for 3 years, when the initiative was implemented I immediately received 3 GB of bonus storage. I&amp;rsquo;ll get a 4th GB on my yearly anniversary coming up later this month:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The general principle is straightforward:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- When you sign up for any paid Proton plan, you are automatically eligible for Storage Bonuses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- On the one year anniversary of your paid subscription, you will receive 1 GB of additional storage for free that can be used with your ProtonMail inbox. (In the future, your storage will be shared between your ProtonMail inbox and your ProtonDrive vault.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- This will happen every year, and your Storage Bonuses will accumulate as long as you have a paid plan with Proton without interruption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the current bonus value is 1 GB right now, they say this will increase in the future, though it&amp;rsquo;s unclear if the increase is also retroactive or if it will only apply to new bonus accumulations going forward:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current Storage Bonus is 1 GB per year, but this will be increased in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The full details are available, along with a FAQ, from &lt;a href=&#34;https://protonmail.com/support/knowledge-base/storage-bonus/?utm_campaign=ww-en-2c-mail-coms_email-storage_reward_email&amp;amp;utm_source=proton_users&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_content=mail_paid%3E1yr&amp;amp;utm_term=learn_more_about_storage_here&#34;&gt;their support article&lt;/a&gt;. The tl;dr is basically that you get bonus storage every year on the anniversary of your paid account as long as you remain with a paid subscription on &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; Proton product. This means that if you pay for ProtonVPN but not ProtonMail, you&amp;rsquo;re still eligible for the bonus storage. That eligibility and current storage accumulation continues to apply even if you stop paying for ProtonVPN and start paying for ProtonMail (or ProtonDrive when it comes out) as long as the two periods overlap. Having a lapse in paid subscription will reset the accumulation of bonus storage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All told, I think it&amp;rsquo;s another nice perk from ProtonMail, and with the ability to leverage the storage for ProtonDrive, a product that I&amp;rsquo;m &lt;em&gt;highly&lt;/em&gt; looking forward to, the more storage that I can get my hands on the better.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trying Out NextDNS</title>
      <link>https://hugo.unusually.pink/trying-out-nextdns/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hugo.unusually.pink/trying-out-nextdns/</guid>
      <description>I recently decided to take a little bit of time to set up NextDNS. While on the surface it&amp;rsquo;s similar to the myriad other DNS resolvers out there you can opt to use instead of the likely horrible DNS servers provided by your ISP, NextDNS is essentially a cloud-based Pi-hole. You can use some of the built-in blacklists in the product to block things like advertising, trackers, malware domains, and more.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;I recently decided to take a little bit of time to set up &lt;a href=&#34;https://nextdns.io/&#34;&gt;NextDNS&lt;/a&gt;. While on the surface it&amp;rsquo;s similar to the myriad other DNS resolvers out there you can opt to use instead of the likely horrible DNS servers provided by your ISP, NextDNS is essentially a cloud-based &lt;a href=&#34;https://pi-hole.net/&#34;&gt;Pi-hole&lt;/a&gt;. You can use some of the built-in blacklists in the product to block things like advertising, trackers, malware domains, and more. There are a few key benefits to blocking things at the DNS level rather than relying on something to do the blocking your web browser. First off, most mobile browsers don&amp;rsquo;t offer the same robust extension ecosystems we&amp;rsquo;re all used to with full computers; you might be able to toggle some settings to block trackers, for example, but advertising is often a different beast altogether (though the &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; bad advertisements typically also have egregious tackers, meaning that blocking the trackers will block the ads.) Additionally, there are some nefarious browser extension posing as ad-blockers, and there have been instances of &lt;a href=&#34;https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2020/10/popular-chromium-ad-blockers-caught-stealing-user-data-and-accessing-accounts/&#34;&gt;legitimate extensions being sold and turned nefarious&lt;/a&gt;. Google&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://9to5google.com/2019/01/22/google-chrome-break-ad-blockers/&#34;&gt;extremely sleazy war on ad-blocking&lt;/a&gt; also makes DNS-based filtering attractive, though I&amp;rsquo;d still recommend people avoid Chromium-based browsers if at all possible. The other nice part is that you can easily configure DNS settings on a router, meaning the same degree of protection can apply to IoT devices with no accessible network settings of their own. This similarly applies to applications on your computer that connect to the network outside of a browser, as we&amp;rsquo;ll see later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NextDNS handles this by allowing you to specify your public IP address in their portal, thus linking traffic from your home with your NextDNS profile and all of the configurations that are in place there. The only caveat to it is needing to configure DDNS in some way or simply remembering to go to the portal in order to update the IP address should it ever change. Additionally, they offer apps for basically every major platform for configuring your devices and pointing them to the appropriate account. While you &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; just update the DNS settings in your host operating system rather than using an app, the app is still required for linking your device to your profile so that it will leverage the appropriate block lists. What I found to be &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; nice was that the iOS and iPad apps are able to leverage the new iOS 14 DNS profiles, meaning that it &lt;em&gt;doesn&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em&gt; need to create a shell VPN tunnel just for your DNS requests; that&amp;rsquo;s a huge win.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To really test it out, for about 2 weeks I disabled the ad-blockers in my common browsers and tried to let NextDNS handle the brunt of my filtering needs. Getting it configured everywhere was fairly simple. The web portal will tell you what your current public IP is and offers a simple button to update your account to leverage that IP address. This made it simple to get basically everything in my home network using it after I modified the DNS servers in my router. I still went ahead and configured the settings individually on my devices, too, for the rare instance during a global pandemic when I&amp;rsquo;m on a network other than my home network. The iOS and iPad apps just need you to tap a button to add the new DNS profile to the device. Likewise, the macOS app simply adds a new icon to your tray at the top-right and offers a toggle for turning on your NextDNS settings. Unsurprisingly, there&amp;rsquo;s no Manjaro Linux app, though the service offers a bevy of examples for configuring your DNS settings on Linux; you&amp;rsquo;re just stuck in the position of not being able to link the device to your NextDNS account if you happen to leave the home network. The only real problem I ran into was that I had configured Firefox to use DNS over HTTPS and forgotten about it; once I realized I needed an additional change beyond the OS DNS settings, everything was fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Operating this way, for the most part browsing the web was business as usual. Not &lt;em&gt;quite&lt;/em&gt; as many advertisements were being blocked as I would have expected with a browser extension enabled (more on that later), but on the whole the experience was still positive. What really surprised me, though, was the degree to which IoT devices are just an absolute dumpster fire; checking the metrics NextDNS generates showed that anywhere from 10 - 20% of my total DNS requests were being blocked, but nearly all of the top 10 blocked domains were based on under-the-hood queries being made by my devices phoning home rather than from actual advertising or tracking on web pages. All of this is nicely showcased with graphs in the NextDNS portal:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hugo.unusually.pink/images/next_dns_graphs-1024x403.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I expected the combined privacy invasion of my two Amazon Echo devices to be the worst offender, my single Roku device actually took the top spot by a significant margin. My top 10 blocked domains were:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;scribe.logs.roku.com - 17,226&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;device-metrics-us-2.amazon.com - 1,327&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;telemetry.dropbox.com - 1,121&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;giga.logs.roku.com - 1,095&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;device-metrics-us.amazon.com - 794&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;mads.amazon-adsystem.com - 717&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only non-device domain making the top 10 was from telemetry queries from Dropbox, the frequency of which was a bit disturbing. Roku really caught me off guard, though, with a single device making over 18,000 queries in just a couple of weeks. While using more domains, the two Echo devices made under 3,000 (which is still really bad!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a bit of an aside, I was curious if the devices would simply give up on whatever they were phoning home about and drop the information or if they were storing it locally to upload in a bulk at the first opportunity. I ended up disabling NextDNS on my router around 9 AM and checked on the traffic of both my Echo and my Roku, neither of which were being actively used at the time. The Roku showed zero data use since the time I had been streaming with it the night before:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hugo.unusually.pink/images/roku_wifi_small.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Echo, on the other hand, &lt;em&gt;immediately&lt;/em&gt; spiked with network usage to transmit who-knows-what. That&amp;rsquo;s nice and terrifying:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hugo.unusually.pink/images/echo_wifi_small.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other insight I found particularly interesting was just how deeply some of the biggest players on the web have their claws embedded across the Internet. For example, I don&amp;rsquo;t think any big Internet company is more evil than Facebook (though Google is trying hard), so I created a custom blocklist preventing &lt;code&gt;facebook.com&lt;/code&gt; from resolving. This prevents not just Facebook from loading but also some of Facebook&amp;rsquo;s other properties. For example, I hate and don&amp;rsquo;t use Instagram, but some friends occasionally send me posts from there. Instagram straight up won&amp;rsquo;t work if the main Facebook domain can&amp;rsquo;t be resolved. How gross is that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NextDNS operates by giving you 300,000 customized DNS queries per month where your policies and blacklists will be applied. After 300k queries, the service will act like a normal DNS resolver; while your devices won&amp;rsquo;t suddenly stop having functioning DNS, they won&amp;rsquo;t be benefiting from any of the blocks you might be expecting. For just a couple of dollars a month, you can get access to unlimited DNS queries, and subscribing for a year gives a month for free. I found staying on top of my query usage to be a bit confusing, though. As is shown in the screenshot above, my total number of queries for the month is provided, along with how many were blocked. I was averaging around 30,000 queries per day on this graph. I realized after the first week, though, that going into my account settings in the NextDNS portal gave me a &lt;em&gt;different&lt;/em&gt; metric on how many of my free queries had been used, and the data there was significantly lower. I ended my testing after using 280,000 queries according to the analytics graph, while my account settings showed that I had used just shy of 200,000 queries. I have no idea how those two numbers are different by 80,000 queries, especially when the two weeks of testing were done in the same month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I liked NextDNS, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t perfect. I had mentioned previously that the blocking wasn&amp;rsquo;t quite as good as what I&amp;rsquo;d expect from just relying on an extension when browsing the web. The main reason I could see for this is that some companies host trackers and advertising on the same domain they use for other, more legitimate purposes. For example, checking the &lt;a href=&#34;https://unusually.pink/safari-14/&#34;&gt;blocked tracking metrics within Safari 14&lt;/a&gt; showed that &lt;code&gt;bing.com&lt;/code&gt; was still high in the running. Naturally a service like NextDNS can&amp;rsquo;t just block the entire Bing domain without breaking plenty of services people actually might want to use. If &amp;ldquo;close enough&amp;rdquo; satisfies your needs for blocking ads then I could see NextDNS being a good solution. If you&amp;rsquo;re like me and want to block &lt;em&gt;everything&lt;/em&gt;, though, then you&amp;rsquo;re still going to need extensions in your browser, and that makes the value proposition for paying for something like NextDNS for unlimited queries a bit less tenable. What ultimately made the decision for me, though, was that I ended up running into a handful of issues with the app I used the most: the one on macOS. I&amp;rsquo;m willing to own that the issue might stem from my setup or my device, as my MacBook has 4 different VPN clients on it that I use (and frequently switch between) for work, the network stack on the device crashes with semi-regular frequency, and my home network is &lt;em&gt;significantly&lt;/em&gt; more convoluted than most. What I saw, though, was that my DNS queries would periodically just fail. Trying to &lt;code&gt;dig&lt;/code&gt; from the CLI would give me a timeout error, like the NextDNS servers weren&amp;rsquo;t responding. Pings to known IP addresses worked fine. If I turned off the NextDNS macOS application, then everything worked fine. Toggling it back on would result in broken queries again. Fixing this was a mixed back that ranged from completely closing and re-launching the app to disabling my wireless network in macOS all the way to rebooting my laptop. Between that problem and the fact that it wasn&amp;rsquo;t a standalone blocking solution for me, I opted to not dive into paying for the service, even though it has a lot of promise and &lt;em&gt;does&lt;/em&gt; keep my Roku from being the chattiest device possible.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Safari 14</title>
      <link>https://hugo.unusually.pink/safari-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hugo.unusually.pink/safari-14/</guid>
      <description>Last week the 10.15.7 update to macOS Catalina came with a nice surprise: Safari 14. I was caught off guard by this since I had assumed we wouldn&amp;rsquo;t see Safari 14 until Big Sur released later this year. It was also a nice surprise for me since Safari has become my browser of choice, not just on my iPhone and iPad, but also on my MacBook Pro. The big reason for this is that I do my best to avoid any Chromium-based browser.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Last week the 10.15.7 update to macOS Catalina came with a nice surprise: Safari 14. I was caught off guard by this since I had assumed we wouldn&amp;rsquo;t see Safari 14 until &lt;a href=&#34;https://unusually.pink/thoughts-on-apples-wwdc-2020/&#34;&gt;Big Sur released later this year&lt;/a&gt;. It was also a nice surprise for me since Safari has become my browser of choice, not just on my iPhone and iPad, but also on my MacBook Pro. The big reason for this is that I do my best to avoid any &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chromium_(web_browser)&#34;&gt;Chromium&lt;/a&gt;-based browser. Over the last few years we&amp;rsquo;ve seen diversity in browsers erode more and more as new browsers are built based on Chromium (e.g. Brave) while others abandon their own engines in favor of using Chromium (e.g. Opera and Edge.) I personally see this homogeneous browsing platform as being pretty bad for the Internet as a whole, as it opens up the possibility for web developers to focus all of their development on Chrome and ignore everything else. This leads to sites that &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; work on Chrome and that ignore web standards, just like we saw back in the day when much of the web was developed with only Internet Explorer 6 in mind. The difference now is the way the web has evolved into an entire platform. In 2004 the main issue was that sites developed just for IE 6 wouldn&amp;rsquo;t quite render properly on other browsers. In 2020, there are entire web apps that straight up won&amp;rsquo;t work on non-Chromium browsers. That&amp;rsquo;s something I can&amp;rsquo;t support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two &lt;em&gt;major&lt;/em&gt; browsers moving forward with different engines are Firefox (with Gecko) and Safari (with WebKit.) I was previously using Firefox on my laptops, but I became extremely concerned recently when &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mozilla.org/blog/2020/08/11/changing-world-changing-mozilla/&#34;&gt;Mozilla had massive layoffs and switched their mission to focus on revenue&lt;/a&gt;. I certainly understand that Mozilla needs to make money in order to continue making Firefox, but when a group lays off their entire incident response team, I don&amp;rsquo;t exactly feel warm and fuzzy inside about using the product. I still use it on my Linux installations, but on macOS I switched to Safari.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pleasant part about switching to Safari is that, for the most part, it&amp;rsquo;s been a very slick browser that I&amp;rsquo;ve enjoyed. While Safari 14 doesn&amp;rsquo;t do anything too Earth-shattering or even different from any other browsers, it does bring Apple&amp;rsquo;s offering up to parity with some of the major players. For example, Safari will now &lt;em&gt;finally&lt;/em&gt; display favicons for websites on tabs. How they&amp;rsquo;ve made it this far without supporting them I&amp;rsquo;ll never understand, but it immediately makes a huge difference in quickly finding the tab I want&amp;hellip; and I say this as a person who typically doesn&amp;rsquo;t have more than 10 tabs open at any given time. Tab addicts (you know who you are) will especially appreciate this when Safari starts stacking tabs on top of one another. As another update to tabs, Safari can now preview the content of a page when the mouse is hovered over a tab. This can also be useful for quickly finding the appropriate tab without actually having to switch to anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The big change, though, is how Safari communicates with the user about how it has helped protect against invasive tracking. This feature is &lt;em&gt;extremely&lt;/em&gt; similar to the Protections Dashboard in Firefox. There&amp;rsquo;s an icon to the left of the address bar that can be clicked at any given time to see a breakdown of trackers on the current page. Clicking will also allow me to see the specifics of what trackers are being blocked:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hugo.unusually.pink/images/safari_icon.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a bigger picture, I can also get an overall view of what&amp;rsquo;s been blocked in the past 30 days. I can see which sites were attempting to be the most invasive, and similar to the per-site rendering, each can be expanded to show which trackers they had embedded:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hugo.unusually.pink/images/safari_websites.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, I can click on the &lt;strong&gt;Trackers&lt;/strong&gt; heading in order to see a list of which trackers appear the most frequently across the sites I&amp;rsquo;m visiting. I can expand those listings to see which specific sites are hosting that tracker:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hugo.unusually.pink/images/safari_trackers.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t think it should come as a surprise to anyone that Google, Bing, and Facebook appear the most frequently after just a short period of testing. It&amp;rsquo;s also interesting to see trackers from both Facebook and Snapchat when I don&amp;rsquo;t use either of those &amp;ldquo;services&amp;rdquo;. It really shows you how pervasive they are across the Internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I can already hear the Apple-haters I know railing on the fact that Firefox already has this feature, in my opinion it&amp;rsquo;s nice to see Apple bringing their browser up to feature parity and offering a more transparent and secure browsing experience to people in a package that &lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; does not leverage Chromium but which &lt;em&gt;does&lt;/em&gt; have a support team behind it that&amp;rsquo;s more than a skeleton crew. Similarly, you &lt;em&gt;still&lt;/em&gt; don&amp;rsquo;t see anything like this today in Chrome or Edge, likely because the companies behind them both appear relatively high up in the tracker list.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back To Firefox</title>
      <link>https://hugo.unusually.pink/back-to-firefox/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hugo.unusually.pink/back-to-firefox/</guid>
      <description>Back in 2002, Firefox was the new hotness in the world of web browsers. Rising from the ashes of Netscape Navigator, the browser emerged as a true competitor to the horror of Internet Explorer. It offered competition with superior rendering and web compliance without the plethora of security issues plaguing Internet Explorer. While Firefox grew in popularity against Internet Explorer through the mid-2000’s, it eventually started to decline in the face of Google’s Chrome browser which took the browser market by storm with its release in the latter half of 2008.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Back in 2002, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/new/&#34;&gt;Firefox&lt;/a&gt; was the new hotness in the world of web browsers. Rising from the ashes of Netscape Navigator, the browser emerged as a true competitor to the horror of Internet Explorer. It offered competition with superior rendering and web compliance without the plethora of security issues plaguing Internet Explorer. While Firefox grew in popularity against Internet Explorer through the mid-2000’s, it eventually started to decline in the face of Google’s Chrome browser which took the browser market by storm with its release in the latter half of 2008. People appreciated the speed and efficiency of Google’s new browser, leaving Firefox to languish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the past decade, however, Firefox has undergone a slow yet steady transformation. Prior to the arrival of Chrome, Firefox was fixed on becoming the browser that could do &lt;em&gt;everything&lt;/em&gt;, for better or for worse. At the peak of its decline, Firefox was trying to be your web browser, your RSS reader (for the minority of users who had any clue what RSS was), and your IRC client (for the significantly smaller minority of users who had any clue what the hell IRC was), which overall made the browser require more resources for features that most users didn’t need or want, all the while the browser existed inside of a single, monolithic binary. By comparison, the Chrome browser broke each tab into a separate process so that complications with one tab wouldn’t impact the operation of the others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, though, the tables have begun to turn yet again. After achieving dominance in the browser market, Google has started to act like a GOP senator; they’re willing to sacrifice the good of their constituents (users) in favor of their own interests. For example, Google recognizes the impact of adblocking on its own business. As a result, they’ve &lt;a href=&#34;https://9to5google.com/2019/01/22/google-chrome-break-ad-blockers/&#34;&gt;proposed changes which would cripple adblockers&lt;/a&gt;. While they’ve bounced back and forth on this particular change since they first proposed it in January, they’ve continued to flirt with the idea; clearly Google doesn’t see blocking advertisements as a good thing. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.commitstrip.com/en/2015/09/28/scumbag-chrome/&#34;&gt;Chrome’s resource utilization continues to grow&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hugo.unusually.pink/images/BackToFirefox_commit_chrome.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time, &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mozilla.org/blog/2017/11/14/introducing-firefox-quantum/&#34;&gt;Firefox began a re-architecture of their browser which allowed for separate processes per tab&lt;/a&gt;. Since then, Mozilla has continued to refine their experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fastcompany.com/90428050/firefox-at-15-its-rise-fall-and-privacy-first-renaissance&#34;&gt;Firefox at 15: Its Rise, Fall, and Privacy-First Renaissance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://markosaric.com/firefox/&#34;&gt;Give Firefox a Chance for a Faster, Calmer, and Distraction-Free Internet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/70.0/releasenotes/&#34;&gt;Compositor improvements in Firefox for macOS that reduce power consumption, speed up page load by as much as 22 percent and reduce resource usage for video by by up to 37 percent&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mozilla.org/futurereleases/2019/11/04/restricting-notification-permission-prompts-in-firefox/&#34;&gt;Restricting Notification Permission Prompts in Firefox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theregister.co.uk/2019/11/21/ublock_origin_firefox_unblockable_tracker/&#34;&gt;Bad News: ‘Unblockable’ web trackers emerge. Good news: Firefox with uBlock Origin can stop it&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s a lot to unpack here, and if you want the full details just read all of the articles linked above. The tl;dr is that Firefox now opens a separate process per tab so that each tab can operate independently. Firefox has taken a stance on blocking trackers and other invasive behavior to fingerprint users. Firefox has improved performance on macOS &lt;em&gt;significantly&lt;/em&gt; over the past year. Do you &lt;strong&gt;fucking&lt;/strong&gt; hate the pop-up you get from what feels like every website where they want to give you notifications? Firefox is going to block those by default, and users have to actively opt into them. And as ISPs start to act even more shady in an attempt to circumvent user attempts to block tracking, Firefox is the browser empowering you to put the power over that tracking into your own hands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As time goes by, it becomes more and more clear to me that Firefox is the browser focused on user rights and privacy. While I like the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unusually.pink/blog/unusually-pink-impressions-acer-chromebook-315&#34;&gt;idea of Chromebooks and the simplicity they represent&lt;/a&gt;, they continue to become less attractive as I have to look at other options which don’t completely disregard my privacy. I’m feeling as though I’m better off getting a cheap laptop that I install my Linux distribution of choice on and use Firefox over opting for a Chromebook where Google will dictate my privacy choices on my behalf.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ProtonMail Bonus Storage</title>
      <link>https://hugo.unusually.pink/protonmail-bonus-storage/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hugo.unusually.pink/protonmail-bonus-storage/</guid>
      <description>Brandi and I both love ProtonMail; we like it so much that it got the honor of being a topic in our very first episode! The biggest draws for paying for a ProtonMail Plus account are:
  Support for a custom domain (e.g. @unusually.pink)
  5 GB of storage (up from 500 MB)
  5 email aliases
  The ability to send up to 1000 messages per day (up from 150)</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Brandi and I both love &lt;a href=&#34;https://protonmail.com/&#34;&gt;ProtonMail&lt;/a&gt;; we like it so much that it got the honor of being a topic in our &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unusually.pink/podcast/episode-1-game-of-thrones-and-protonmail&#34;&gt;very first episode&lt;/a&gt;! The biggest draws for paying for a ProtonMail Plus account are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Support for a custom domain (e.g. @unusually.pink)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5 GB of storage (up from 500 MB)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5 email aliases&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ability to send up to 1000 messages per day (up from 150)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of those are really nice perks! I have 3 different email aliases, one of which comes from a custom domain I added to the account. I don’t &lt;em&gt;personally&lt;/em&gt; use a lot of storage… for now. I do my best to keep my inbox empty. Note that I said “inbox”, though, rather than “mailbox.” I do have an archive folder where I throw messages that contain something important that might be useful later… though I’ve been trying my best to stop storing things like that in email and storing them in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unusually.pink/podcast/episode-8-playlists-and-privacy&#34;&gt;1Password&lt;/a&gt; instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I have plenty of real-estate left in my inbox, last week ProtonMail made it even more difficult for me to start bumping my head against the storage limit; they gave me additional storage for free! In an email with a subject of “We&amp;rsquo;re giving you extra storage to say thanks”, they described how they’ve added 10 &lt;strong&gt;million&lt;/strong&gt; users to the service over the past year, and how they’re working on a redesigned ProtonMail interface while also continuing to flesh out ProtonCalendar and ProtonDrive, none of which would have been possible without the support of paid accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a way to say thanks for your early support, we are giving everyone with an existing paid plan 5GB of extra storage for free. […] Because the bonus is to thank our longtime supporters, it only applies to users who upgraded before Nov. 10, 2019. This bonus storage upgrade is permanent as long as you continue your subscription with us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To me, this is super awesome. I like being able to support a service like ProtonMail, a service that I’ve come to rely on for my personal email. I’m also eagerly awaiting the arrival of ProtonCalendar and (especially) ProtonDrive, so it’s nice to see that my payments are helping to facilitate the creation of those services, too. While I don’t particularly need the 5 GB of storage right now, it could certainly come in handy later on down the road, especially considering I have no plans on letting my service lapse. I checked out the billing on my account and verified that it was added as a line item to my subscription for a $0 charge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, if you happen to be looking forward to the redesign of ProtonMail, I recently realized you can check it out over at: &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.protonmail.com&#34;&gt;beta.protonmail.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new interface is pretty slick, in my opinion, and I’m excited to see what other great things the future has in store for the service. Keep on encrypting, and stay pink!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
