<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>quarantine on Unusually Pink</title>
    <link>https://hugo.unusually.pink/tags/quarantine/</link>
    <description>Recent content in quarantine on Unusually Pink</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>2021</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hugo.unusually.pink/tags/quarantine/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Quarantine Time Script</title>
      <link>https://hugo.unusually.pink/posts/quarantine-time-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hugo.unusually.pink/posts/quarantine-time-script/</guid>
      <description>Are you tired of sitting at home wondering how many days you’ve been choosing to quarantine like a responsible adult? Me too! The number of times I’ve been in conversations or working on posts for blogs or social media and thought, “Wait, how long have I been at home now?” followed by wasting time doing rough calendar math in my head was enough that I finally burned some time this weekend putting together a script for it.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Are you tired of sitting at home wondering how many days you’ve been choosing to quarantine like a responsible adult? Me too! The number of times I’ve been in conversations or working on posts for blogs or social media and thought, “Wait, how long have I been at home now?” followed by wasting time doing rough calendar math in my head was enough that I finally burned some time this weekend putting together a script for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the interest of full disclosure, every time this has come up before I’ve done some very simple PowerShell to actually calculate this, at least once I passed the point where I couldn’t just think of it off the top of my head:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$now = Get-Date
$then = Get-Date -Date &amp;quot;2020/03/11&amp;quot;
($now - $then).Days
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Clearly this is extremely simple! I’ve found myself needing a few shell scripts, though, so I figured it would be a good opportunity to write this in Bash instead for a little exposure. The biggest key was to just figure out how the heck to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a date at a specific time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Subtract the dates.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;date-at-a-specific-time&#34;&gt;Date at a specific time&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was pretty easy after a quick &lt;a href=&#34;https://duckduckgo.com&#34;&gt;DuckDuckGo&lt;/a&gt; search. The &lt;code&gt;date&lt;/code&gt; utility includes a &lt;code&gt;-d&lt;/code&gt; parameter that allows me to give it a string that it’ll use as the date, just like &lt;code&gt;-Date&lt;/code&gt; does in PowerShell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;subtract-the-dates&#34;&gt;Subtract the dates&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second piece also ended up being &lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt; more straightforward than I expected. The &lt;code&gt;date&lt;/code&gt; utility similarly includes a few codes I can use to specify how I’d like the date to be formatted, including &lt;code&gt;%s&lt;/code&gt; which will give the date in seconds relative to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Unix_time&#34;&gt;Unix epoch time&lt;/a&gt;. I could get both dates in seconds, subtract the current date from when I started quarantine, and then convert the seconds to days. For those keeping score at home, there are 86,400 seconds in a day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an added bonus, &lt;code&gt;date&lt;/code&gt; returns the time in seconds just like everything else in the universe that isn’t Java-based. I’m looking at you, &lt;a href=&#34;https://failti.me/posts/groovy_prog/&#34;&gt;Groovy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;getting-a-starting-date&#34;&gt;Getting a starting date&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The easy method would’ve been to hard-code the date when I started quarantine and leave it at that. To make it a little more extensible, though, I instead opted to pass the date as a parameter. Given that people can pass anything as a parameter, though, I put together a regex to enforce the YYYY/MM/DD format on whatever is typed. That being said, I still included an additional check after parsing the starting date regardless since it would still be possible to specify a date that matches the regex but that isn’t real (e.g. 2020/02/31.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;code&#34;&gt;Code&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the code in all of its janky glory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s extremely simple, but it was a fun little learning experience to kill some time on a weekend when I was sitting at home… continuing to quarantine…&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
