<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>keyboard on Unusually Pink</title>
    <link>https://hugo.unusually.pink/tags/keyboard/</link>
    <description>Recent content in keyboard on Unusually Pink</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>2021</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hugo.unusually.pink/tags/keyboard/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Keychron K2 V2</title>
      <link>https://hugo.unusually.pink/posts/keychron-k2-v2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hugo.unusually.pink/posts/keychron-k2-v2/</guid>
      <description>I recently ran into a problem with my keyboard at home, a Logitech K350, AKA a Logitech Wave; the O key stopped reliably working. Sometimes it would work fine, sometimes it would work only when pressed with an excessive amount of force no touch-typist could reliably muster (at which point the key would clank down awkwardly), and sometimes it just wouldn&amp;rsquo;t work at all. Unsurprisingly, the letter O is one that I use with a good bit of regularly, so this presented a problem.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;I recently ran into a problem with my keyboard at home, a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.logitech.com/en-us/product/wireless-keyboard-k350?crid=27&#34;&gt;Logitech K350&lt;/a&gt;, AKA a Logitech Wave; the O key stopped reliably working. Sometimes it would work fine, sometimes it would work only when pressed with an excessive amount of force no touch-typist could reliably muster (at which point the key would clank down awkwardly), and sometimes it just wouldn&amp;rsquo;t work at all. Unsurprisingly, the letter O is one that I use with a good bit of regularly, so this presented a problem. I decided to go ahead and order a new keyboard and started sizing up my options. I didn&amp;rsquo;t do much research, though, before &lt;a href=&#34;http://craftbrewgeek.com&#34;&gt;Craft Brew Geek&lt;/a&gt; recommended the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.keychron.com/products/keychron-k2-wireless-mechanical-keyboard?variant=31063869751385&#34;&gt;Keychron K2 V2&lt;/a&gt;. He hadn&amp;rsquo;t used one but had seen positive feedback on it from some highly respected people (MKBHD, anyone?), and I think he wanted someone he knew to try it out before he decided if he should get one. I was happy to oblige after doing a little research of my own and seeing almost exclusively positive feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing worth noting is that this is &lt;strong&gt;Version 2&lt;/strong&gt;. That&amp;rsquo;s important because you can find the first version floating around on the cheap. It&amp;rsquo;s important to not mix them up, though; the initial offering of the K2 was fraught with problems that V2 tackles nicely. V2 comes in a few different variants based on the lighting and body style that you want, along with how much you want to pay. I went for the variant with RGB lighting (cool but not that important) and an aluminum frame (extremely important.) I had read online that the keyboard sans frame was light to a detriment without enough weight to properly hold it down on the desk. I did pay more for the frame, but with the build and the features, this is still relatively cheap in the world of mechanical keyboards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/keychron_1.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The K2 is a TKL (tenkeyless) keyboard, meaning that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a number pad. Unlike many other TKL models, though, it has 84 keys because it still features dedicated arrow keys &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; dedicated Home, End, Page Up, and Page Down keys. Memorizing another function layer for keyboards that don&amp;rsquo;t feature dedicated keys like this isn&amp;rsquo;t the end of the world, but I view having them as a significant quality of life bonus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bigger quality of life bonus, though, falls to the keycaps. The K2 features macOS-based keycaps. It comes with replacement keycaps for Windows in case you use an &lt;strong&gt;that&lt;/strong&gt; operating system and need to swap Option for Windows and Command for Alt. This is pretty common among mechanical keyboards, though it&amp;rsquo;s worth mentioning that the K2 has a dedicated physical toggle to control if it&amp;rsquo;s operating in macOS or Windows mode; most keyboards use a software function for that. The bigger difference, though, is in the function row. Along with having the standard F1 - F12 markings, the keycaps also show the corresponding macOS function. As a macOS user, I can&amp;rsquo;t stress how helpful it is to have the keycaps appropriately marked so that I know which key is going to turn up my volume and which one will launch Exposé, for example. As another quality of life bonus, the K2 also features a dedicated screenshot key that&amp;rsquo;s the equivalent of hitting Command + Shift + 4 on macOS. That&amp;rsquo;s extremely cool in my opinion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On top of all of this, Keychron also provides orange keycaps that you can opt to use on Escape and on the key which controls the backlighting. I thought they looked snazzy and decided to use them, though you can swap to more standard keys if you wish. I was also a pleasant surprised that a wire keycap puller was included rather than one of the cheaper plastic ones that&amp;rsquo;s all but guaranteed to scratch up your keycaps. While there are plenty of dedicated keys, there&amp;rsquo;s even more functionality of the K2 tucked behind key combinations in conjunction with the Function key. The included instruction booklet clearly highlights all of these, and it was a matter of minutes to get everything configured the way I wanted it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/keychron_2.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lighting in my photo isn&amp;rsquo;t great, but rest assured that you can eschew RGB in favor of locking the lights in to a nice shade of pink.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m the type of person who rarely uses any type of adjustable riser on my keyboards, and this was one of the biggest flaws with the original take on the K2; it was almost completely flat. V2 of the K2 has a nice, gentle slope that&amp;rsquo;s pretty much exactly where I want it to be. For those who want more of an angle, there are 2 sets of adjustable feet on the bottom. The official website only calls out the difference of 9 degrees, which has to be for the more drastic of the pairs. I&amp;rsquo;d guess the other is 4 degrees, but I wasn&amp;rsquo;t about to dig up a protractor to find out. The default slope makes for a &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; nice typing experience for me, so I haven&amp;rsquo;t even worried about the feet beyond confirming that they exist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Typing on the K2 is an overall pleasant experience with one minor issue I&amp;rsquo;ll touch on later. Keychron offers three choices of switch: Gateron Blues, Browns, and Reds. This was my only real hesitance in deciding to buy the keyboard since I&amp;rsquo;ve always been a stickler for Cherry switches. I opted for the Gateron Browns even though I would prefer Blues simply because I&amp;rsquo;m using this keyboard for work, and I don&amp;rsquo;t need my typing to be any louder than it already is while I&amp;rsquo;m thundering out 120 WPM on calls. While the Gateron Browns don&amp;rsquo;t feel &lt;em&gt;quite&lt;/em&gt; as nice as Cherry Browns in my opinion, they&amp;rsquo;re &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; close. Both Cherry and Gateron Browns even actuate at the same 55 grams. I feel good that my concern over the switches wasn&amp;rsquo;t warranted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The K2 can connect to devices either via Bluetooth or USB-C. I&amp;rsquo;ll likely never use it via Bluetooth if my Plum Nano serves as any indication, so USB-C will be my go-to method. This is where one of the two issues I have with the K2 V2 comes into play. The USB-C port is on the &lt;em&gt;left&lt;/em&gt; side of the keyboard rather than the back, which you can see in the top image. The provided USB-C cable accounts for this by connecting at a right-angle so that it can immediately be directed behind the board, and this seems to work fine&amp;hellip; as long as I have &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; cable. If I&amp;rsquo;m ever forced to use a different, more standard cable, that&amp;rsquo;s going to make for a janky setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other issue I have with the K2 V2 I hesitate to even really call an &amp;ldquo;issue&amp;rdquo;; it&amp;rsquo;s more something I need to adjust to a little bit as a touch-typist. The right Shift key is a little bit shorter than it would be on a standard ANSI QWERTY keyboard. This is done to allow for the dedicated arrow keys. I would say that 98% of the time (yes, I&amp;rsquo;m completely making up this number), it&amp;rsquo;s not an issue. The other 2% of the time, I accidentally extend my pinky just a bit too far and hit the up arrow or awkwardly catch the edge of the Shift key. It&amp;rsquo;s not a huge ordeal, and as someone who has periodically dealt with using ISO keyboards before I know I&amp;rsquo;ll adjust quickly; it feels worth mentioning, though. It&amp;rsquo;s also good practice for me since my &lt;a href=&#34;https://starlabs.systems/pages/lite-mk-iii&#34;&gt;Starlabs Lite Mark III&lt;/a&gt; that&amp;rsquo;s currently sitting in customs in the UK has a much shorter right Shift key for the exact same reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/starlabs_lite_mk3.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the whole, I&amp;rsquo;ve been &lt;em&gt;extremely&lt;/em&gt; pleased with the K2 V2 so far. I&amp;rsquo;ve used it for a little over a week, generally spending 9 - 14 hours a day on it between work, training, and personal projects. It&amp;rsquo;s a treat to type on, the functionality is nice without being overkill, and I think the size really hits the sweet spot between not taking over my desk and not forcing me to re-adjust it every 5 lines of code because it&amp;rsquo;s constantly moving; the aluminum frame that I opted for undoubtedly helps it in that regard. I really do think that for $90 USD you could do significantly worse, and the K2 V2 has features and a build quality I&amp;rsquo;d be expecting from a mechanical keyboard in the $120 - $150 USD price range. I think this is a great keyboard for anyone, but especially if you&amp;rsquo;re a macOS user in the market for a mechanical keyboard, the Keychron K2 V2 would be a smart place to start.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
