<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>pinebook-pro on Unusually Pink</title>
    <link>https://hugo.unusually.pink/tags/pinebook-pro/</link>
    <description>Recent content in pinebook-pro on Unusually Pink</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>2021</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hugo.unusually.pink/tags/pinebook-pro/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Swapfile Fix on Manjaro Linux Pinebook Pro</title>
      <link>https://hugo.unusually.pink/swapfile-fix-on-manjaro-linux-pinebook-pro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hugo.unusually.pink/swapfile-fix-on-manjaro-linux-pinebook-pro/</guid>
      <description>I wrote about a month ago of an update on my Pinebook Pro after switching to Manjaro Linux. I continue to make heavy use of my Pinebook Pro while I&amp;rsquo;m still social distancing and staying at home, giving me lots of time to work on personal projects without much else to do.
Today I ran into an interesting issue, though, after applying a round of updates. I mentioned in my last Pinebook Pro post about going through the process of creating a swapfile using the directions from the Manjaro wiki so that I could hibernate the machine and get much better battery life.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;I wrote about a month ago of an update &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unusually.pink/blog/unusually-pink-impressions-pinebook-pro&#34;&gt;on my Pinebook Pro&lt;/a&gt; after &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unusually.pink/blog/pinebook-pro-follow-up-manjaro-linux&#34;&gt;switching to Manjaro Linux&lt;/a&gt;. I continue to make heavy use of my Pinebook Pro while I&amp;rsquo;m still social distancing and staying at home, giving me lots of time to work on personal projects without much else to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today I ran into an interesting issue, though, after applying a round of updates. I mentioned in my last Pinebook Pro post about going through the process of creating a swapfile using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.manjaro.org/index.php?title=Swap#Using_a_Swapfile&#34;&gt;directions from the Manjaro wiki&lt;/a&gt; so that I could hibernate the machine and get &lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt; better battery life. I literally just opened the device back up, though, and saw a familiar message that there wasn&amp;rsquo;t enough swap space to successfully hibernate the machine, leaving me with about 20% less battery life than I had been expecting. Running &lt;code&gt;htop&lt;/code&gt; quickly showed me that my swap space was back to nothing. Weird.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following the instructions, my swapfile is literally called &lt;strong&gt;swapfile&lt;/strong&gt; on the root of the filesystem. I verified it was still in place with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;ll / | grep swap
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the file still in place, I ran through the instructions again. These ones were both successful:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo mkswap /swapfile
sudo chmod u=rw,go= /swapfile
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;I got an error when running this, though:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo swapon /swappfile
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;This told me:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;swapon: /swapfile: swapon failed: Invalid argument&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Weird. I verified that I still had my swapfile entry in &lt;code&gt;/etc/fstab&lt;/code&gt; to assign the swapfile on boot by running:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo cat /etc/fstab
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;I tried running the &lt;code&gt;swapon&lt;/code&gt; command a different way to have it apply everything in the &lt;code&gt;fstab&lt;/code&gt; file:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo swapon -a
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;This gave me another &amp;ldquo;Invalid argument&amp;rdquo; error still referencing &amp;ldquo;/swapfile&amp;rdquo;. At this point, I took to the Internet. After a couple of searches, I stumbled across &lt;a href=&#34;https://unix.stackexchange.com/questions/294600/i-cant-enable-swap-space-on-centos-7&#34;&gt;a matching Stack Exchange question&lt;/a&gt;. The top answer claims that the issue is the initial &lt;code&gt;fallocate&lt;/code&gt; command used to create the file (the same command used in the Manjaro wiki) doesn&amp;rsquo;t physically allocate the 4 GB on the storage for speed, but that&amp;rsquo;s apparently problematic for &lt;code&gt;swapon&lt;/code&gt;. Following that answer, I ran a &lt;code&gt;dd&lt;/code&gt; command to replace my swapfile with something physically allocated:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo dd if=/dev/zero of=/swapfile count=4096 bs=1MiB
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;This takes a few moments to run, especially on the eMMC storage of the Pinebook Pro. Once it completed, though, I repeated the other commands and verified they were all successful. Sure enough, running &lt;code&gt;htop&lt;/code&gt; once again shows my 4 GB of allocated swap space.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pinebook Pro Follow-up: Manjaro Linux</title>
      <link>https://hugo.unusually.pink/pinebook-pro-follow-up-manjaro-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hugo.unusually.pink/pinebook-pro-follow-up-manjaro-linux/</guid>
      <description>I had written in early February about my Pinebook Pro laptop after roughly a month of using it. Now that significantly more time has passed, time which I&amp;rsquo;ve almost exclusively spent at home due to nationwide stay-at-home orders and social distancing, I figure I&amp;rsquo;d share some of my thoughts on the laptop I raved about initially, and more specifically what I&amp;rsquo;ve done with the operating system.
The OS If you read my original post then you may recall that I was debating swapping the default Debian operating system for something different.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;I had &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unusually.pink/blog/unusually-pink-impressions-pinebook-pro&#34;&gt;written in early February about my Pinebook Pro laptop&lt;/a&gt; after roughly a month of using it. Now that significantly more time has passed, time which I&amp;rsquo;ve almost exclusively spent at home due to nationwide stay-at-home orders and social distancing, I figure I&amp;rsquo;d share some of my thoughts on the laptop I raved about initially, and more specifically what I&amp;rsquo;ve done with the operating system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-os&#34;&gt;The OS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you read my original post then you may recall that I was debating swapping the default Debian operating system for something different. While I mentioned NetBSD in the post I ended up installing &lt;a href=&#34;https://manjaro.org/&#34;&gt;Manjaro Linux&lt;/a&gt; instead. Why? There are a few reasons to consider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest reasons why swapping the OS can be considered important is that there are some issues with the Debian build that came on my device. It&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mrfixit2001/debian_desktop&#34;&gt;custom setup put together by a community member&lt;/a&gt;. It looks incredible, but that comes at a cost; the highly customized environment means that many things in it &lt;em&gt;cannot&lt;/em&gt; be updated; this includes both Chromium and Firefox. Running outdated browsers isn&amp;rsquo;t exactly cool, and I wasn&amp;rsquo;t too keen on having to compile Firefox from source every time there was a new release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand many of the community members seemed to really love Manjaro Linux, so I figured I&amp;rsquo;d gvie it a shot. Along with people in the Pinebook community raving about it, it&amp;rsquo;s also been hovering near the top of &lt;a href=&#34;https://distrowatch.com/&#34;&gt;Distrowatch&lt;/a&gt; for a while now. In fact it was &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pine64.org/2020/03/15/march-update-manjaro-on-pinebook-pro-pinephone-software/&#34;&gt;announced in March&lt;/a&gt; that Manjaro was going to be the default OS for new Pinebook Pro devices, which is pretty slick! They&amp;rsquo;re shipping with the KDE variant, though, and while I&amp;rsquo;ve read about people having a good experience with that, I personaly prefer the more lightweight &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.xfce.org/&#34;&gt;XFCE desktop&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s lighter, simpler, and overall I feel like it&amp;rsquo;s a better fit for the Pinebook Pro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;getting-the-os&#34;&gt;Getting The OS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As something of a noob when it comes to working with open source SoC setups like a Rock64 or Raspberry Pi, I struggled a little with figuring out exactly how to install a new OS on the Pinebook Pro. The first thing I figured out is that, currently, you cannot boot the Pinebook Pro from USB. I made a few bootable flash drives like I would&amp;rsquo;ve historically used when installing Linux on a more traditional device without success. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.pine64.org/index.php/Pinebook_Pro&#34;&gt;Pinebook Pro wiki&lt;/a&gt; seems to contradict itself on this point, saying:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Pinebook Pro is capable of booting from eMMC, USB 2.0, USB 3.0, or an SD card. It cannot boot from USB-C. The boot order of the hard-coded ROM of its RK3399 SoC is: SPI NOR, eMMC, SD, USB OTG.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then in the very next paragraph it says:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this time, the Pinebook Pro ships with a Debian + MATE build with uboot on the eMMC. Its boot order is: SD, then eMMC. Booting off USB storage is not currently available, but will be in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t put it past myself to just be misunderstanding something, though, so your mileage may vary. As you might be able to guess from the quotes shared above, I just ordred a cheap microSD card online and used that for the OS installation; everything worked great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Manjaro specifically, the best way to get the proper image is to go to the forum announcement for the latest version, like &lt;a href=&#34;https://forum.manjaro.org/t/manjaro-arm-20-04-released/133374&#34;&gt;this one for the 20.04 release&lt;/a&gt;. There you can select the appropriate link for your Pinebook Pro and for your preferred desktop environment. Once you select that, you&amp;rsquo;ll be taken to another page &lt;a href=&#34;https://osdn.net/projects/manjaro-arm/storage/pbpro/xfce/20.04/&#34;&gt;like this one listing all of the images files you can download for that version and desktop environment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be aware that if you want to install Manjaro &lt;strong&gt;directly on the laptop&lt;/strong&gt;, be sure to grab the image file with &amp;ldquo;emmc-installer&amp;rdquo; in the file name! This is the image designed to be flashed onto the internal eMMC storage of the Pinebook Pro! Grabbing the image without this will simply create a microSD card that will run the OS. This isn&amp;rsquo;t bad if you&amp;rsquo;d like to try out Manjaro while leaving the Debian installation on your eMMC, but I wanted to go all-in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;preparing-your-media&#34;&gt;Preparing Your Media&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To prepare the media, you can use basically any option that&amp;rsquo;ll allow you to flash the .img file you downloaded onto the microSD card. You can be old-school and use &lt;code&gt;dd&lt;/code&gt; from the command line, but I went easy mode and used &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.balena.io/etcher/&#34;&gt;balenaEtcher&lt;/a&gt; instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-rest&#34;&gt;The Rest&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The boot order on the Pinebook Pro automatically has the microSD card slot above the eMMC, so once you have a microSD card prepared just insert it into the Pinebook Pro, boot the device, and follow the prompts; it&amp;rsquo;s honestly pretty simple to install. The only catch is a known bug with the 20.04 release where you have to hit &lt;code&gt;Esc&lt;/code&gt; while looking at the Manjaro logo after booting from the microSD card before it&amp;rsquo;ll move forward; as a known bug I would imagine this won&amp;rsquo;t be relevant for future releases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the Manjaro logo has been present for about 15 seconds, press ESC (this is a bug, we know).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once it&amp;rsquo;s all done, you boot to this gorgeous view!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hugo.unusually.pink/images/PinebookProFollow-upManjaroLinux_manjaro_pbp_xfce.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;caveats&#34;&gt;Caveats&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the most part, Manjaro works like a complete dream, and I&amp;rsquo;ve been extremely happy with it. There are just a couple of caveats that might be worth mentioning, though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;initial-update&#34;&gt;Initial Update&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, there was a bug when running the initial software update on the factory image. First I had to figure out &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; to update it, but after some quick DuckDuckGo-fu (since I&amp;rsquo;ve really only used Debian-based flavors of Linux before) I figured I could update Manjaro via:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34; data-lang=&#34;shell&#34;&gt;sudo pacman -Syyu
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Note that you can aslo just click the little shield icon in the bottom-right corner of the screen. Regardless of method, though, immediately after booting my new OS I would get the following error when attempting to update:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conflicting files: nss /usr/lib/p11-kit-trust.so already exists in filesystem&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another benefit to choosing Manjaro is that it has an extremely active community, so it&amp;rsquo;s easy to search on errors like this and get solutions! I quickly found a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NexyTfO0iuY&#34;&gt;YouTube video&lt;/a&gt; covering this error and providing the solution:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34; data-lang=&#34;shell&#34;&gt;sudo pacman -Syyu --overwrite /usr/lib*/p11-kit-trust.so
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;After that initial update succeeded I&amp;rsquo;ve been able to perform subsequent updates without needing the &lt;code&gt;--overwrite&lt;/code&gt; parameter. Updating via the GUI also works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;swap&#34;&gt;Swap&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s entirely possible I just made a mistake in my installation, but I eventually realized that I didn&amp;rsquo;t have a swap partition or file. I realized this because I noticed that the battery drain while under suspend was a bit severe; I was losing roughly 6% of my battery per hour. This meant that leaving the device on suspend for a day would completely drain a full battery. I changed my XFCE setting so that when closing the lid of the device it would hibernate. This gave me an error, though, that I didn&amp;rsquo;t have enough swap space to hibernate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I checked the output of &lt;code&gt;htop&lt;/code&gt; and realized that I didn&amp;rsquo;t have enough space because I didn&amp;rsquo;t have &lt;strong&gt;any&lt;/strong&gt; swap. Luckily for me, the Manjaro folks have a wiki page dedicated to exactly this; I ended up following the steps to &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.manjaro.org/index.php?title=Swap#Using_a_Swapfile&#34;&gt;create a swapfile rather than adjusting my partitions to have a swap partition&lt;/a&gt;. Since there are 4 GB of RAM in the Pinebook Pro, I ended up creating a 4 GB swap file. Once it&amp;rsquo;s created you can verify it by looking at &lt;code&gt;htop&lt;/code&gt; or running &lt;code&gt;swapon&lt;/code&gt;. If you&amp;rsquo;re concerned about the amount of storage on the eMMC, you can see how much you&amp;rsquo;re using via:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34; data-lang=&#34;shell&#34;&gt;df -H | grep /$
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;typing-and-the-touchpad&#34;&gt;Typing and the Touchpad&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed on occasion is that typing does not disable the touchpad on the laptop, meaning that it&amp;rsquo;s easy for your hand to accidentally brush it, clicking somewhere else and causing a bit of havoc on whatever it is you&amp;rsquo;re trying to do. I&amp;rsquo;ve accidentally done it once just while working on this article. I&amp;rsquo;ve not found a solution for this yet (I&amp;rsquo;ll update the post if I do), but it hasn&amp;rsquo;t been a big deal for me. It&amp;rsquo;s just something to be mindful about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-end&#34;&gt;The End&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the whole, I&amp;rsquo;m &lt;em&gt;extremely&lt;/em&gt; pleased with my switch to Manjaro. If you&amp;rsquo;re running a Pinebook Pro with the original Debian build, I&amp;rsquo;d highly recommend giving Manjaro a shot; it honestly feels like a whole new device afterward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unusually.pink/blog/its-all-about-open-source&#34;&gt;open source love alive&lt;/a&gt;, and stay pink!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unusually Pink Impressions: Pinebook Pro</title>
      <link>https://hugo.unusually.pink/unusually-pink-impressions-pinebook-pro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hugo.unusually.pink/unusually-pink-impressions-pinebook-pro/</guid>
      <description>In my last post about not using Chrome OS, I neglected to get into what I was replacing my Chromebooks with since that seemed like a lengthy post in its own right. As the title gave away, my switch went to the Pinebook Pro from Pine 64. I had been interested in the original $99 USD Pinebook when that came out a couple of years ago, but it seemed a bit too basic for what I wnanted.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;In my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unusually.pink/blog/rip-chrome-os&#34;&gt;last post about not using Chrome OS&lt;/a&gt;, I neglected to get into &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; I was replacing my Chromebooks with since that seemed like a lengthy post in its own right. As the title gave away, my switch went to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pine64.org/pinebook-pro/&#34;&gt;Pinebook Pro&lt;/a&gt; from Pine 64. I had been interested in the original $99 USD Pinebook when that came out a couple of years ago, but it seemed a bit &lt;strong&gt;too&lt;/strong&gt; basic for what I wnanted. The Pinebook Pro seemed to offer a more compelling experience for $199. The description on the site even seemed to match exactly what I was wanting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Pinebook Pro is meant to deliver solid day-to-day Linux or *BSD experience and to be a compelling alternative to mid-ranged Chromebooks that people convert into Linux laptops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to have to deal with Windows, nor was I wanting to go through a lot of research to find a Windows laptop or Chromebook that I could then convert to a Linux laptop. The Pinebook Pro seemed to take care of this for me while also giving me an outlet to support a great company doing some awesome things for the open source community. I was a little leery on what kind of performance I would get out of an ARM processor and if I would hit any compatibility issues, but so far everything has been buttery smooth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;hardware&#34;&gt;Hardware&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hardware is absurdly nice for a $199 device. The Magnesium alloy body just feels solid and sturdy. It has enough heft to make the laptop feel more expensive than it is without being a pain to carry around. It also just looks sleek given that there&amp;rsquo;s literally nothing on the top, not even branding. It&amp;rsquo;s a spotless, black surface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hugo.unusually.pink/images/UnusuallyPinkImpressionsPinebookPro_IMG_0051.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t normally leave my laptops completely unemblazoned, so I just ordered some stickers for it earlier today. I&amp;rsquo;ll share pictures on the socials once those are on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under the hood is the a screen that you almost feel has no business being on a $200 machine. It&amp;rsquo;s a 14&amp;quot; 1080p IPS display that looks absolutely gorgeous. Everything from typing away in a Terminal or blog post to watching videos looks terrific on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The keyboard is also surprisingly nice. It&amp;rsquo;s spacious, and the keys have an impressive amount of travel to them. Given that these days I rarely use my personal laptop unless I&amp;rsquo;m doing a lot of typing where I need a physical keyboard, the keys on the Pinebook Pro really deliver. Rarely do I even bother to sit at a desk and connect an external keyboard; the default experience is just fine. The keys have good tactile feedback to go along with that travel distance, so you&amp;rsquo;re never left doubting if you pressed a particular key or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hugo.unusually.pink/images/UnusuallyPinkImpressionsPinebookPro_IMG_0052.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may notice that the keyboard also features literally the only external branding other than the sticker on the bottom of the device. The super key has a Pine 64 logo on it, which is a nice, subtle touch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hugo.unusually.pink/images/UnusuallyPinkImpressionsPinebookPro_IMG_0050.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trackpad is unfortunately not quite as solid as the keyboard. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel particular sensitive and the pointer come across as &amp;ldquo;floaty&amp;rdquo;. Hitting big buttons is fine, but it can be annoying to make more precise movements like grabbing the corner of an application to resize it. If I&amp;rsquo;m using the device for something that&amp;rsquo;s mouse-intensive, I&amp;rsquo;ll typically reach for my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.logitech.com/en-us/product/mx-ergo-wireless-trackball-mouse&#34;&gt;Logitech MX Ergo trackball&lt;/a&gt;, but the trackpad is still workable in a pinch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The speakers aren&amp;rsquo;t bad, but they&amp;rsquo;re about what you expect from laptop speakers. Only Apple seems to posess the voodoo required to make great sounding laptop speakers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The device comes with a barrel jack charger. You can also charge it via the USB-C port as well, which is what I much more commonly do with the charger which came with my Acer Chromebook 315.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;software&#34;&gt;Software&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the device is booted, you&amp;rsquo;ll be using a customized Debian Linux version that comes from the factory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Distributor ID:    Debian
Description:    Debian GNU/Linux 9.12 (stretch)
Release:    9.12
Codename:    stretch&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being that it&amp;rsquo;s Debian Linux, you can do pretty much anything else that you&amp;rsquo;d expect with Debian Linux&amp;hellip; and that&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;awesome&lt;/strong&gt;. There are some limitations in the packages simply regarding what software supports ARM and which software does not, but everything I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to do so far has worked fine. That being said, I&amp;rsquo;m mainly still using the device very similar to a Chromebook; I want a web browser and a Terminal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hugo.unusually.pink/images/UnusuallyPinkImpressionsPinebookPro_Screenshotat2020-02-0915-17-28.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ARM processor and included 4 GB of RAM do an excellent job of keeping everything snappy. It&amp;rsquo;ll occasionally take a little bit longer to launch a heavier application, but otherwise it&amp;rsquo;s often easy to forget that I&amp;rsquo;m on a $200 Linux laptop and not my $2000 MacBook Pro for work. The 64 GB of local storage is a nice change from most Chromebooks as well. Rarely is my system ever bumping its head against the hardware, even when I&amp;rsquo;m streaming music and have a bunch of browser tabs open.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hugo.unusually.pink/images/UnusuallyPinkImpressionsPinebookPro_image-asset.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Need to install something new? Just &lt;code&gt;sudo apt install package-name&lt;/code&gt; and you&amp;rsquo;re good to go! That being said, just like normal with Debian you get a wide array of software out of the box&amp;hellip; all of which still only amounts to a 5 GB footprint in what comes from the factory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;to-do&#34;&gt;To Do&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a few things to do out of the box when you get a Pinebook Pro; I would &lt;strong&gt;highly&lt;/strong&gt; recommend reading &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.pine64.org/index.php/Pinebook_Pro&#34;&gt;the wiki page&lt;/a&gt; about the device so you know what those are instead of trying to do things on your own. For example, there&amp;rsquo;s no traditional &amp;ldquo;first run&amp;rdquo; experience to set things up given that this is a highly customized Debian image. Instead, you log in with the default credentials &lt;code&gt;rock/rock&lt;/code&gt; to get things started. It&amp;rsquo;s highly recommended you &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.pine64.org/index.php/Pinebook_Pro#Initial_user_changes.2C_password.2C_name.2C_etc&#34;&gt;rename the &lt;code&gt;rock&lt;/code&gt; account&lt;/a&gt; if you want to keep all of the customizations. If you make a brand new account, which is totally an option if you want to go that route, you&amp;rsquo;ll end up in a session that looks much more like a traditional Debian installation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the Wiki does an awesome job of covering what to do when you get the device, my recommendations are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Disable the root account.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo passwd -l root&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install and enable &lt;code&gt;ufw&lt;/code&gt; for a firewall.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo apt install ufw&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo ufw enable&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run the &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.pine64.org/index.php/Pinebook_Pro#Default_Debian_MATE_Desktop_Quick_Start&#34;&gt;system update script&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update the rest of the system.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo apt update &amp;amp;&amp;amp; sudo apt upgrade&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update the &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.pine64.org/index.php/Pinebook_Pro#Trackpad&#34;&gt;keyboard and trackpad firmware&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check your keyboard version to make sure it&amp;rsquo;s on the correct language. Mine came as UK English.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If that&amp;rsquo;s not correct, type &lt;code&gt;keyboard&lt;/code&gt; at the menu launcher, open the keyboard preferences, go to the &lt;code&gt;Layouts&lt;/code&gt; tab, and select the apporpriate layout.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Verify if your timezone is correct or needs to be updated.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;tzselect&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, all of this assumes you&amp;rsquo;re going to keep rolling with the factory Debian image. There&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.pine64.org/index.php/Pinebook_Pro_Software_Release&#34;&gt;wide array of operating systems you can choose from&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m personally super tempted to give the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.armbsd.org/arm/&#34;&gt;NetBSD image&lt;/a&gt; a shot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;wrap-up&#34;&gt;Wrap Up&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, I&amp;rsquo;m &lt;em&gt;extremely&lt;/em&gt; pleased with the Pinebook Pro so far. They&amp;rsquo;ve got a great community, and I&amp;rsquo;ve spent a little time so far keeping tabs on their IRC server and Discord. If you can&amp;rsquo;t find something in particular on the wiki (which would be surprising; it&amp;rsquo;s extremely well-maintained), the helpful folks on IRC can likely assist. If you&amp;rsquo;re a fan of budget laptops but want to move away from Chrome OS or Windows, the Pinebook Pro seems like a great option if you feel comfortable with Linux.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
