<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>firefox on Unusually Pink</title>
    <link>https://hugo.unusually.pink/tags/firefox/</link>
    <description>Recent content in firefox on Unusually Pink</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>2021</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hugo.unusually.pink/tags/firefox/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Switching To Brave</title>
      <link>https://hugo.unusually.pink/switching-to-brave/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hugo.unusually.pink/switching-to-brave/</guid>
      <description>I spend the majority of my computing time on the MacBook Pro that I use for work. For a very long time, I&amp;rsquo;ve used Safari as my main browser on it. Unsurprisingly, Safari integrates very nicely with the rest of macOS, and I honestly just really like it as a browser. Lately, though, I&amp;rsquo;ve been experiencing increased frustration with Safari and the web as a whole that has had me looking for alternatives.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;I spend the majority of my computing time on the MacBook Pro that I use for work. For a very long time, I&amp;rsquo;ve used Safari as my main browser on it. Unsurprisingly, Safari integrates very nicely with the rest of macOS, and I honestly just really like it as a browser. Lately, though, I&amp;rsquo;ve been experiencing increased frustration with Safari and the web as a whole that has had me looking for alternatives. I&amp;rsquo;ll preface this entire post by saying that I could easily work around most of my problems by doing what I&amp;rsquo;ve historically done and using Safari for most things and a different browser for the remainder that don&amp;rsquo;t work well in Safari, but I really dislike having multiple browsers open. While I&amp;rsquo;m not nearly as guilty as most of my colleagues about having an egregious number of tabs open, it&amp;rsquo;s still a pain to deal with swapping between browser windows and finding what site is open where.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;issues&#34;&gt;Issues&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main issue with Safari is compatibility. As someone who is (mercifully) not a web developer, I don&amp;rsquo;t know if the problem is with WebKit itself, with the utter dominance of the Blink, or a combination of the two, but the web in 2021 feels much like the web of the early 2000&amp;rsquo;s. The difference is that instead of everyone developing specifically for Internet Explorer 6, they&amp;rsquo;re developing for Chrome. Various web conferencing applications, for example, just won&amp;rsquo;t work in Safari. Some of them like Microsoft Teams will flat-out tell you this if you try, while others will let you make the attempt and then not work as expected. I get that this is commonly done so that developers can offer a &amp;ldquo;desktop&amp;rdquo; app via Electron, but it still sucks. My favorite bug from recent memory is that SharePoint will manage to get the selection area mis-aligned with the mouse cursor in Safari, meaning that to click on a particular file or directory I have to just watch the highlighting rather than my cursor and click on something arbitrary; it&amp;rsquo;s either that or I refresh the page and hope for a better experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lack of configuration options also make Safari periodically difficult to use in a work environment. For example, 3rd party cookies are blocked by default in Safari. This is &lt;em&gt;awesome&lt;/em&gt;, in my opinion, since they should be blocked 99% of the time, yet almost no one outside of the technically minded is going to bother going into their settings to make that change. However, sometimes I need to allow 3rd party cookies, and Safari doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to offer up options for this. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://admin.teams.microsoft.com&#34;&gt;Microsoft Teams Admin Center&lt;/a&gt; is a shining example of this. Without 3rd party cookies, you&amp;rsquo;ll just get an error page. I&amp;rsquo;ve historically had to fire up a different browser in order to access it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final issue, which is definitely Safari-specific, is the update cadence. Most browsers are providing monthly updates. Safari, much like the Internet Explorer of years past, is still tying its major updates with OS updates. This means that &lt;a href=&#34;https://unusually.pink/safari-14/&#34;&gt;while the release of Safari 14 was awesome&lt;/a&gt;, for example, I&amp;rsquo;ll wait much longer for Safari 15 to bring additional improvements than I would with a competing browser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the whole, I still &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; like Safari, and I think it&amp;rsquo;s great in a personal context. For work, though, it&amp;rsquo;s just a bit too inflexible and unsupported.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;brave&#34;&gt;Brave&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My primary concern with alternative browsers was simply native support. I have a MacBook Pro running an M1 chip, and while translating x86 applications to ARM via Rosetta 2 has been seamless with plenty of applications, I wanted my browsing experience to be as snappy as possible. Tons of applications feature ARM support under Linux, which I&amp;rsquo;ve seen firsthand with my &lt;a href=&#34;https://unusually.pink/unusually-pink-impressions-pinebook-pro/&#34;&gt;Pinebook Pro&lt;/a&gt;. I figured it would only be a matter of time before developers made the necessary tweaks for M1 support. Firefox was &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.macrumors.com/2020/12/15/firefox-now-natively-supports-m1-macs/&#34;&gt;one of the first browsers I knew of to support M1 chips&lt;/a&gt;, but I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure if that was the direction I wanted to go. I love Firefox, and I still use it on all of my Linux systems; I&amp;rsquo;m using it to write this post on my &lt;a href=&#34;https://unusually.pink/star-lite-mk-iii/&#34;&gt;Star Lite Mk III&lt;/a&gt; right now. There have been a lot of concerns surrounding the direction of Firefox after &lt;a href=&#34;https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2020/08/firefox-maker-mozilla-lays-off-250-workers-says-covid-19-lowered-revenue/&#34;&gt;Mozilla laid off a large number of staff in 2020&lt;/a&gt;, a group that allegedly included most &amp;ndash; if not all &amp;ndash; of their incident response team. Additionally, I experience many of the same issues with Firefox and the Gecko engine as I do with Safari and WebKit in today&amp;rsquo;s Chrome-centric web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, I decided to give Brave a shot. Brave &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.engadget.com/apple-silicon-brave-browser-132047721.html&#34;&gt;added M1 support at the very end of 2020&lt;/a&gt;, and I already had it installed on my machine to use whenever Safari wasn&amp;rsquo;t an option for all of the aforementioned reasons. I simply swapped it to my default browser and spent the past week using it. Brave is a Chromium fork, meaning it renders pages like Chrome and will experience the same high degree of compatibility across sites. It also can install all of the same extensions as Chrome, though that&amp;rsquo;s far less important than one might think as I&amp;rsquo;ll discuss shortly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like most Chromium forks, all of the Google junk that gets added to Chrome is absent. In fact, Brave&amp;rsquo;s main mission is to be a privacy-focused browser. It features a robust advertising and tracking blocker built-in, with tons of options for configuring exceptions, disabling it entirely for certain sites, and more. What really surprised me was the aggression of blocking that it was capable of. I used the tracking blocker in Safari, for example, and the typical reporting from it would block somewhere around 200 trackers per week. After using Brave for a week, my metrics look like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hugo.unusually.pink/images/brave_blocker.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be clear, this is in no way an apples-to-apples (no pun intended) comparison since I have Brave blocking both trackers and ads while Safari can only do trackers. The numbers are still staggering after just a week, though, and I was particularly interested in seeing metrics like how much bandwidth was saved by not loading that content. There are also baseline levels of blocking that can be configured, and I initially attempted to go with the Strict option. I quickly found that too many sites flat out broke, so I switched it to Standard with much better results. Additionally, options exist for allowing things like buttons on sites for Twitter, Facebook, LinkedIn, etc. The other bonus is that such robust blocking built in means I didn&amp;rsquo;t need the array of security extensions I may be inclined to install with other browsers. After a week, the only extension I&amp;rsquo;ve added to Brave is one for my password manager.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another nice security feature with Brave is that it offers two different takes on Incognito mode. The first is the traditional Incognito mode where it won&amp;rsquo;t load any cookies from your main browsing session, and any cookies gathered during that Incognito session are removed once it ends. The other option does the exact same as the first, but it also &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.torproject.org/&#34;&gt;routes your traffic through Tor&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brave has seemingly endless customization, and everything discussed thus far can be toggled off and on in the settings. Don&amp;rsquo;t need Tor with Incognito? You can turn it off so that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t even show up as an option. In fact, going through the settings to configure Brave is the only real hurdle to using it, and it probably took me about 30 minutes to look through everything and get it set up the way that I wanted. That being said, I found the default configuration to be &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; good, and for most people who may not care to go through the settings it&amp;rsquo;ll be more than fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brave seems great on my battery life with no discernible difference from Safari. I haven&amp;rsquo;t really paid much attention to it, though, because honestly everything seems to scream on an M1 MacBook Pro without using much energy in the first place. I don&amp;rsquo;t know if I&amp;rsquo;ve ever heard the fan kick on in the months that I&amp;rsquo;ve used the device, and I literally never pay attention to the battery life. I typically work from various locations around my apartment for the morning and then settle in at my desk with a dock during the afternoon. I&amp;rsquo;ve worked undocked for an entire day a couple of times before and still ended the day with enough battery life to comfortably return to my normal routine the next day without any problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a week, I&amp;rsquo;ve been pleased with Brave. As is typically the case, I&amp;rsquo;m always open to checking out new software, and I&amp;rsquo;m interested in maybe giving Vivaldi, which I&amp;rsquo;ve used on Linux previously, a try on my MacBook once they offer M1 support.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back To Firefox</title>
      <link>https://hugo.unusually.pink/back-to-firefox/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hugo.unusually.pink/back-to-firefox/</guid>
      <description>Back in 2002, Firefox was the new hotness in the world of web browsers. Rising from the ashes of Netscape Navigator, the browser emerged as a true competitor to the horror of Internet Explorer. It offered competition with superior rendering and web compliance without the plethora of security issues plaguing Internet Explorer. While Firefox grew in popularity against Internet Explorer through the mid-2000’s, it eventually started to decline in the face of Google’s Chrome browser which took the browser market by storm with its release in the latter half of 2008.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Back in 2002, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/new/&#34;&gt;Firefox&lt;/a&gt; was the new hotness in the world of web browsers. Rising from the ashes of Netscape Navigator, the browser emerged as a true competitor to the horror of Internet Explorer. It offered competition with superior rendering and web compliance without the plethora of security issues plaguing Internet Explorer. While Firefox grew in popularity against Internet Explorer through the mid-2000’s, it eventually started to decline in the face of Google’s Chrome browser which took the browser market by storm with its release in the latter half of 2008. People appreciated the speed and efficiency of Google’s new browser, leaving Firefox to languish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the past decade, however, Firefox has undergone a slow yet steady transformation. Prior to the arrival of Chrome, Firefox was fixed on becoming the browser that could do &lt;em&gt;everything&lt;/em&gt;, for better or for worse. At the peak of its decline, Firefox was trying to be your web browser, your RSS reader (for the minority of users who had any clue what RSS was), and your IRC client (for the significantly smaller minority of users who had any clue what the hell IRC was), which overall made the browser require more resources for features that most users didn’t need or want, all the while the browser existed inside of a single, monolithic binary. By comparison, the Chrome browser broke each tab into a separate process so that complications with one tab wouldn’t impact the operation of the others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, though, the tables have begun to turn yet again. After achieving dominance in the browser market, Google has started to act like a GOP senator; they’re willing to sacrifice the good of their constituents (users) in favor of their own interests. For example, Google recognizes the impact of adblocking on its own business. As a result, they’ve &lt;a href=&#34;https://9to5google.com/2019/01/22/google-chrome-break-ad-blockers/&#34;&gt;proposed changes which would cripple adblockers&lt;/a&gt;. While they’ve bounced back and forth on this particular change since they first proposed it in January, they’ve continued to flirt with the idea; clearly Google doesn’t see blocking advertisements as a good thing. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.commitstrip.com/en/2015/09/28/scumbag-chrome/&#34;&gt;Chrome’s resource utilization continues to grow&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hugo.unusually.pink/images/BackToFirefox_commit_chrome.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time, &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mozilla.org/blog/2017/11/14/introducing-firefox-quantum/&#34;&gt;Firefox began a re-architecture of their browser which allowed for separate processes per tab&lt;/a&gt;. Since then, Mozilla has continued to refine their experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fastcompany.com/90428050/firefox-at-15-its-rise-fall-and-privacy-first-renaissance&#34;&gt;Firefox at 15: Its Rise, Fall, and Privacy-First Renaissance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://markosaric.com/firefox/&#34;&gt;Give Firefox a Chance for a Faster, Calmer, and Distraction-Free Internet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/70.0/releasenotes/&#34;&gt;Compositor improvements in Firefox for macOS that reduce power consumption, speed up page load by as much as 22 percent and reduce resource usage for video by by up to 37 percent&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mozilla.org/futurereleases/2019/11/04/restricting-notification-permission-prompts-in-firefox/&#34;&gt;Restricting Notification Permission Prompts in Firefox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theregister.co.uk/2019/11/21/ublock_origin_firefox_unblockable_tracker/&#34;&gt;Bad News: ‘Unblockable’ web trackers emerge. Good news: Firefox with uBlock Origin can stop it&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s a lot to unpack here, and if you want the full details just read all of the articles linked above. The tl;dr is that Firefox now opens a separate process per tab so that each tab can operate independently. Firefox has taken a stance on blocking trackers and other invasive behavior to fingerprint users. Firefox has improved performance on macOS &lt;em&gt;significantly&lt;/em&gt; over the past year. Do you &lt;strong&gt;fucking&lt;/strong&gt; hate the pop-up you get from what feels like every website where they want to give you notifications? Firefox is going to block those by default, and users have to actively opt into them. And as ISPs start to act even more shady in an attempt to circumvent user attempts to block tracking, Firefox is the browser empowering you to put the power over that tracking into your own hands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As time goes by, it becomes more and more clear to me that Firefox is the browser focused on user rights and privacy. While I like the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unusually.pink/blog/unusually-pink-impressions-acer-chromebook-315&#34;&gt;idea of Chromebooks and the simplicity they represent&lt;/a&gt;, they continue to become less attractive as I have to look at other options which don’t completely disregard my privacy. I’m feeling as though I’m better off getting a cheap laptop that I install my Linux distribution of choice on and use Firefox over opting for a Chromebook where Google will dictate my privacy choices on my behalf.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unusually Pink Updates: Dropbox, Password Managers, and Ad Blocking</title>
      <link>https://hugo.unusually.pink/unusually-pink-updates-dropbox-password-managers-and-ad-blocking/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hugo.unusually.pink/unusually-pink-updates-dropbox-password-managers-and-ad-blocking/</guid>
      <description>This will be one of those weird amalgam posts featuring multiple only mildly-related topics but which are too short to be a post in their own right. I though it would be helpful to provide some updates on a few things that Brandi and I have talked about in some of our past episodes. They’re all tech-related… but you already know that from reading the title.
Dropbox Upgrades and Price Increases On June 1st, Dropbox added more features to their Plus plan.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;This will be one of those weird amalgam posts featuring multiple only mildly-related topics but which are too short to be a post in their own right. I though it would be helpful to provide some updates on a few things that Brandi and I have talked about in some of our &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unusually.pink/podcast&#34;&gt;past episodes&lt;/a&gt;. They’re all tech-related… but you already know that from reading the title.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;dropbox-upgrades-and-price-increases&#34;&gt;Dropbox Upgrades and Price Increases&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On June 1st, Dropbox added more features to their &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dropbox.com/individual/plans-comparison&#34;&gt;Plus plan&lt;/a&gt;. I’ve been a Plus customer for a couple of years now. It’s less of a “I need to pay for the extra space” situation and more of a “I store some important shit in here and this gives me more peace of mind” situation. The main features from the upgrade, according to the email they sent me, are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Double your storage—save everything with 2 TB (2,000 GB).&lt;br&gt;
World-class sync technology—move out-of-date files off your computer’s hard drive and to the cloud with Dropbox Smart Sync.&lt;br&gt;
Dropbox Rewind—roll back accidental changes to any folder, or your entire account, up to 30 days.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The extra storage is nice, though suffice to say it’s not exactly something I &lt;strong&gt;need&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hugo.unusually.pink/images/UnusuallyPinkUpdatesDropboxPasswordManagersandAdBlocking_dropbox_space.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rewind seems &lt;strong&gt;really&lt;/strong&gt; nice, though. I store a lot of PowerShell scripts in Dropbox, so I could see rewind being useful if I accidentally break one or need to snag an older version for some reason. While I’ve recently been making an effort to check in my bigger, more important scripts with &lt;a href=&#34;https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/services/devops/&#34;&gt;Azure DevOps&lt;/a&gt; for version control, smaller ones that I’m the only person likely to use still just go into Dropbox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things aren’t all roses and unicorns, though, as the added storage and features come at a cost: $2 USD more per month. This bumps the monthly price up to $12 USD. The good part is that if you go with yearly pricing, you save that $2 a month and pay $120 for the year. I’m actually still on monthly pricing despite having used the Plus service for a few years so I’ll need to move over for sure. While the bonus storage is available now the new pricing isn’t happening for me until July. So before early July I need to swap to yearly billing to avoid paying the extra couple of bucks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;wired-password-manager-recommendations&#34;&gt;Wired Password Manager Recommendations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unusually.pink/podcast/episode-8-playlists-and-privacy&#34;&gt;last episode&lt;/a&gt;, Brandi and I spoke a bit about password managers. Right after we recorded that episode &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wired.com/story/best-password-managers/&#34;&gt;Wired published an article all about password managers&lt;/a&gt;. The timing seemed perfect to share it. Of the ones Wired recommends Dashlane is the only that I haven’t used. It also makes me feel good that my preferred password manager, &lt;a href=&#34;https://1password.com/&#34;&gt;1Password&lt;/a&gt;, was Wired’s #1 recommendation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of Wired, I love their content but always run into my 5 free articles per month limit. I just happened to see earlier today that they’re &lt;a href=&#34;https://subscribe.wired.com/subscribe/wired/121031?source=EDT_WIR_TWITTER_0_WEEKOFJUNE03_3_ZZ&amp;amp;utm_brand=wired&amp;amp;utm_source=twitter&amp;amp;utm_social-type=owned&amp;amp;mbid=social_twitter&amp;amp;utm_medium=social&amp;amp;utm_campaign=wired&#34;&gt;doing a deal&lt;/a&gt; where you can snag a year’s subscription for just $10. This includes the print editions plus digital content (normally $50 a year) or just digital if you don’t care about print (normally $30 a year.) I was fortunate enough to see it right when &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/WIRED/status/1136709547022848006&#34;&gt;they posted to Twitter&lt;/a&gt;. I have no clue how long this is running for, but it seems pretty worthwhile if you’re a geek and like tech news. And no… we don’t get anything for promoting this. I just like Wired.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;browser-ad-blocking&#34;&gt;Browser Ad Blocking&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also from our &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unusually.pink/podcast/episode-8-playlists-and-privacy&#34;&gt;last episode&lt;/a&gt;, we discussed how &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.zdnet.com/article/google-chrome-could-soon-kill-off-most-ad-blocker-extensions/&#34;&gt;Google was initially thinking about making changes to the webRequest API&lt;/a&gt; that would essentially cripple ad blockers. Like we discussed in the episode, after those initial reports and backlash in January Google had backed off a little and said they would think through how this API update should work. At the end of May, though, it came to light that &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.androidpolice.com/2019/05/29/google-still-plans-to-kill-chromes-existing-adblock-apis/&#34;&gt;Google still plans to nuke the webRequest API pieces that allow current ad blockers to work&lt;/a&gt;… that is &lt;a href=&#34;https://9to5google.com/2019/05/29/chrome-ad-blocking-enterprise-manifest-v3/&#34;&gt;unless you’re a G Suite customer&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What’s worse is that these proposed changes seem to be in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.chromium.org/&#34;&gt;open-source Chromium project&lt;/a&gt;. So unless Microsoft does some work on their fork, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microsoftedgeinsider.com/en-us/&#34;&gt;Chromium-based version of Edge&lt;/a&gt; could also be impacted. Suffice to say this gives me some &lt;strong&gt;significant&lt;/strong&gt; pause on my previously mentioned plans to buy a new Chromebook. I’m now re-evaluating what I should do for my laptop situation. And if you haven’t used &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/&#34;&gt;Firefox Quantum&lt;/a&gt; recently, now might be a great time to check it out.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All Dracula (Theme) Everything</title>
      <link>https://hugo.unusually.pink/all-dracula-everything/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hugo.unusually.pink/all-dracula-everything/</guid>
      <description>When you spend a significant portion of each and every day staring at a computer screen, it&amp;rsquo;s important for things to look nice. Aside from just aesthetics, it can help reduce eye strain and improve productivity. With that in mind, we wanted to help spread the word about one of the best themes ever created: Dracula. I believe I first learned about the Dracula theme from someone I follow on Twitter, though enough time is passed that I&amp;rsquo;m not 100% positive on who or if that&amp;rsquo;s even where I really found it.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;When you spend a significant portion of each and every day staring at a computer screen, it&amp;rsquo;s important for things to look nice. Aside from just aesthetics, it can help reduce eye strain and improve productivity. With that in mind, we wanted to help spread the word about one of the best themes ever created: &lt;a href=&#34;https://draculatheme.com/&#34;&gt;Dracula&lt;/a&gt;. I &lt;em&gt;believe&lt;/em&gt; I first learned about the Dracula theme from someone I follow on Twitter, though enough time is passed that I&amp;rsquo;m not 100% positive on who or if that&amp;rsquo;s even where I really found it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dracula is a beautiful dark theme with a focus on pink, green, red, and white to give it a striking visual style that&amp;rsquo;s also easy on the eyes; it&amp;rsquo;s nice when working with code to see things stand out so clearly. One of the strengths of Dracula is also that it feels like it exists for &lt;em&gt;everything&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;terminalapphttpsdraculathemecomterminal&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://draculatheme.com/terminal&#34;&gt;Terminal.app&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hugo.unusually.pink/images/AllDraculaThemeEverything_terminal.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spend a &lt;strong&gt;large&lt;/strong&gt; portion of my day working out of Terminal.app on my MacBook Pro, and the Dracula theme fits with it perfectly. While you end up with a lot more white text here than in most text editors, the smooth color scheme still makes for something a bit more pleasing to look at than the stock green text on a blackbackground that I&amp;rsquo;ve used in my terminal emulators for decades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;bonus&#34;&gt;Bonus&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you aren&amp;rsquo;t using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.zsh.org/&#34;&gt;zsh&lt;/a&gt; as your shell already, you should definitely consider switching to it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;vimhttpsdraculathemecomvim&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://draculatheme.com/vim&#34;&gt;Vim&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hugo.unusually.pink/images/AllDraculaThemeEverything_vim.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vim has been my text editor of choice for years now. While the learning curve is steep compared to a lot of other text editors, it&amp;rsquo;s honestly not too difficult to get started with the basics. Once you&amp;rsquo;ve got those covered, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to simply look up what you need when the need arises to expand your skills with it. After a little time, you can quickly become much more productive; I&amp;rsquo;m now significantly &lt;em&gt;slower&lt;/em&gt; when navigting plaintext with a combination of arrow keys with Ctrl, Home, and End.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;caveat&#34;&gt;Caveat&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The directions on the Dracula site for installing the theme with my favorite Vim plugin manager, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tpope/vim-pathogen&#34;&gt;Pathogen&lt;/a&gt; aren&amp;rsquo;t quite correct and assume you&amp;rsquo;ve done a few steps that many people will not have done. The directions instruct you to do this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;git submodule add &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:git@github.com&#34;&gt;git@github.com&lt;/a&gt;:dracula/vim.git bundle/dracula&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This may give you the following error:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;fatal: not a git repository (or any of the parent directories): .git&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The error is &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; generic, so searching the Interwebs might not give you relevant results. The tl;dr is that you can&amp;rsquo;t clone a submodule via git into a directory that isn&amp;rsquo;t already a git repository. So if you&amp;rsquo;re in the &lt;code&gt;~/.vim&lt;/code&gt; directory you can remedy that by running:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;git init .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I &lt;em&gt;still&lt;/em&gt; got an error after running the original command, though:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:git@github.com&#34;&gt;git@github.com&lt;/a&gt;: Permission denied (publickey).
fatal: Could not read from remote repository.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t have git set up in a way to allow me to clone with that format, or maybe you&amp;rsquo;re intended to change the &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:git@github.com&#34;&gt;git@github.com&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; to your own GitHub user information? I&amp;rsquo;m honestly not sure, but rather than screwing with it I just changed the URL to the https URI for the repository:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;git submodule add &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dracula/vim.git&#34;&gt;https://github.com/dracula/vim.git&lt;/a&gt; bundle/dracula&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This cloned without any issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;bonus-1&#34;&gt;Bonus&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you like my font in the screenshots above, I recenetly switched to using &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/microsoft/cascadia-code&#34;&gt;Cascadia Code&lt;/a&gt; from Microsoft. It looks terrific, is extremely readable, and works well in both text editors and the terminal. While I&amp;rsquo;ve stopped using it in favor of Cascadia Code, &lt;a href=&#34;https://mozilla.github.io/Fira/&#34;&gt;Fira Mona&lt;/a&gt; from Mozilla is also an extremely strong font if Cascadia isn&amp;rsquo;t your thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;atomhttpsdraculathemecomatom&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://draculatheme.com/atom&#34;&gt;Atom&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I do most of my work in Vim, occasionally I&amp;rsquo;ll find myself wanting/needing a GUI-based editor. In those cases, my editor of choice is Atom from GitHub. It has a solid built-in package manager with a wide array of official and community-created plugins for language support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;visual-studio-codehttpsdraculathemecomvisual-studio-code&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://draculatheme.com/visual-studio-code&#34;&gt;Visual Studio Code&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one is more Brandi&amp;rsquo;s thing than mine, but Visual Studio Code is another terrific GUI text editor. It also has the best &lt;a href=&#34;https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=ms-vscode.PowerShell&#34;&gt;PowerShell plugin&lt;/a&gt; of any text editor, making it the de facto PowerShell editor if that&amp;rsquo;s what you work in (even though I still use Vim with &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/PProvost/vim-ps1&#34;&gt;vim-ps1&lt;/a&gt;.) Both Visual Studio Code and Atom are &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.electronjs.org/&#34;&gt;Electron&lt;/a&gt; applications, so you get a similar footprint and responsiveness with either of them. I say that as a warning since Electron apps can be a little on the slow side when launching them. More on that later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;firefoxhttpsdraculathemecomfirefox&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://draculatheme.com/firefox&#34;&gt;Firefox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hugo.unusually.pink/images/AllDraculaThemeEverything_image-asset.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hugo kudos to Brandi for discovering this one, but there&amp;rsquo;s even a Dracula theme for Firefox! As a privacy-focused individual, Firefox is my browser of choice on all of my laptops. I&amp;rsquo;ve spent years using and being happy with the default dark theme in Firefox, but Dracula just takes it to the next level. I really appreciate how subtle the theme is with just hints of pink you see around active menus or the currently active tab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;honorable-mentions&#34;&gt;Honorable Mentions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;notepadhttpsdraculathemecomnotepad-plus-plus&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://draculatheme.com/notepad-plus-plus&#34;&gt;Notepad++&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back when I was using a Windows laptop for my job, I&amp;rsquo;d do a lot of my code editing in Atom and/or Visual Studio Code. They&amp;rsquo;re great editors, but Electron apps can be a bit on the slow side given that you&amp;rsquo;re loading the Chromium runtime engine for it. Notepad++ was what I used as a backup when I just needed to quickly open a plaintext file for quick viewing and/or edits rather than a prolonged coding session.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;windows-terminalhttpsdraculathemecomwindows-terminal&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://draculatheme.com/windows-terminal&#34;&gt;Windows Terminal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another holdover from when I used Windows for work, you may recall the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unusually.pink/podcast/episode-6-huzzah-hobbies&#34;&gt;podcast episode where we raved about the new Windows Terminal&lt;/a&gt;. While I no longer have a Windows 10 machine, if I did you can bet that I&amp;rsquo;d be using the Dracula theme with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much like the elements in the Dracula theme&amp;hellip; stay pink!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
