<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>mozilla on Unusually Pink</title>
    <link>https://hugo.unusually.pink/tags/mozilla/</link>
    <description>Recent content in mozilla on Unusually Pink</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>2021</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hugo.unusually.pink/tags/mozilla/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Back To Firefox</title>
      <link>https://hugo.unusually.pink/posts/back-to-firefox/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hugo.unusually.pink/posts/back-to-firefox/</guid>
      <description>Back in 2002, Firefox was the new hotness in the world of web browsers. Rising from the ashes of Netscape Navigator, the browser emerged as a true competitor to the horror of Internet Explorer. It offered competition with superior rendering and web compliance without the plethora of security issues plaguing Internet Explorer. While Firefox grew in popularity against Internet Explorer through the mid-2000’s, it eventually started to decline in the face of Google’s Chrome browser which took the browser market by storm with its release in the latter half of 2008.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Back in 2002, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/new/&#34;&gt;Firefox&lt;/a&gt; was the new hotness in the world of web browsers. Rising from the ashes of Netscape Navigator, the browser emerged as a true competitor to the horror of Internet Explorer. It offered competition with superior rendering and web compliance without the plethora of security issues plaguing Internet Explorer. While Firefox grew in popularity against Internet Explorer through the mid-2000’s, it eventually started to decline in the face of Google’s Chrome browser which took the browser market by storm with its release in the latter half of 2008. People appreciated the speed and efficiency of Google’s new browser, leaving Firefox to languish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the past decade, however, Firefox has undergone a slow yet steady transformation. Prior to the arrival of Chrome, Firefox was fixed on becoming the browser that could do &lt;em&gt;everything&lt;/em&gt;, for better or for worse. At the peak of its decline, Firefox was trying to be your web browser, your RSS reader (for the minority of users who had any clue what RSS was), and your IRC client (for the significantly smaller minority of users who had any clue what the hell IRC was), which overall made the browser require more resources for features that most users didn’t need or want, all the while the browser existed inside of a single, monolithic binary. By comparison, the Chrome browser broke each tab into a separate process so that complications with one tab wouldn’t impact the operation of the others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, though, the tables have begun to turn yet again. After achieving dominance in the browser market, Google has started to act like a GOP senator; they’re willing to sacrifice the good of their constituents (users) in favor of their own interests. For example, Google recognizes the impact of adblocking on its own business. As a result, they’ve &lt;a href=&#34;https://9to5google.com/2019/01/22/google-chrome-break-ad-blockers/&#34;&gt;proposed changes which would cripple adblockers&lt;/a&gt;. While they’ve bounced back and forth on this particular change since they first proposed it in January, they’ve continued to flirt with the idea; clearly Google doesn’t see blocking advertisements as a good thing. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.commitstrip.com/en/2015/09/28/scumbag-chrome/&#34;&gt;Chrome’s resource utilization continues to grow&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/BackToFirefox_commit_chrome.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time, &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mozilla.org/blog/2017/11/14/introducing-firefox-quantum/&#34;&gt;Firefox began a re-architecture of their browser which allowed for separate processes per tab&lt;/a&gt;. Since then, Mozilla has continued to refine their experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fastcompany.com/90428050/firefox-at-15-its-rise-fall-and-privacy-first-renaissance&#34;&gt;Firefox at 15: Its Rise, Fall, and Privacy-First Renaissance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://markosaric.com/firefox/&#34;&gt;Give Firefox a Chance for a Faster, Calmer, and Distraction-Free Internet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/70.0/releasenotes/&#34;&gt;Compositor improvements in Firefox for macOS that reduce power consumption, speed up page load by as much as 22 percent and reduce resource usage for video by by up to 37 percent&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mozilla.org/futurereleases/2019/11/04/restricting-notification-permission-prompts-in-firefox/&#34;&gt;Restricting Notification Permission Prompts in Firefox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theregister.co.uk/2019/11/21/ublock_origin_firefox_unblockable_tracker/&#34;&gt;Bad News: ‘Unblockable’ web trackers emerge. Good news: Firefox with uBlock Origin can stop it&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s a lot to unpack here, and if you want the full details just read all of the articles linked above. The tl;dr is that Firefox now opens a separate process per tab so that each tab can operate independently. Firefox has taken a stance on blocking trackers and other invasive behavior to fingerprint users. Firefox has improved performance on macOS &lt;em&gt;significantly&lt;/em&gt; over the past year. Do you &lt;strong&gt;fucking&lt;/strong&gt; hate the pop-up you get from what feels like every website where they want to give you notifications? Firefox is going to block those by default, and users have to actively opt into them. And as ISPs start to act even more shady in an attempt to circumvent user attempts to block tracking, Firefox is the browser empowering you to put the power over that tracking into your own hands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As time goes by, it becomes more and more clear to me that Firefox is the browser focused on user rights and privacy. While I like the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unusually.pink/blog/unusually-pink-impressions-acer-chromebook-315&#34;&gt;idea of Chromebooks and the simplicity they represent&lt;/a&gt;, they continue to become less attractive as I have to look at other options which don’t completely disregard my privacy. I’m feeling as though I’m better off getting a cheap laptop that I install my Linux distribution of choice on and use Firefox over opting for a Chromebook where Google will dictate my privacy choices on my behalf.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
