<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>dracula-theme on Unusually Pink</title>
    <link>https://unusually.pink/tags/dracula-theme/</link>
    <description>Recent content in dracula-theme on Unusually Pink</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>2021 - John Fabry</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://unusually.pink/tags/dracula-theme/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Twenty Twenty-One WordPress Theme</title>
      <link>https://unusually.pink/twenty-twenty-one-wordpress-theme/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unusually.pink/twenty-twenty-one-wordpress-theme/</guid>
      <description>While I made the change a few weeks ago, it seems fitting that my first post of 2021 should be about my swap to the Twenty Twenty-One WordPress theme. For anyone who isn&amp;rsquo;t aware, each year WordPress releases a new &amp;ldquo;official&amp;rdquo; theme for the platform. While theme-elitists out there may scoff at them in favor of paid, premium themes, I&amp;rsquo;ve always found the yearly offerings to be elegant and well-designed. I had originally planned on putting this post together on January 1st, but what can I say&amp;hellip; movies on HBO Now aren&amp;rsquo;t going to binge-watch themselves.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;While I made the change a few weeks ago, it seems fitting that my first post of 2021 should be about my swap to the Twenty Twenty-One WordPress theme. For anyone who isn&amp;rsquo;t aware, each year WordPress releases a new &amp;ldquo;official&amp;rdquo; theme for the platform. While theme-elitists out there may scoff at them in favor of paid, premium themes, I&amp;rsquo;ve always found the yearly offerings to be elegant and well-designed. I had &lt;em&gt;originally&lt;/em&gt; planned on putting this post together on January 1st, but what can I say&amp;hellip; movies on HBO Now aren&amp;rsquo;t going to binge-watch themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I&amp;rsquo;ve typically enjoyed the yearly WordPress theme releases, the previous iteration of this blog was actually back on the Twenty Sixteen theme since the yearly releases after that one didn&amp;rsquo;t feel like they were a particularly good fit for a blog. I still liked the look of the Twenty Sixteen theme, especially after I switched the colors around to match the &lt;a href=&#34;https://unusually.pink/all-dracula-everything/&#34;&gt;Dracula Theme&lt;/a&gt;, but the fact remains that 2016 is more or less ancient history in the world of web design. As a result, parts of the site just felt a bit&amp;hellip; antiquated. For example, while the banner at the top allowed me to show off the Unusually Pink graphics that we originally commissioned for the podcast, it left the site feeling just a bit old.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://unusually.pink/images/cropped-cropped-Unusually-Pink-Facebook-Cover-Photo.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The artwork is still amazing, though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I spent a decent bit of time tweaking the Twenty Sixteen theme to suit my needs, once I saw the &lt;a href=&#34;https://make.wordpress.org/core/2020/09/23/introducing-twenty-twenty-one/&#34;&gt;Twenty Twenty-One theme announcement in September I decided to stop further tweaking and try being patient&lt;/a&gt;. I also followed a bit &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/wordpress/twentytwentyone&#34;&gt;of the progress on the GitHub repository&lt;/a&gt;, but not being a web developer meant that it didn&amp;rsquo;t really give me a good vibe for how the theme would feel in practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the theme released, though, I immediately found myself drawn to how minimalist and streamlined it is. I feel like it provides me with the bare necessities, and then I can expand upon it from there to fit my needs without a lot of unnecessary overhead. One look at the current layout at the time of this writing probably clues you in to the fact that these aren&amp;rsquo;t the default colors; I once again opted to update the design to feel like the Dracula theme. While Twenty Twenty-One offers less in the customization UI for modifying the colors, it can still easily be done via CSS (a level of access that I sorely missed when &lt;a href=&#34;https://unusually.pink/unusually-pink-migration/&#34;&gt;the site was hosted on Squarespace&lt;/a&gt;.) I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if there&amp;rsquo;s a better way to do it than just opening the published site in my browser&amp;rsquo;s developer tools and using the inspection feature to get the classes of the objects I want to change, but that ended up getting me to the end result I wanted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along with the colors, I also felt the need to adjust some of the font sizes. In the default setup, Twenty Twenty-One opts for &lt;strong&gt;big&lt;/strong&gt; fonts, and while they looked kind of nice on my brand new MacBook Pro with a Retina display, on my 1080p, 11&amp;quot; &lt;a href=&#34;https://unusually.pink/star-lite-mk-iii/&#34;&gt;Star Lite Mk III&lt;/a&gt; going to a post would result in just the header and the post title being visible. None of the actual content could be read without scrolling. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t thrilled about my site looking so gigantic on lower resolution displays, so many of the font sizes were tweaked. That being said, as someone with extremely poor vision I&amp;rsquo;m a fan of large-ish fonts, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to completely flip to tiny text. Readability is, arguably, one of the most import things on a text-heavy site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If anyone is curious, my full CSS customizations are below. Hopefully it&amp;rsquo;s not too offensive since frontend is most definitely not my specialty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While there may still be some minor adjustments for sizes and spacing, for the most part I like where things are at. I&amp;rsquo;ve historically disliked blog landing pages which only showed the beginning of each post, but I&amp;rsquo;ve done a bit of a 180 in that regard. With Twenty Twenty-One I&amp;rsquo;ve been appreciating how the front page is much less cumbersome, especially when trying to reach the links or search box at the very bottom of the page. I think it also provides a bit of a cleaner focus on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://unusually.pink/about/&#34;&gt;link for the About page&lt;/a&gt; that I link to on most of my online profiles.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All Dracula (Theme) Everything</title>
      <link>https://unusually.pink/all-dracula-theme-everything/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unusually.pink/all-dracula-theme-everything/</guid>
      <description>When you spend a significant portion of each and every day staring at a computer screen, it&amp;rsquo;s important for things to look nice. Aside from just aesthetics, it can help reduce eye strain and improve productivity. With that in mind, we wanted to help spread the word about one of the best themes ever created: Dracula. I believe I first learned about the Dracula theme from someone I follow on Twitter, though enough time is passed that I&amp;rsquo;m not 100% positive on who or if that&amp;rsquo;s even where I really found it.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;When you spend a significant portion of each and every day staring at a computer screen, it&amp;rsquo;s important for things to look nice. Aside from just aesthetics, it can help reduce eye strain and improve productivity. With that in mind, we wanted to help spread the word about one of the best themes ever created: &lt;a href=&#34;https://draculatheme.com/&#34;&gt;Dracula&lt;/a&gt;. I &lt;em&gt;believe&lt;/em&gt; I first learned about the Dracula theme from someone I follow on Twitter, though enough time is passed that I&amp;rsquo;m not 100% positive on who or if that&amp;rsquo;s even where I really found it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dracula is a beautiful dark theme with a focus on pink, green, red, and white to give it a striking visual style that&amp;rsquo;s also easy on the eyes; it&amp;rsquo;s nice when working with code to see things stand out so clearly. One of the strengths of Dracula is also that it feels like it exists for &lt;em&gt;everything&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;terminalapphttpsdraculathemecomterminal&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://draculatheme.com/terminal&#34;&gt;Terminal.app&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://unusually.pink/images/AllDraculaThemeEverything_terminal.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spend a &lt;strong&gt;large&lt;/strong&gt; portion of my day working out of Terminal.app on my MacBook Pro, and the Dracula theme fits with it perfectly. While you end up with a lot more white text here than in most text editors, the smooth color scheme still makes for something a bit more pleasing to look at than the stock green text on a blackbackground that I&amp;rsquo;ve used in my terminal emulators for decades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;bonus&#34;&gt;Bonus&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you aren&amp;rsquo;t using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.zsh.org/&#34;&gt;zsh&lt;/a&gt; as your shell already, you should definitely consider switching to it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;vimhttpsdraculathemecomvim&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://draculatheme.com/vim&#34;&gt;Vim&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://unusually.pink/images/AllDraculaThemeEverything_vim.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vim has been my text editor of choice for years now. While the learning curve is steep compared to a lot of other text editors, it&amp;rsquo;s honestly not too difficult to get started with the basics. Once you&amp;rsquo;ve got those covered, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to simply look up what you need when the need arises to expand your skills with it. After a little time, you can quickly become much more productive; I&amp;rsquo;m now significantly &lt;em&gt;slower&lt;/em&gt; when navigting plaintext with a combination of arrow keys with Ctrl, Home, and End.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;caveat&#34;&gt;Caveat&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The directions on the Dracula site for installing the theme with my favorite Vim plugin manager, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tpope/vim-pathogen&#34;&gt;Pathogen&lt;/a&gt; aren&amp;rsquo;t quite correct and assume you&amp;rsquo;ve done a few steps that many people will not have done. The directions instruct you to do this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;git submodule add &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:git@github.com&#34;&gt;git@github.com&lt;/a&gt;:dracula/vim.git bundle/dracula&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This may give you the following error:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;fatal: not a git repository (or any of the parent directories): .git&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The error is &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; generic, so searching the Interwebs might not give you relevant results. The tl;dr is that you can&amp;rsquo;t clone a submodule via git into a directory that isn&amp;rsquo;t already a git repository. So if you&amp;rsquo;re in the &lt;code&gt;~/.vim&lt;/code&gt; directory you can remedy that by running:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;git init .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I &lt;em&gt;still&lt;/em&gt; got an error after running the original command, though:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:git@github.com&#34;&gt;git@github.com&lt;/a&gt;: Permission denied (publickey).
fatal: Could not read from remote repository.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t have git set up in a way to allow me to clone with that format, or maybe you&amp;rsquo;re intended to change the &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:git@github.com&#34;&gt;git@github.com&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; to your own GitHub user information? I&amp;rsquo;m honestly not sure, but rather than screwing with it I just changed the URL to the https URI for the repository:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;git submodule add &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dracula/vim.git&#34;&gt;https://github.com/dracula/vim.git&lt;/a&gt; bundle/dracula&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This cloned without any issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;bonus-1&#34;&gt;Bonus&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you like my font in the screenshots above, I recenetly switched to using &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/microsoft/cascadia-code&#34;&gt;Cascadia Code&lt;/a&gt; from Microsoft. It looks terrific, is extremely readable, and works well in both text editors and the terminal. While I&amp;rsquo;ve stopped using it in favor of Cascadia Code, &lt;a href=&#34;https://mozilla.github.io/Fira/&#34;&gt;Fira Mona&lt;/a&gt; from Mozilla is also an extremely strong font if Cascadia isn&amp;rsquo;t your thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;atomhttpsdraculathemecomatom&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://draculatheme.com/atom&#34;&gt;Atom&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I do most of my work in Vim, occasionally I&amp;rsquo;ll find myself wanting/needing a GUI-based editor. In those cases, my editor of choice is Atom from GitHub. It has a solid built-in package manager with a wide array of official and community-created plugins for language support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;visual-studio-codehttpsdraculathemecomvisual-studio-code&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://draculatheme.com/visual-studio-code&#34;&gt;Visual Studio Code&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one is more Brandi&amp;rsquo;s thing than mine, but Visual Studio Code is another terrific GUI text editor. It also has the best &lt;a href=&#34;https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=ms-vscode.PowerShell&#34;&gt;PowerShell plugin&lt;/a&gt; of any text editor, making it the de facto PowerShell editor if that&amp;rsquo;s what you work in (even though I still use Vim with &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/PProvost/vim-ps1&#34;&gt;vim-ps1&lt;/a&gt;.) Both Visual Studio Code and Atom are &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.electronjs.org/&#34;&gt;Electron&lt;/a&gt; applications, so you get a similar footprint and responsiveness with either of them. I say that as a warning since Electron apps can be a little on the slow side when launching them. More on that later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;firefoxhttpsdraculathemecomfirefox&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://draculatheme.com/firefox&#34;&gt;Firefox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://unusually.pink/images/AllDraculaThemeEverything_image-asset.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hugo kudos to Brandi for discovering this one, but there&amp;rsquo;s even a Dracula theme for Firefox! As a privacy-focused individual, Firefox is my browser of choice on all of my laptops. I&amp;rsquo;ve spent years using and being happy with the default dark theme in Firefox, but Dracula just takes it to the next level. I really appreciate how subtle the theme is with just hints of pink you see around active menus or the currently active tab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;honorable-mentions&#34;&gt;Honorable Mentions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;notepadhttpsdraculathemecomnotepad-plus-plus&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://draculatheme.com/notepad-plus-plus&#34;&gt;Notepad++&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back when I was using a Windows laptop for my job, I&amp;rsquo;d do a lot of my code editing in Atom and/or Visual Studio Code. They&amp;rsquo;re great editors, but Electron apps can be a bit on the slow side given that you&amp;rsquo;re loading the Chromium runtime engine for it. Notepad++ was what I used as a backup when I just needed to quickly open a plaintext file for quick viewing and/or edits rather than a prolonged coding session.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;windows-terminalhttpsdraculathemecomwindows-terminal&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://draculatheme.com/windows-terminal&#34;&gt;Windows Terminal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another holdover from when I used Windows for work, you may recall the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unusually.pink/podcast/episode-6-huzzah-hobbies&#34;&gt;podcast episode where we raved about the new Windows Terminal&lt;/a&gt;. While I no longer have a Windows 10 machine, if I did you can bet that I&amp;rsquo;d be using the Dracula theme with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much like the elements in the Dracula theme&amp;hellip; stay pink!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
